<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
        <atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
        <description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 12:44:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <sy:updatePeriod>
            hourly        </sy:updatePeriod>
        <sy:updateFrequency>
            1        </sy:updateFrequency>
        
<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
            <item>
                <title>Rocket Report: Firefly lights the markets up; SpaceX starts selling trips to Mars</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/08/rocket-report-firefly-lights-the-markets-up-spacex-starts-selling-ships-to-mars/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/08/rocket-report-firefly-lights-the-markets-up-spacex-starts-selling-ships-to-mars/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Eric Berger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 11:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/08/rocket-report-firefly-lights-the-markets-up-spacex-starts-selling-ships-to-mars/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA["Get on board! We are going to Mars!"]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Edition 8.06 of the Rocket Report! After years of disappointing results from SPACs and space companies, it is a good sign to see Firefly's more traditional initial public offering doing so well. The company has had such a long and challenging road over more than a decade; the prospect of their success should be heartening to the commercial space industry.</p>
<p>As always, we <a href="https://arstechnica.wufoo.com/forms/launch-stories/">welcome reader submissions.</a> If you don't want to miss an issue, please subscribe using the box below (the form will not appear on AMP-enabled versions of the site). Each report will include information on small-, medium-, and heavy-lift rockets as well as a quick look ahead at the next three launches on the calendar.</p>
<figure class="ars-img-shortcode id-1314289 align-center">
    <div>
                        <img decoding="async" width="560" height="81" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png" class="center full" alt="" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png 560w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll-300x43.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
                  </div>
      </figure>

<p><strong>Virgin Galactic delays resumption of spaceflights</strong>. The Richard Branson-founded company plans to resume private space tourism trips in the autumn of 2026 after its Delta spacecraft’s first commercial flight, a research mission that was delayed from summer 2026 to also occur in the fall, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-08-06/virgin-galactic-spce-to-delay-first-spaceplane-flight-to-fall-2026">Bloomberg reports</a>. Virgin Galactic announced an updated timeline on Wednesday, when it reported quarterly financial results that fell short of analysts’ expectations. Revenue was about $410,000 for the second quarter.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/08/rocket-report-firefly-lights-the-markets-up-spacex-starts-selling-ships-to-mars/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/08/rocket-report-firefly-lights-the-markets-up-spacex-starts-selling-ships-to-mars/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/20250805204418_057650-1152x648.jpeg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/20250805204418_057650-500x500.jpeg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>United Launch Alliance</media:credit><media:text>The Vulcan rocket for ULA's first national security mission nears its initial launch, NET August 12. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>New executive order puts all grants under political control</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/new-executive-order-puts-all-grants-under-political-control/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/new-executive-order-puts-all-grants-under-political-control/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[John Timmer]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 23:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive order]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research grants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/new-executive-order-puts-all-grants-under-political-control/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[All new funding on hold until Trump administration can cancel any previously funded grants.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>On Thursday, the Trump administration <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/08/improving-oversight-of-federal-grantmaking/">issued an executive order</a> asserting political control over grant funding, including all federally supported research. The order requires that any announcement of funding opportunities be reviewed by the head of the agency or someone they designate, which means a political appointee will have the ultimate say over what areas of science the US funds. Individual grants will also require clearance from a political appointee and "must, where applicable, demonstrably advance the President’s policy priorities."</p>
<p>The order also instructs agencies to formalize the ability to cancel previously awarded grants at any time if they're considered to "no longer advance agency priorities." Until a system is in place to enforce the new rules, agencies are forbidden from starting new funding programs.</p>
<p>In short, the new rules would mean that all federal science research would need to be approved by a political appointee who may have no expertise in the relevant areas, and the research can be canceled at any time if the political winds change. It would mark the end of a system that has enabled US scientific leadership for roughly 70 years.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/new-executive-order-puts-all-grants-under-political-control/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/new-executive-order-puts-all-grants-under-political-control/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>142</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GettyImages-2224884015-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GettyImages-2224884015-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Nicolas Tucat</media:credit><media:text>What are the chances that climate science like this will pass an ideological litmus test?</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>FCC Democrat: Trump admin is declaring “Mission Accomplished” on broadband</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/fcc-democrat-trump-admin-is-declaring-mission-accomplished-on-broadband/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/fcc-democrat-trump-admin-is-declaring-mission-accomplished-on-broadband/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCC]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/fcc-democrat-trump-admin-is-declaring-mission-accomplished-on-broadband/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[FCC studies broadband "with one eye closed and the other half-open," Democrat says.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The Federal Communications Commission is hamstringing its upcoming review of broadband availability by ignoring the prices consumers must pay for Internet service, FCC Commissioner Anna Gomez said in a <a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-413527A1.pdf">statement</a> yesterday.</p>
<p>"Some point to existing law to argue that availability is the only metric Congress allows to measure broadband deployment success. But the law does not require this agency to view broadband availability with one eye closed and the other one half-open," said Gomez, the only Democrat on the Republican-majority commission.</p>
<p>The FCC <a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-413494A1.pdf">said on Tuesday</a> that it voted to kick off the next annual review with a Notice of Inquiry (NOI) that "reorients the Commission's approach to the Section 706 Report by adhering more closely to the plain language of the statute and takes a fresh look at this question of whether broadband 'is being deployed to all Americans in a reasonable and timely fashion.'" That would remove affordability as a factor in the review.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/fcc-democrat-trump-admin-is-declaring-mission-accomplished-on-broadband/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/fcc-democrat-trump-admin-is-declaring-mission-accomplished-on-broadband/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>53</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/dollar-sign-1152x648-1754598445.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/dollar-sign-500x500-1754598466.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | metamorworks</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Stone tools may hint at ancestors of Homo floresiensis</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/stone-tools-may-hint-at-ancestors-of-homo-floresiensis/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/stone-tools-may-hint-at-ancestors-of-homo-floresiensis/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kiona N. Smith]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hobbits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hominins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homo erectus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homo floresiensis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homo luzonensis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleoanthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stone tools]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/stone-tools-may-hint-at-ancestors-of-homo-floresiensis/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[The stone flakes don't look like much, but they're a clue in an ancient cold case.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some stone tools found near a river on the Indonesian island of Sulawesi suggest that the first hominins had reached the islands by at least 1.04 million years ago. That's around the same time that the ancestors of the infamously diminutive “Hobbits” may have reached the island of Flores.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Archaeologist Budianto Hakim of Indonesia’s National Research and Innovation Agency and his colleagues were the ones who recently unearthed the tools from a site on Sulawesi. Although a handful of stone flakes from that island don't tell us who the ancestors of the small species were </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">or how they reached remote islands like Flores and Luzon, the tools are one more piece in the puzzle. And this handful of stone flakes may eventually play a role in helping us understand how other hominin species conquered most of the world long before we came along. </span></p>
<h2><b>Crossing the ocean a million years ago</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes the deep past leaves the smallest traces. At the Calio site, a sandstone outcrop in what's now a cornfield outside the village of Ujung in southern Sulawesi, people left behind just a handful of sharp stone flakes roughly a million years ago. There are seven of them, ranging from 22 to 60 millimeters long, and they're scratched, worn, and chipped from tumbling around at the bottom of a river. But it's still clear that they were once shaped by skilled human—or at least human-like—hands that used hard stones as hammers to make sharp-edged chert flakes for cutting and scraping.</span></p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/stone-tools-may-hint-at-ancestors-of-homo-floresiensis/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/stone-tools-may-hint-at-ancestors-of-homo-floresiensis/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Stone-tools-from-Calio-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Stone-tools-from-Calio-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Hakim at al. 2025</media:credit><media:text>These stone flakes would have been useful cutting tools to ancient hominins.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Google discovered a new scam—and also fell victim to it</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/08/google-sales-data-breached-in-the-same-scam-it-discovered/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/08/google-sales-data-breached-in-the-same-scam-it-discovered/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salesforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social engineering]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/08/google-sales-data-breached-in-the-same-scam-it-discovered/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Disclosure comes two months after Google warned the world of ongoing spree.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>In June, Google <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/voice-phishing-data-extortion">said</a> it unearthed a campaign that was mass-compromising accounts belonging to customers of Salesforce. The means: an attacker pretending to be someone in the customer's IT department feigning some sort of problem that required immediate access to the account. Two months later, Google has disclosed that it, too, was a victim.</p>
<p>The series of hacks are being carried out by financially motivated threat actors out to steal data in hopes of selling it back to the targets at sky-high prices. Rather than exploiting software or website vulnerabilities, they take a much simpler approach: calling the target and asking for access. The technique has proven remarkably successful. Companies whose Salesforce instances have been breached in the campaign, <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/google-suffers-data-breach-in-ongoing-salesforce-data-theft-attacks/">Bleeping Computer reported, </a>include Adidas, Qantas, Allianz Life, Cisco, and the LVMH subsidiaries Louis Vuitton, Dior, and Tiffany &amp; Co.</p>
<h2>Better late than never</h2>
<p>The attackers abuse a Salesforce feature that allows customers to link their accounts to third-party apps that integrate data with in-house systems for blogging, mapping tools, and similar resources. The attackers in the campaign contact employees and instruct them to connect an external app to their Salesforce instance. As the employee complies, the attackers ask the employee for an eight-digit security code that the Salesforce interface requires before a connection is made. The attackers then use this number to gain access to the instance and all data stored in it.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/08/google-sales-data-breached-in-the-same-scam-it-discovered/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/08/google-sales-data-breached-in-the-same-scam-it-discovered/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/social-engineering-scam-call-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/social-engineering-scam-call-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Broken handset on a floor with pixel details.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>After using ChatGPT, man swaps his salt for sodium bromide—and suffers psychosis</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/after-using-chatgpt-man-swaps-his-salt-for-sodium-bromide-and-suffers-psychosis/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/after-using-chatgpt-man-swaps-his-salt-for-sodium-bromide-and-suffers-psychosis/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Nate Anderson]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bromism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChatGPT]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/after-using-chatgpt-man-swaps-his-salt-for-sodium-bromide-and-suffers-psychosis/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Literal "hallucinations" were the result.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>After seeking advice on health topics from ChatGPT, a 60-year-old man who had a "history of studying nutrition in college" decided to try a health experiment: He would eliminate all chlorine from his diet, which for him meant eliminating even table salt (sodium chloride). His ChatGPT conversations led him to believe that he could replace his sodium chloride with sodium bromide, which he obtained over the Internet.</p>
<p>Three months later, the man showed up at his local emergency room. His neighbor, he said, was trying to poison him. Though extremely thirsty, the man was paranoid about accepting the water that the hospital offered him, telling doctors that he had begun distilling his own water at home and that he was on an extremely restrictive vegetarian diet. He did not mention the sodium bromide or the ChatGPT discussions.</p>
<p>His distress, coupled with the odd behavior, led the doctors to run a broad set of lab tests, revealing multiple micronutrient deficiencies, especially in key vitamins. But the bigger problem was that the man appeared to be suffering from a serious case of "bromism." That is, an excess amount of the element bromine had built up in his body.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/after-using-chatgpt-man-swaps-his-salt-for-sodium-bromide-and-suffers-psychosis/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/after-using-chatgpt-man-swaps-his-salt-for-sodium-bromide-and-suffers-psychosis/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>170</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GettyImages-2201240678-1152x648-1754591948.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GettyImages-2201240678-500x500-1754591905.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Bromine—you don't want too much in your diet!</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Did a rival tribe kill and eat their neighbors 5,700 years ago?</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/archaeologists-unearth-fresh-evidence-of-neolithic-cannibalism/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/archaeologists-unearth-fresh-evidence-of-neolithic-cannibalism/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cannibalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neolithic]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/archaeologists-unearth-fresh-evidence-of-neolithic-cannibalism/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA["The evidence points to a violent episode—possibly the result of conflict between neighboring farming communities.”]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<div class="ars-video"><div class="relative" allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/1107753965?color=ff9933"></div><div class="caption font-impact dusk:text-gray-300 mb-4 mt-2 inline-flex flex-row items-stretch gap-1 text-base leading-tight text-gray-400 dark:text-gray-300">
    <div class="caption-icon bg-[left_top_5px] w-[10px] shrink-0"></div>
    <div class="caption-content">
      Credit: IPHES-CERCA/Luis Quevedo/Madrid Scientific Films.

          </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p>Human remains from 11 individuals recovered from El Mirador Cave in Spain showed evidence of cannibalism, archaeologists have concluded. According to a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-10266-w">new paper</a> published in the journal Scientific Reports, the cannibalism was likely the result of a violent episode between competing Late Neolithic herding communities about 5,700 years ago.</p>
<p>“Cannibalism is one of the most complex behaviors to interpret, due to the inherent difficulty of understanding the act of humans consuming other humans," said co-author Palmira Saladié, a<span lang="ES-TRAD"> researcher at IPHES-CERCA and the Universitat Rovira i Virgili (URV). "Moreover, in many cases we lack all the necessary evidence to associate it with a specific behavioral context. Finally, societal biases tend to interpret it invariably as an act of barbarism.”</span></p>
<p>The El Mirador Cave is located at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archaeological_site_of_Atapuerca">Sierra de Atapuerca</a>, an archaeological site in the Burgos province of northern Spain. There is <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17492670/#:~:text=Abstract,clear%20case%20of%20gastronomic%20cannibalism.">prior evidence</a> of cannibalism at the Atapuerca site, including the remains of six Early Bronze Age humans, which included <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0305440320300029">skull caps</a> possibly used as containers during ceremonial consumption. In addition, since 1994, more than 160 bone fragments have been recovered from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archaeological_site_of_Atapuerca#Trinchera_Dolina_(1981_to_present)">Aurora Stratum</a> (TD-6) in the Gran Dolina cavern at Sierra de Atapuerca. Over 30 percent of those fragments <a href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/10.1086/653807">showed signs</a> of butchering and consumption, such as slice marks, scrape marks, and chop marks.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/archaeologists-unearth-fresh-evidence-of-neolithic-cannibalism/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/archaeologists-unearth-fresh-evidence-of-neolithic-cannibalism/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/cannibal7-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/cannibal7-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Maria D. Guillen/IPHES-CERCA</media:credit><media:text>Archaeological excavation work at El Mirador site in Spain.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>OpenAI launches GPT-5 free to all ChatGPT users</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-launches-gpt-5-free-to-all-chatgpt-users/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-launches-gpt-5-free-to-all-chatgpt-users/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[agentic AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI agents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI assistants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI development tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generative ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large language models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multimodal AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-launches-gpt-5-free-to-all-chatgpt-users/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[New model claims fewer confabulations, better coding, and "safe completions" approach.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>On Thursday, OpenAI <a href="https://openai.com/gpt-5/">announced</a> GPT-5 and three variants—GPT-5 Pro, GPT-5 mini, and GPT-5 nano—what the company calls its "best AI system yet," with availability for some of the models across all ChatGPT tiers, including free users. The new model family arrives with claims of reduced confabulations, improved coding capabilities, and a new approach to handling sensitive requests that OpenAI calls "safe completions."</p>
<p>It's also the first time OpenAI has given free users access to a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/06/with-the-launch-of-o3-pro-lets-talk-about-what-ai-reasoning-actually-does/">simulated reasoning</a> AI model, which breaks problems down into multiple steps using a technique that tends to improve answer accuracy for logical or analytical questions.</p>
<p>GPT-5 represents OpenAI's latest attempt to unify its various AI capabilities into a single system. The company says the GPT-5 family acts as a "unified system" with a smart, efficient model that answers most questions, a deeper reasoning model called "GPT-5 thinking" for harder problems, and a real-time router that decides which approach to use based on conversation type, complexity, tool needs, and user intent. Like GPT-4o, GPT-5 is a multimodal system that can interact via images, voice, and text.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-launches-gpt-5-free-to-all-chatgpt-users/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-launches-gpt-5-free-to-all-chatgpt-users/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>115</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/openai_iceblue_hero-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/openai_iceblue_hero-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>OpenAI / Benj Edwards</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>2025 Porsche Panamera Turbo S: A different approach to a luxury sedan</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-porsche-panamera-turbo-s-a-different-approach-to-a-luxury-sedan/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-porsche-panamera-turbo-s-a-different-approach-to-a-luxury-sedan/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Porsche Panamera Turbo S]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-porsche-panamera-turbo-s-a-different-approach-to-a-luxury-sedan/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Sometimes, a car makes more sense when you experience it in context.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>REIDEN, Germany—There is a lot to be said for testing a car on the roads it was developed on. A <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/04/a-beginners-guide-to-the-world-of-weird-and-wonderful-japanese-import-cars/">Kei car</a>, for example, makes more sense in downtown Tokyo than on one of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2017/05/microcar-madness-at-the-lane-motor-museum/">Nashville's arterial highways</a>, surrounded by construction trucks. Likewise the German supersedans. For decades, an arms race has been conducted between rival engineers in Munich, Ingolstadt, Stuttgart, and Zuffenhausen, each trying to best the others and build the ultimate four-door, four-wheel Autobahn crusher, fit for the fattest fat-cat captains of industry. The Panamera Turbo S E-Hybrid is Porsche's entry into this heavyweight bout.</p>
<p>In most of the world, the horsepower war has little relevance. Huge engine outputs, short acceleration times, and ridiculous top speeds that result from a casual indifference to fitting a speed limiter are at best of interest to the bench racers and are otherwise academic. Not so in Germany. After inventing the motorway in 1932, the country declined to impose speed limits on some sections, a practice it maintains as long as there's daylight and the weather is good. And drivers there make use of that privilege—in the fast lane, at least.</p>
<p>Seen in this context, the $239,000 Panamera Turbo S starts making more sense. It's the most powerful Panamera to date, combining a (fruity-sounding) 591 hp (441 kW) 4.0 L V8 that has been reworked compared to the version you might find under the hood of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2019/04/the-porsche-panamera-turbo-sport-turismo-to-hybrid-or-not-to-hybrid/">the last version</a>. New monoscroll turbochargers and a higher peak combustion chamber pressure help warm up the catalytic converters quicker, and instead of cylinder deactivation at low load, the engine can change how much and how long it opens its intake valves, shortening the travel and duration under those conditions.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-porsche-panamera-turbo-s-a-different-approach-to-a-luxury-sedan/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-porsche-panamera-turbo-s-a-different-approach-to-a-luxury-sedan/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/2025-Porsche-Panamera-Turbo-S-1-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/2025-Porsche-Panamera-Turbo-S-1-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Jonathan Gitlin</media:credit><media:text>You can tell a Panamera Turbo by the "turnbonite" colored badging and wheels. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Sonos says it’s forced to raise prices while trying to win back customers</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/sonos-says-it-is-forced-to-raise-prices-while-trying-to-win-back-customers/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/sonos-says-it-is-forced-to-raise-prices-while-trying-to-win-back-customers/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 16:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sonos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tariffs]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/sonos-says-it-is-forced-to-raise-prices-while-trying-to-win-back-customers/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Sonos expects to spend $5 million on tariffs this quarter. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>During what's supposed to be a year of redemption, Sonos has announced that its gadgets will become more expensive this year, complicating the company's comeback plans.</p>
<p>Tariffs that US President Donald Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/07/further-modifying-the-reciprocal-tariff-rates/">announced</a> last week take effect today, including a 19 percent tariff on goods imported from Malaysia (the levy is said <a href="https://www.reuters.com/en/malaysian-pharmaceuticals-semiconductors-exempt-us-tariffs-minister-says-2025-08-01/">not to apply to semiconductors</a> and was cut down from a 25 percent tariff that <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-07-10/malaysia-optimistic-of-deal-to-lower-us-tariffs-before-deadline">Trump threatened</a> in July.) Among other countries affected is Vietnam, which now sees a 20 percent tariff (down from the 46 percent rate announced in April).</p>
<p>Sonos makes all its audio products in the US, “short of a few accessories and our passive speaker partnership with Sonance," which entails <a href="https://www.sonos.com/en-us/search?q=sonance">in-wall and in-ceiling speakers</a>, in Malaysia and Vietnam, Sonos CEO Tom Conrad said yesterday, per a <a href="https://seekingalpha.com/article/4809786-sonos-inc-sono-q3-2025-earnings-call-transcript">transcript</a> of Sonos’ Q3 2025 earnings call. The new CEO explained:</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/sonos-says-it-is-forced-to-raise-prices-while-trying-to-win-back-customers/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/sonos-says-it-is-forced-to-raise-prices-while-trying-to-win-back-customers/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Sonos-1152x648-1754583290.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Sonos-500x500-1754583277.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Sonos</media:credit><media:text>A couple uses Sonos' Arc Ultra soundbar and Sub 4 subwoofer.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Trump wanted a US-made iPhone. Apple gave him a gold statue.</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/trump-wanted-a-us-made-iphone-apple-gave-him-a-gold-statue/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/trump-wanted-a-us-made-iphone-apple-gave-him-a-gold-statue/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 15:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tariffs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us-china trade war]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/trump-wanted-a-us-made-iphone-apple-gave-him-a-gold-statue/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Trump's chip tariffs won't hit Apple despite no plans for a US-made iPhone.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>It's now clear that Apple plans to survive Donald Trump's trade war by playing to the president's ego.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Trump announced that Apple would be exempt from a threatened 100 percent tariff on semiconductors that could have driven up the cost of iPhones globally, Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/trump-says-us-levy-100-tariff-imported-chips-some-firms-exempt-2025-08-07/">reported</a>. In an apparent effort to secure this exemption, Apple promised to increase its total investment commitment in the US by $100 billion, while also gifting Trump a one-of-a-kind statue that Apple CEO Tim Cook had engraved with Trump's name.</p>
<p>It serves as a bizarre love letter to Trump's push to bring tech manufacturing into the US, despite Apple resisting that push for its most popular product.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/trump-wanted-a-us-made-iphone-apple-gave-him-a-gold-statue/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/trump-wanted-a-us-made-iphone-apple-gave-him-a-gold-statue/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>304</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GettyImages-2228840629-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GettyImages-2228840629-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Win McNamee / Staff | Getty Images News</media:credit><media:text>Donald Trump speaks behind an engraved glass disc gifted to him by Apple CEO Tim Cook during an event in the Oval Office of the White House.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Review: Framework Desktop is a mash-up of a regular desktop PC and the Mac Studio</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/review-framework-desktop-is-a-mash-up-of-a-regular-desktop-pc-and-the-mac-studio/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/review-framework-desktop-is-a-mash-up-of-a-regular-desktop-pc-and-the-mac-studio/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AMD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework desktop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ryzen ai]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/review-framework-desktop-is-a-mash-up-of-a-regular-desktop-pc-and-the-mac-studio/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Size matters most for Framework's first stab at a desktop workstation/gaming PC.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Framework’s main claim to fame is its commitment to modular, upgradeable, repairable laptops. The jury’s still out on early 2024’s Framework Laptop 16 and mid-2025’s Framework Laptop 12, neither of which has seen a hardware refresh, but so far, the company has released half a dozen iterations of its flagship Framework Laptop 13 in less than five years. If you bought one of the originals right when it first launched, you could go to Framework’s site, buy an all-new motherboard and RAM, and get a substantial upgrade in performance and other capabilities without having to change anything else about your laptop.</p>
<p>Framework’s laptops haven’t been adopted as industry-wide standards, but in many ways, they seem built to reflect the flexibility and modularity that has drawn me to desktop PCs for more than two decades.</p>
<p>That's what makes the Framework Desktop so weird. Not only is Framework navigating into a product category where its main innovation and claim to fame is totally unnecessary. But it’s actually doing that with a desktop that’s <em>less</em> upgradeable and modular than any given self-built desktop PC.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/review-framework-desktop-is-a-mash-up-of-a-regular-desktop-pc-and-the-mac-studio/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/review-framework-desktop-is-a-mash-up-of-a-regular-desktop-pc-and-the-mac-studio/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>72</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/IMG_3290-1152x648.jpeg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/IMG_3290-500x500.jpeg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Andrew Cunningham</media:credit><media:text>The Framework Desktop.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>2025 Subaru WRX tS review: A scalpel-sharp chassis lets this car dance</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-subaru-wrx-ts-review-a-scalpel-sharp-chassis-lets-this-car-dance/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-subaru-wrx-ts-review-a-scalpel-sharp-chassis-lets-this-car-dance/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jim Resnick]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 14:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Subaru WRX]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-subaru-wrx-ts-review-a-scalpel-sharp-chassis-lets-this-car-dance/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Lots of suspension tweaks but no extra power for this WRX variant.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The Subaru WRX has always been the equivalent of an automotive shrug. Not because it lacks character but because it simply doesn't care what others think. It's a punk rock band with enough talent to fill stadiums but band members who don't seem to care about chasing fame. And the STI versions of yesteryear proved so talented that fame chased them.</p>
<p>For 2025, Subaru updated the WRX to now include the tS, which at first glance appears to be the same flannel-wearing street fighter. But looks can be deceiving. The tS hides sharpened tools underneath, translating to better handling and responsiveness.</p>
<h2>What does “tS” really mean?</h2>
<p>Subaru positions the tS as being tuned by STI, but it's not an STI return. Sure, that's technically true; only Subaru can name something STI. And to be clear, there's no extra power here, no gigantic wing that takes out flocks of birds, and no pink STI badge on the trunk. But the tS is imbued with enough STI-ness to make a case.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-subaru-wrx-ts-review-a-scalpel-sharp-chassis-lets-this-car-dance/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/2025-subaru-wrx-ts-review-a-scalpel-sharp-chassis-lets-this-car-dance/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>77</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/IMG_6987-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/IMG_6987-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Jim Resnick</media:credit><media:text>Subaru went with a sedan for the current version of the WRX. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>President Trump says Intel’s new CEO “must resign immediately”</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/president-trump-says-intels-new-ceo-must-resign-immediately/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/president-trump-says-intels-new-ceo-must-resign-immediately/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Tim Bradshaw, Financial Times]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 13:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lip-Bu Tan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/president-trump-says-intels-new-ceo-must-resign-immediately/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[President accuses semiconductor industry veteran Lip-Bu Tan of being "highly conflicted."]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has called for the newly appointed chief executive of Intel, Lip-Bu Tan, to resign, alleging that the semiconductor industry veteran is “highly conflicted.”</p>
<p>“The CEO of INTEL is highly CONFLICTED and must resign, immediately,” Trump said in his post on his Truth Social website on Thursday. “There is no other solution to this problem.”</p>
<p>The US president’s post did not provide details of Tan’s alleged conflicts of interest. Trump’s broadside follows a letter from Republican Senator Tom Cotton to the US chipmaker’s board chair this week expressing “concern about the security and integrity of Intel’s operations” and Tan’s ties to China.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/president-trump-says-intels-new-ceo-must-resign-immediately/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/president-trump-says-intels-new-ceo-must-resign-immediately/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>203</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/lipbutan-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/lipbutan-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>picture alliance/Getty</media:credit><media:text>Intel chief Lip-Bu Tan. The US president’s Truth Social post did not provide details of Tan’s alleged conflicts of interest.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>RFK Jr. defends $500M cut for mRNA vaccines with pseudoscience gobbledygook</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/rfk-jr-defends-500m-cut-for-mrna-vaccines-with-pseudoscience-gobbledygook/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/rfk-jr-defends-500m-cut-for-mrna-vaccines-with-pseudoscience-gobbledygook/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 11:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antigen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kennedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pandemic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SARS-CoV-2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virus]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/rfk-jr-defends-500m-cut-for-mrna-vaccines-with-pseudoscience-gobbledygook/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[He clearly has no idea what antigenic shift means. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>If anyone needed a reminder that US health secretary and fervent anti-vaccine advocate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. has no background in science or medicine, look no further than <a href="https://x.com/SecKennedy/status/1952851097019633766">the video he posted on social media</a> Tuesday evening.</p>
<p>In the two-and-a-half-minute clip, Kennedy announced that he is cancelling nearly $500 million in funding for the development of mRNA-based vaccines against diseases that pose pandemic threats. The funding will be clawed back from 22 now-defunct contracts awarded through the federal agency tasked with developing medical countermeasures to public health threats. The agency is the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority (BARDA).</p>
<p>Kennedy is generally opposed to vaccines, but he is particularly hostile to mRNA-based vaccines. Since the remarkably successful debut of mRNA COVID-19 vaccines during the COVID-19 pandemic—which were developed and mass-produced with unprecedented speed—Kennedy has continually disparaged and spread misinformation about them.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/rfk-jr-defends-500m-cut-for-mrna-vaccines-with-pseudoscience-gobbledygook/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/08/rfk-jr-defends-500m-cut-for-mrna-vaccines-with-pseudoscience-gobbledygook/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>224</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2216099156-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2216099156-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Tasos Katopodis</media:credit><media:text>US Secretary of Health and Human Services Robert F. Kennedy Jr. testifies before the Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions on Capitol Hill on May 20, 2025 in Washington, DC.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Here’s how deepfake vishing attacks work, and why they can be hard to detect</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/08/heres-how-deepfake-vishing-attacks-work-and-why-they-can-be-hard-to-detect/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/08/heres-how-deepfake-vishing-attacks-work-and-why-they-can-be-hard-to-detect/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deepfakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speech synthesis]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/08/heres-how-deepfake-vishing-attacks-work-and-why-they-can-be-hard-to-detect/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Why AI-based voice cloning is the next frontier in social-engineering attacks.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>By now, you’ve likely heard of fraudulent calls that use AI to clone the voices of people the call recipient knows. Often, the result is what sounds like a grandchild, CEO, or work colleague you’ve known for years reporting an urgent matter requiring immediate action, saying to wire money, divulge login credentials, or visit a malicious website.</p>
<p>Researchers and <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/publications/increasing_threats_of_deepfake_identities_0.pdf">government officials</a> have been warning of the threat for years, with the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/alerts/2023/09/12/nsa-fbi-and-cisa-release-cybersecurity-information-sheet-deepfake-threats">saying</a> in 2023 that threats from deepfakes and other forms of synthetic media have increased “exponentially.” Last year, Google’s Mandiant security division <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/ai-powered-voice-spoofing-vishing-attacks">reported</a> that such attacks are being executed with “uncanny precision, creating for more realistic phishing schemes.”</p>
<h2>Anatomy of a deepfake scam call</h2>
<p>On Wednesday, security firm Group-IB <a href="https://www.group-ib.com/blog/voice-deepfake-scams/">outlined</a> the basic steps involved in executing these sorts of attacks. The takeaway is that they’re easy to reproduce at scale and can be challenging to detect or repel.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/08/heres-how-deepfake-vishing-attacks-work-and-why-they-can-be-hard-to-detect/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/08/heres-how-deepfake-vishing-attacks-work-and-why-they-can-be-hard-to-detect/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/deepfake_audio_voice_hero_2-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/deepfake_audio_voice_hero_2-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Tornado Cash sold crypto “privacy”; the US saw “money laundering.”</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/tornado-cash-sold-crypto-privacy-the-us-saw-money-laundering-a-jury-isnt-sure-what-to-think/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/tornado-cash-sold-crypto-privacy-the-us-saw-money-laundering-a-jury-isnt-sure-what-to-think/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Nate Anderson]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 21:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roman storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tornado cash]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/tornado-cash-sold-crypto-privacy-the-us-saw-money-laundering-a-jury-isnt-sure-what-to-think/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Tornado didn't want to know its customers, which included North Korean hackers.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>"Crypto mixers" exist because of a peculiar feature of cryptocurrencies—most are fully traceable using their public blockchain ledgers. To provide more privacy to crypto account owners, a mixer will let people toss their crypto into a large pool, where it is "mixed" with other people's crypto. At a later date, each crypto owner can choose to withdraw their money from the pool into a new, anonymous wallet, thus making the movement of the crypto harder to track.</p>
<p>Of course, the obfuscation doesn't work well if the blockchain shows 1,231.7 BTC entering a mixer and 1,231.7 BTC being withdrawn to a new wallet. So mixers will take steps to disguise the transactions. Tornado Cash, which operated on the Ethereum blockchain, mandated that users could only deposit money into its pools in 0.1, 1, 10, and 100 ETH increments, making it far harder to spot specific amounts entering and leaving the mixer.</p>
<p>Tornado Cash also used a complex system of "relayers" to pay the Ethereum "gas fees" charged for transactions on the network; without doing this, it would be clear which old account was paying to "mix" money into which new account. The whole process relied on the use of irrevocable "smart contracts," all of which sounds rather technically daunting, but Tornado put a nice user interface atop the details that made the service far easier to use than it might sound.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/tornado-cash-sold-crypto-privacy-the-us-saw-money-laundering-a-jury-isnt-sure-what-to-think/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/tornado-cash-sold-crypto-privacy-the-us-saw-money-laundering-a-jury-isnt-sure-what-to-think/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>94</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/getty-blockchain-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/getty-blockchain-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | Yuichiro Chino</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>US executive branch agencies will use ChatGPT Enterprise for just $1 per agency</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-announces-deal-to-offer-chatgpt-to-us-executive-branch-at-almost-no-cost/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-announces-deal-to-offer-chatgpt-to-us-executive-branch-at-almost-no-cost/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 20:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ai action plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChatGPT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChatGPT Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive branch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LLM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preventing Woke AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump administration]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-announces-deal-to-offer-chatgpt-to-us-executive-branch-at-almost-no-cost/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Questions linger about ideological bias in models as well as data security.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>OpenAI <a href="https://openai.com/index/providing-chatgpt-to-the-entire-us-federal-workforce/">announced an agreement</a> to supply more than 2 million workers for the US federal executive branch access to ChatGPT and related tools at practically no cost: just $1 per agency for one year.</p>
<p>The deal was announced just one day after the US General Services Administration (GSA) signed a blanket deal to allow OpenAI and rivals like Google and Anthropic to supply tools to federal workers.</p>
<p>The workers will have access to ChatGPT Enterprise, a type of account that includes access to frontier models and cutting-edge features with relatively high token limits, alongside a more robust commitment to data privacy than general consumers of ChatGPT get. ChatGPT Enterprise has been trialed over the past several months at several corporations and other types of large organizations.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-announces-deal-to-offer-chatgpt-to-us-executive-branch-at-almost-no-cost/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/08/openai-announces-deal-to-offer-chatgpt-to-us-executive-branch-at-almost-no-cost/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>99</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/openai-sam-altman-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/openai-sam-altman-500x500-1739898913.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | Jason Redmond/AFP</media:credit><media:text>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman speaks during the Microsoft Build conference at the Seattle Convention Center Summit Building in Seattle, Washington on May 21, 2024. (Photo by Jason Redmond / AFP)</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Hulu’s days look numbered, but there’s reason for Disney to keep it around </title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/hulus-days-look-numbered-but-theres-reason-for-disney-to-keep-it-around/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/hulus-days-look-numbered-but-theres-reason-for-disney-to-keep-it-around/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hulu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/hulus-days-look-numbered-but-theres-reason-for-disney-to-keep-it-around/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Hulu will finish integrating into the Disney+ app in 2026, Disney says. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Bob Iger, the CEO of The Walt Disney Company, announced today that Disney will "fully integrate" Hulu into the Disney+ app in 2026. Although a company representative told <a href="https://variety.com/2025/digital/news/hulu-app-phased-out-disney-plus-fully-integrating-1236480450/">Variety</a> that people will still be able to buy standalone subscriptions to Hulu, we can't help but wonder how long that will last.</p>
<p>A prim and polished app combining the catalogs, recommendations, and profiles for Disney+ and Hulu subscribers could make a standalone Hulu app redundant. In fact, the ability to successfully combine those two<a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/these-are-the-best-streaming-services-you-arent-watching/"> streaming services</a> into one platform could, depending on how executives look at it, make the entire Hulu business redundant.</p>
<p>Some are reporting that Iger means that the Hulu app will be <a href="https://variety.com/2025/digital/news/hulu-app-phased-out-disney-plus-fully-integrating-1236480450/">phased out next year</a>, while others are saying that the death of the Hulu app is <a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-hulu-app-may-not-be-long-for-this-world-2000639568">likely but not yet guaranteed</a>.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/hulus-days-look-numbered-but-theres-reason-for-disney-to-keep-it-around/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/hulus-days-look-numbered-but-theres-reason-for-disney-to-keep-it-around/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>103</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Futurama-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Futurama-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Hulu</media:credit><media:text>A scene from &lt;em&gt;Futurama&lt;/em&gt;, which is a Hulu original series now. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Coding error blamed after parts of Constitution disappear from US website</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/coding-error-blamed-after-parts-of-constitution-disappear-from-us-website/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/coding-error-blamed-after-parts-of-constitution-disappear-from-us-website/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us constitution]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/coding-error-blamed-after-parts-of-constitution-disappear-from-us-website/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[US restores deleted portions after people noticed the Constitution had shrunk.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The Library of Congress today said a coding error resulted in the deletion of parts of the US Constitution from Congress' website and promised a fix after many Internet users pointed out the missing sections this morning.</p>
<p>"It has been brought to our attention that some sections of Article 1 are missing from the Constitution Annotated (<a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/">constitution.congress.gov</a>) website," the Library of Congress <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/librarycongress.bsky.social/post/3lvqilhwb6k2x">said today</a>. "We've learned that this is due to a coding error. We have been working to correct this and expect it to be resolved soon."</p>
<p>The missing portions of the Constitution were restored to <a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/constitution/">one part of the website</a> a few hours after the Library of Congress statement and reappeared on a <a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/browse/article-1/">different part of the website</a> another hour or so later. The Constitution Annotated website carried a notice saying it "is currently experiencing data issues. We are working to resolve this issue and regret the inconvenience."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/coding-error-blamed-after-parts-of-constitution-disappear-from-us-website/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/coding-error-blamed-after-parts-of-constitution-disappear-from-us-website/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>147</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/constitution-1152x648-1754508701.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/constitution-500x500-1754508711.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | Joe Sohm/Visions of America </media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>