<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
    <atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
    <description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 23:28:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
      hourly    </sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
      1    </sy:updateFrequency>
    
<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
      <item>
        <title>De-extinction company provides a progress report on thylacine efforts</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/effort-to-bring-back-the-tasmanian-tiger-builds-steam/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/effort-to-bring-back-the-tasmanian-tiger-builds-steam/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[John Timmer]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 23:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[de-extinction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dunnart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genomics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marsupials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thylacine]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/effort-to-bring-back-the-tasmanian-tiger-builds-steam/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Stem cell editing, complete genome, and cane toad resistance mark necessary steps. ]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Colossal, the company founded to try to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/03/de-extinction-company-manages-to-generate-first-elephant-stem-cells/">restore the mammoth</a> to the Arctic tundra, has also decided to tackle a number of other species that have gone extinct relatively recently: <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/01/the-next-de-extinction-target-the-dodo/">the dodo</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2022/08/de-extinction-company-sets-its-next-first-target-the-thylacine/#page-2">the thylacine</a>. Because of significant differences in biology, not the least of which is the generation time of Proboscideans, these other efforts may reach many critical milestones well in advance of the work on mammoths.</p>
<p>Late last week, Colossal released a progress report on the work involved in resurrecting the thylacine, also known as the Tasmanian tiger, which went extinct when the last known survivor died in a zoo in 1936. Marsupial biology has some features that may make de-extinction somewhat easier, but we have far less sophisticated ways of manipulating it compared to the technology we've developed for working with the stem cells and reproduction of placental mammals. But, based on these new announcements, the technology available for working with marsupials is expanding rapidly.</p>
<h2>Cane toad resistance</h2>
<p>Colossal has branched out from its original de-extinction mission to include efforts to keep species from ever needing its services. In the case of marsupial predators, the de-extinction effort is incorporating work that will benefit existing marsupial predators: generating resistance to the toxins found on the cane toad, an invasive species that has spread widely across Australia.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/effort-to-bring-back-the-tasmanian-tiger-builds-steam/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/effort-to-bring-back-the-tasmanian-tiger-builds-steam/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-629464499-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-629464499-500x500-1729635923.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Universal History Archive</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Shady drugmaker used code words to sell knockoff weight-loss drug: lawsuit</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2024/10/shady-drugmaker-sold-diy-weight-loss-drug-marked-for-animal-use-suit-alleges/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2024/10/shady-drugmaker-sold-diy-weight-loss-drug-marked-for-animal-use-suit-alleges/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 22:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eli lilly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GLP-1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mounjaro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pharmaceutical industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tirzepatide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zepbound]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2024/10/shady-drugmaker-sold-diy-weight-loss-drug-marked-for-animal-use-suit-alleges/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[After cease-and-desist letter, Pivotal Peptides allegedly sold mix-your-own tirzepatide as "11 mg."]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Amid ongoing legal battles over coveted GLP-1 therapies, a drug vendor in Washington state is accused of running an outlandish scheme to sell do-it-yourself kits to make illicit knockoff versions of weight-loss and diabetes drugs, Zepbound and Mounjaro.</p>
<p>For the alleged scheme, vendor Pivotal Peptides has customers buy a set of ingredients they have to mix together to create their own injectable versions of the drugs. Customers don't need a prescription or even a medical consultation to order the kit, even though the brand-name drugs are prescription-only. That may not be surprising, though, since the dubious white powder customers receive is stated to be "a research chemical for lab research and veterinary purposes only." Once purchased, the kit's instructions recommend users disinfect their home work surface before beginning and stress the importance of using the sterile water included in the kit to dissolve the powder to the desired concentration. The instructions then explain how to inject oneself with the homemade mixture using a 30-gauge syringe.</p>
<p>That's all according to <a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/0001.00_2024-10-21-Complaint-for-False-Advertising-and-Promotion-Pivotal-1.pdf">a lawsuit filed Monday by pharmaceutical giant Eli Lilly</a>, maker of tirzepatide-based Zepbound and Mounjaro, which are sold as ready-to-use medicines in single-dose pens or vials. The lawsuit against Pivotal Peptides is one of three that Lilly filed this week, all accusing questionable drugmakers of unlawfully selling knockoff versions of its tirzepatide drugs that have not been tested or approved. But the one against Pivotal Peptides stands out for the scheme the owners allegedly used to sell their knockoff version.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2024/10/shady-drugmaker-sold-diy-weight-loss-drug-marked-for-animal-use-suit-alleges/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2024/10/shady-drugmaker-sold-diy-weight-loss-drug-marked-for-animal-use-suit-alleges/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-1287271384-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-1287271384-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Stefan Cristian Cioata</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Streaming subscription fees have been rising while content quality is dropping</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/subscribers-are-paying-more-for-streaming-content-that-they-are-enjoying-less/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/subscribers-are-paying-more-for-streaming-content-that-they-are-enjoying-less/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 22:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/subscribers-are-paying-more-for-streaming-content-that-they-are-enjoying-less/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Surveys show decline in customer satisfaction with what is available to stream. ]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Subscription fees for video streaming services have been on a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/09/disney-made-2-4-billion-in-revenue-in-3-months-leak-claims/">steady incline</a>. But despite subscribers paying more, surveys suggest that viewers are becoming less satisfied with what's available to watch.</p>
<p>At the start of 2024, the industry began declaring <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/bradadgate/2024/01/23/why-peak-tv-may-have-reached-its-end-after-a-decade-of-success/">the end of Peak TV</a>, a term coined by FX Networks chairman John Landgraf, refers to an era of rampant content spending that gave us shows like <em>The Wire</em>, <em>Breaking Bad, </em>and <em>Game of Thrones</em>. For streaming services, the Peak TV era meant trying to lure subscribers with original content that was often buoyed by critical acclaim and/or top-tier actors, writers, and/or directors. However, as streaming services struggle to reach or maintain profitability, 2024 saw a drop in the number of new scripted shows for the first time in at least 10 years, FX Research <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/02/12/peak-tv-decline-scripted-shows-low">found</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, overall satisfaction with the quality of content available on streaming services seems to have declined for the past couple of years. Most surveys suggest a generally small decline in perceived quality, but that’s still perturbing considering how <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/06/subscribing-to-max-just-got-up-to-20-more-expensive/">frequently</a> streaming services <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/so-tired-disney-hulu-espn-prices-increase-by-up-to-25-percent-in-october/">increase subscription fees</a>. There was a time when a streaming subscription represented an exclusive ticket to viewing some of the best new TV shows and movies. But we’ve reached a point where the most streamed TV show last year <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/nielsen-2023-streaming-report-suits-the-office-record-1235890306/">was <em>Suits</em></a>—an original from the USA Network cable channel that ended in 2019.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/subscribers-are-paying-more-for-streaming-content-that-they-are-enjoying-less/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/subscribers-are-paying-more-for-streaming-content-that-they-are-enjoying-less/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>77</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-520220499-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-520220499-500x500-1729628490.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Meet the winners of Nikon’s 2024 photomicrography contest</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/photomicrography-contest-winners-showcase-beauty-at-tiny-scales/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/photomicrography-contest-winners-showcase-beauty-at-tiny-scales/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 21:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microphotography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nikon Small World Photo Microscopy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science and art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science photography]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/photomicrography-contest-winners-showcase-beauty-at-tiny-scales/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Nikon Small World photomicrography contest is an annual reminder that science can be beautiful as well as informative.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>A stunning image of differentiated mouse brain tumor cells has won the 2024 Nikon Small World photomicrography contest, yielding valuable insight into how degenerate diseases like Alzheimer's and ALS can arise from disruption in the cytoskeleton of brain cells. The image was taken by Bruno Cisterna, with assistance from Eric Vitriol, both with Augusta University in Georgia.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">"One of the main problems with neurodegenerative diseases is that we don't fully understand what causes them,” Cisterna said in a statement. “To develop effective treatments, we need to figure out the basics first. Our research is crucial for uncovering this knowledge and ultimately finding a cure. Differentiated cells could be used to study how mutations or toxic proteins that cause Alzheimer's or ALS alter neuronal morphology, as well as to screen potential drugs or gene therapies aimed at protecting neurons or restoring their function.”</p>
<p>It's the 50th anniversary of Nikon's annual contest, which was founded back in 1974 "to showcase the beauty and complexity of things seen through the light microscope." <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Micrograph">Photomicrography</a> involves attaching a camera to a microscope (either an optical microscope or an electron microscope) so that the user can take photographs of objects at very high resolutions. British physiologist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Hill_Norris">Richard Hill Norris</a> was one of the first to use it for his studies of blood cells in 1850, and the method has increasingly been highlighted as art since the 1970s. There have been many groundbreaking technological advances in the ensuing decades, particularly with the advent of digital imaging methods.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/photomicrography-contest-winners-showcase-beauty-at-tiny-scales/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/photomicrography-contest-winners-showcase-beauty-at-tiny-scales/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/nikon1-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/nikon1-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Bruno Cisterna &amp; Eric Vitrol/Nikon Small World</media:credit><media:text>Winning image: Differentiated mouse brain tumor cells (actin, microtubules, and nuclei).</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Anthropic publicly releases AI tool that can take over the user’s mouse cursor</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/10/anthropic-publicly-releases-ai-tool-that-can-take-over-the-users-mouse-cursor/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/10/anthropic-publicly-releases-ai-tool-that-can-take-over-the-users-mouse-cursor/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 21:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anthropic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Claude]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Use]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/10/anthropic-publicly-releases-ai-tool-that-can-take-over-the-users-mouse-cursor/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Anthropic is one of the first to go beyond just screen vision.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>AI software company Anthropic has announced a new tool that can take control of the user's mouse cursor and perform basic tasks on their computer.</p>
<p>Announced <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/3-5-models-and-computer-use">alongside</a> other improvements to Anthropic's Claude and Haiku models, the tool is straightforwardly called "Computer Use." It's available exclusively with the company's mid-range 3.5 Sonnet model right now, via the API. Users can give multi-step instructions (Anthropic claims it can go for tens or even hundreds of steps) to accomplish tasks on the user's computer by "looking at a screen, moving a cursor, clicking buttons, and typing text."</p>
<p>Here's how Anthropic says it works:</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/10/anthropic-publicly-releases-ai-tool-that-can-take-over-the-users-mouse-cursor/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/10/anthropic-publicly-releases-ai-tool-that-can-take-over-the-users-mouse-cursor/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-22-at-3.44.28 PM-768x432.png" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-22-at-3.44.28 PM-500x500.png" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Anthropic</media:credit><media:text>An Anthropic employee works with Claude 3.5.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Lawsuit: City cameras make it impossible to drive anywhere without being tracked</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/lawsuit-city-cameras-make-it-impossible-to-drive-anywhere-without-being-tracked/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/lawsuit-city-cameras-make-it-impossible-to-drive-anywhere-without-being-tracked/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 20:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automated license plate readers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flock safety]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/lawsuit-city-cameras-make-it-impossible-to-drive-anywhere-without-being-tracked/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA["Every passing car is captured," says 4th Amendment lawsuit against Norfolk, Va.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Police use of automated license-plate reader cameras is being challenged in a lawsuit alleging that the cameras enable warrantless surveillance in violation of the Fourth Amendment. The city of Norfolk, Virginia, was sued yesterday by plaintiffs represented by the <a href="https://ij.org/about-us/">Institute for Justice</a>, a nonprofit public-interest law firm.</p>
<p>Norfolk, a city with about 238,000 residents, "has installed a network of cameras that make it functionally impossible for people to drive anywhere without having their movements tracked, photographed, and stored in an AI-assisted database that enables the warrantless surveillance of their every move. This civil rights lawsuit seeks to end this dragnet surveillance program," said the <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.vaed.562101/gov.uscourts.vaed.562101.1.0.pdf">complaint</a> filed in US District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia.</p>
<p>Like many other cities, Norfolk uses cameras made by the company Flock Safety. A <a href="https://www.404media.co/lawsuit-argues-warrantless-use-of-flock-surveillance-cameras-is-unconstitutional/">404 Media article</a> said Institute for Justice lawyer Robert Frommer "told 404 Media that the lawsuit could have easily been filed in any of the more than 5,000 communities where Flock is active, but that Norfolk made sense because the Fourth Circuit of Appeals—which Norfolk is part of—recently held that persistent, warrantless drone surveillance in Baltimore is unconstitutional under the Fourth Amendment in a case called <em><a href="https://harvardlawreview.org/print/vol-135/leaders-of-a-beautiful-struggle-v-baltimore-police-department/?ref=404media.co">Beautiful Struggle v Baltimore Police Department</a></em>."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/lawsuit-city-cameras-make-it-impossible-to-drive-anywhere-without-being-tracked/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/lawsuit-city-cameras-make-it-impossible-to-drive-anywhere-without-being-tracked/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>76</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/license-plate-reader-camera-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/license-plate-reader-camera-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:text>An automated license plate reader is seen mounted on a pole on June 13, 2024 in San Francisco, California.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>FortiGate admins report active exploitation 0-day. Vendor isn’t talking.</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/10/fortinet-stays-mum-on-critical-0-day-reportedly-under-active-exploitation/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/10/fortinet-stays-mum-on-critical-0-day-reportedly-under-active-exploitation/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fortigate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fortinet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zeroday]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/10/fortinet-stays-mum-on-critical-0-day-reportedly-under-active-exploitation/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Vulnerability allowing remote code execution has been discussed since at least 9 days ago.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Fortinet, a maker of network security software, has kept a critical vulnerability under wraps for more than a week amid reports that attackers are using it to execute malicious code on servers used by sensitive customer organizations.</p>
<p>Fortinet representatives didn’t respond to emailed questions and have yet to release any sort of public advisory detailing the vulnerability or the specific software that’s affected. The lack of transparency is consistent with <a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/06/china-state-hackers-infected-20000-fortinet-vpns-dutch-spy-service-says/">previous zero-days</a> that have been exploited against Fortinet customers. With no authoritative source for information, customers, reporters, and others have few other avenues for information other than social media posts where the attacks are being discussed.</p>
<h2>RCE stands for remote code execution</h2>
<p>According to one Reddit <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/fortinet/comments/1g6vspq/comment/lsnc32x/">post</a>, the vulnerability affects FortiManager, a software tool for managing all traffic and devices on an organization’s network. Specific versions vulnerable, the post said, include FortiManager versions:</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/10/fortinet-stays-mum-on-critical-0-day-reportedly-under-active-exploitation/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/10/fortinet-stays-mum-on-critical-0-day-reportedly-under-active-exploitation/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/fortigate-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/fortigate-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Fortinet</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Reading Lord of the Rings aloud: Yes, I sang all the songs</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/reading-lord-of-the-rings-aloud-yes-i-sang-all-the-songs/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/reading-lord-of-the-rings-aloud-yes-i-sang-all-the-songs/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Nate Anderson]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 19:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lord of the Rings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading aloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tolkien]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/reading-lord-of-the-rings-aloud-yes-i-sang-all-the-songs/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[It's not easy, but you really <em>can</em> sing in Elvish if you try!]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Like Frodo himself, I wasn't sure we were going to make it all the way to the end of our quest. But this week, my family crossed an important life threshold: every member has now heard J.R.R. Tolkien's <em>Lord of the Rings</em> (LotR) read aloud—and sung aloud—in its entirety.</p>
<p>Five years ago, I read the series to my eldest daughter; this time, I read it for my wife and two younger children. It took a full year each time, reading 20–45 minutes before bed whenever we could manage it, to go "there and back again" with our heroes. The first half of <em>The Two Towers</em>, with its slow-talking Ents and a scattered Fellowship, nearly derailed us on both reads, but we rallied, pressing ahead even when iPad games and TV shows appeared more enticing. Reader, it was worth the push.</p>
<p>Gollum's ultimate actions on the edge of the Crack of Doom, the final moments of Sauron and Saruman as impotent mists blown off into the east, Frodo's woundedness and final ride to the Grey Havens—all of it remains powerful and left a suitable impression upon the new listeners.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/reading-lord-of-the-rings-aloud-yes-i-sang-all-the-songs/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/reading-lord-of-the-rings-aloud-yes-i-sang-all-the-songs/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>66</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/lotr-books-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/lotr-books-500x500-1729016749.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:text>Yes, it will take a while to read.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Qualcomm brings laptop-class CPU cores to phones with Snapdragon 8 Elite</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/qualcomm-brings-laptop-class-cpu-cores-to-phones-with-snapdragon-8-elite/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/qualcomm-brings-laptop-class-cpu-cores-to-phones-with-snapdragon-8-elite/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ARM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snapdragon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snapdragon 8 elite]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/qualcomm-brings-laptop-class-cpu-cores-to-phones-with-snapdragon-8-elite/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[New CPU cores replace more complicated mix-and-match of CPU architectures.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Qualcomm has <a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/products/mobile/snapdragon/smartphones/snapdragon-8-series-mobile-platforms/snapdragon-8-elite-mobile-platform">a new chip for flagship phones</a>, and the best part is that it uses an improved version of the Oryon CPU architecture that the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/10/qualcomm-snapdragon-x-elite-looks-like-the-windows-worlds-answer-to-apple-silicon/">Snapdragon X Elite chips</a> brought to Windows PCs earlier this year.</p>
<p>The Snapdragon 8 Elite is the follow-up to last year's <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/10/qualcomms-snapdragon-8-gen-3-promises-30-percent-faster-cpu/">Snapdragon 8 Gen 3</a>—yet another change to the naming convention that Qualcomm uses for its high-end phone chips, though, as usual, the number 8 is still involved. The 8 Elite uses a "brand-new, 2nd-generation Qualcomm Oryon CPU" with clock speeds up to 4.32 GHz, which Qualcomm says will improve performance by about 45 percent compared to the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3.</p>
<p>Rather than a mix of large, medium, and small CPU cores as it has used in the past, the 8 Elite has two "Prime" cores for hitting that high peak clock speed, while the other six are all "Performance" cores that peak at a lower 3.53 GHz. But it doesn't look like Qualcomm is using a mix of different CPU architectures anymore, choosing to distinguish the higher-performing core from the lower-performing ones by clock speed alone.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/qualcomm-brings-laptop-class-cpu-cores-to-phones-with-snapdragon-8-elite/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/qualcomm-brings-laptop-class-cpu-cores-to-phones-with-snapdragon-8-elite/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Snapdragon8Elite-InsideViewQRD-768x432.png" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Snapdragon8Elite-InsideViewQRD-500x500-1729620238.png" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Qualcomm</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Tesla, Warner Bros. sued for using AI ripoff of iconic Blade Runner imagery</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/tesla-warner-bros-sued-for-using-ai-ripoff-of-iconic-blade-runner-imagery/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/tesla-warner-bros-sued-for-using-ai-ripoff-of-iconic-blade-runner-imagery/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 18:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blade Runner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blade runner 2049]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyright]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyright law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warner bros. discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/tesla-warner-bros-sued-for-using-ai-ripoff-of-iconic-blade-runner-imagery/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA["That movie sucks," Elon Musk said in response to the lawsuit.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk may have personally used AI to rip off a <em>Blade Runner 2049</em> image for a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/10/elon-musk-makes-bold-claims-about-tesla-robotaxi-in-hollywood-backlot/">Tesla cybercab event </a>after producers rejected any association between their iconic sci-fi movie and Musk or any of his companies.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Alcon-Entertainment-v-Tesla-Complaint-10-21-2024.pdf">lawsuit</a> filed Tuesday, lawyers for Alcon Entertainment—exclusive rightsholder of the 2017 <em>Blade Runner 2049</em> movie—accused Warner Bros. Discovery (WBD) of conspiring with Musk and Tesla to steal the image and infringe Alcon's copyright to benefit financially off the brand association.</p>
<p>According to the complaint, WBD did not approach Alcon for permission until six hours before the Tesla event when Alcon "refused all permissions and adamantly objected" to linking their movie with Musk's cybercab.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/tesla-warner-bros-sued-for-using-ai-ripoff-of-iconic-blade-runner-imagery/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/tesla-warner-bros-sued-for-using-ai-ripoff-of-iconic-blade-runner-imagery/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>188</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Blade-Runner-movie-poster-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Blade-Runner-movie-poster-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>via Alcon Entertainment</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Meta Quest 3S is a disappointing half-step to Carmack’s low-cost VR vision</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/10/review-meta-quest-3s-is-cheaper-in-both-senses-of-the-word/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/10/review-meta-quest-3s-is-cheaper-in-both-senses-of-the-word/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 17:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta quest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta quest 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual reality]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/10/review-meta-quest-3s-is-cheaper-in-both-senses-of-the-word/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Significant visual and comfort compromises make last year's Quest 3 a better VR investment.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>It's been just over two years now since <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/12/john-carmack-leaves-meta-after-a-decade-fighting-to-make-vr-a-reality/">soon-to-depart</a> CTO John Carmack told a Meta Connect audience about his vision for a super low-end VR headset that came in at $250 and 250 grams. "We're not building that headset today, but I keep trying," Carmack <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/10/carmack-wants-a-250-vr-headset-to-counterpoint-the-1499-quest-pro/">said at the time</a> with some exasperation.</p>
<p>On the pricing half of the equation, the recently released Quest 3S headset is nearly on target for Carmack's hopes and dreams. Meta's new $299 headset is a significant drop from <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/10/meta-quest-3-review-mixed-reality-version-0-5/">the $499 Quest 3</a> and the cheapest price point for a Meta VR headset since the company raised the price of the aging Quest 2 to $400 <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/07/meta-quest-2-vr-headset-price-jumps-100-to-399-gets-zero-new-features/">back in the summer of 2022</a>. When you account for a few years of inflation in there, the Quest 3S is close to the $250 headset Carmack envisioned.</p>
<figure class="ars-img-shortcode id-2057689 align-center">
    <div>
                        <div class="ars-lightbox">
            <div class="ars-lightbox-item">
              <a data-pswp-width="1440" data-pswp-height="1080" data-pswp-srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-300x225.jpg 300w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-640x480.jpg 640w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-768x576.jpg 768w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-980x735.jpg 980w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-1440x1080.jpg 1440w" data-cropped="true" href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-1440x1080.jpg" target="_blank" class="cursor-zoom-in">
                <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1920" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-scaled.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-300x225.jpg 300w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-640x480.jpg 640w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-768x576.jpg 768w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-980x735.jpg 980w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.27-1440x1080.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px">
              </a>
              <div class="pswp-caption-content" id="caption-2057689">
                A new button on the underside of the Quest 3S lets you transition to pass-through mode at any time.
                                  <div class="ars-gallery-caption-credit">
                    Credit:
                                          Kyle Orland
                                      </div>
                              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
                  </div>
      </figure>

<p>Unfortunately, Meta must still seriously tackle the "250 grams" part of Carmack's vision. The 514g Quest 3S feels at least as unwieldy on your face as the 515g Quest 3, and both are still quite far from the "super light comforts" Carmack envisioned. Add in all the compromises Meta made so the Quest 3S could hit that lower price point, and you have a cheap, half-measure headset that we can only really recommend to the most price-conscious of VR consumers.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/10/review-meta-quest-3s-is-cheaper-in-both-senses-of-the-word/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/10/review-meta-quest-3s-is-cheaper-in-both-senses-of-the-word/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.39-scaled-768x432-1729617618.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/2024-10-22-13.14.39-scaled-500x500-1729617612.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Kyle Orland</media:credit><media:text>Look at all those dots.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Mercedes’ patented steering may finally make EVs exciting to drive</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/10/mercedes-patent-may-finally-solve-numb-steering-problem-of-new-cars/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/10/mercedes-patent-may-finally-solve-numb-steering-problem-of-new-cars/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 15:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes-Benz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steer-by-wire]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/10/mercedes-patent-may-finally-solve-numb-steering-problem-of-new-cars/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[It describes a way of generating feedback for the driver through the steering.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>New cars really are better than they used to be. They last longer, they're more efficient, and they're safer for the occupants in a crash. But it's not entirely a one-way street. If the last time you bought a car was <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2022/09/what-bmw-needs-to-nail-to-make-a-great-electric-m-car/#page-3">more than a decade ago</a>, you're probably shocked at the cumulative effect of inflation since then. But even ignoring sticker shock, there's also the matter of cars (almost) all having lifeless steering. But a <a href="https://register.dpma.de/DPMAregister/pat/PatSchrifteneinsicht?docId=DE102023003348A1&amp;page=1&amp;dpi=300&amp;lang=en&amp;full=true">patent</a> filed last year by Mercedes-Benz might have the answer.</p>
<p>Regular readers <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2022/01/new-cars-have-lost-their-steering-feel-heres-why-that-matters/">will have read me complain</a> about the death of steering feedback more than once. And that's a bad thing if you care about driving, or even if you don't. The late Richard Parry-Jones, an engineer whose career at Ford saw him rise to become CTO and head of global R&amp;D, tracked customer satisfaction data and was able to prove to skeptical colleagues that good steering was highly correlated with customer satisfaction "because bad steering is tiring," <a href="https://www.stevesaxty.com/sfvol2">he wrote</a>.</p>
<p>Mostly, it's down to a switch from hydraulic to electric power-assisted steering—in many cases, the electric motor is placed on the steering column, which has the side effect of filtering out road forces, keeping them from being transferred back up the column and to the driver's hands via the steering wheel.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/10/mercedes-patent-may-finally-solve-numb-steering-problem-of-new-cars/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/10/mercedes-patent-may-finally-solve-numb-steering-problem-of-new-cars/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>145</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/22C0417_009_0-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/22C0417_009_0-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Mercedes-Benz</media:credit><media:text>
</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Dow Jones says Perplexity is “freeriding,” sues over copyright infringement</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/dow-jones-says-perplexity-is-freeriding-sues-over-copyright-infringement/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/dow-jones-says-perplexity-is-freeriding-sues-over-copyright-infringement/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Daniel Thomas and Cristina Criddle, Financial Times]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyright]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LLMs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perplexity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/dow-jones-says-perplexity-is-freeriding-sues-over-copyright-infringement/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[AI startup reportedly "did not bother to respond" to notice of infringement.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Rupert Murdoch’s Dow Jones and the New York Post have accused artificial intelligence start-up Perplexity of a “brazen scheme” to rip off their journalism for its AI-driven search engine in a lawsuit filed in New York on Monday.</p>
<p>The publishers, both subsidiaries of News Corp, alleged the AI start-up, which is seeking to raise up to $1 billion in a funding round that will value it at $8 billion, was “engaging in a massive amount of illegal copying” of their work.</p>
<p>The lawsuit said Perplexity is “diverting customers and critical revenues” away from the news publishers, whose titles include The Wall Street Journal, “freeriding on the valuable content the publishers produce.”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/dow-jones-says-perplexity-is-freeriding-sues-over-copyright-infringement/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/dow-jones-says-perplexity-is-freeriding-sues-over-copyright-infringement/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>98</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/copyright-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/copyright-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Manuel Augusto Marino via Getty</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Hands-on with the 2024 iPad mini: Spot the differences</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/hands-on-with-the-2024-ipad-mini-spot-the-differences/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/hands-on-with-the-2024-ipad-mini-spot-the-differences/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A17 Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad mini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/hands-on-with-the-2024-ipad-mini-spot-the-differences/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[A quick look at what’s new in Apple’s tiny tablet.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>The iPad mini is a niche product, that much is clear. But for those who want an extra-small tablet, the launch of the sixth-generation iPad mini in 2021 was a red-letter day. For the first time in ages, the mini got close to the same kind of performance and features as its bigger brethren.</p>
<p>Then it didn’t get any updates for a couple of years. It was still a good tablet, but it wasn’t positioned to take advantage of new products or features on Apple’s docket like Apple Intelligence or the Apple Pencil Pro.</p>
<p>Enter the new 2024 refresh of the iPad mini, which releases October 23. For the most part, it’s the same as the previous generation—but Apple has laser-focused on a couple of tweaks to modernize the device just enough to keep it competitive in the company’s current ecosystem.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/hands-on-with-the-2024-ipad-mini-spot-the-differences/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/hands-on-with-the-2024-ipad-mini-spot-the-differences/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>70</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/iPad-mini-front-scaled-768x432-1729562225.jpeg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/iPad-mini-front-scaled-500x500-1729562250.jpeg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Samuel Axon</media:credit><media:text>The 2024 iPad mini.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>After seeing hundreds of launches, SpaceX’s rocket catch was a new thrill</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/10/after-seeing-hundreds-of-launches-spacexs-rocket-catch-was-a-new-thrill/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/10/after-seeing-hundreds-of-launches-spacexs-rocket-catch-was-a-new-thrill/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Stephen Clark]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:44:12 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Commercial space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[super heavy]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/10/after-seeing-hundreds-of-launches-spacexs-rocket-catch-was-a-new-thrill/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[For a few moments, my viewing angle made it look like the rocket was coming right at me.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>BOCA CHICA BEACH, Texas—I've taken some time to process what happened on the mudflats of South Texas a little more than a week ago and relived the scene in my mind countless times.</p>
<p>With each replay, it's still as astonishing as it was when I saw it on October 13, standing on an elevated platform less than 4 miles away. It was surreal watching SpaceX's enormous 20-story-tall Super Heavy rocket booster plummeting through the sky before being caught back at its launch pad by giant mechanical arms.</p>
<p>This is the way, according to SpaceX, to enable a future where it's possible to rapidly reuse rockets, not too different from the way airlines turn around their planes between flights. This is required for SpaceX to accomplish the company's mission, set out by Elon Musk two decades ago, of building a settlement on Mars.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/10/after-seeing-hundreds-of-launches-spacexs-rocket-catch-was-a-new-thrill/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/10/after-seeing-hundreds-of-launches-spacexs-rocket-catch-was-a-new-thrill/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>207</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/IMG_8012-copy-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/IMG_8012-copy-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Stephen Clark/Ars Technica</media:credit><media:text>Coming in for the catch.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>T-Mobile, AT&amp;T oppose unlocking rule, claim locked phones are good for users</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/t-mobile-att-oppose-unlocking-rule-claim-locked-phones-are-good-for-users/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/t-mobile-att-oppose-unlocking-rule-claim-locked-phones-are-good-for-users/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phone locking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[t-mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[verizon]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/t-mobile-att-oppose-unlocking-rule-claim-locked-phones-are-good-for-users/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Carriers fight plan to require unlocking of phones 60 days after activation.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>T-Mobile and AT&amp;T say US regulators should drop a plan to require unlocking of phones within 60 days of activation, claiming that locking phones to a carrier's network makes it possible to provide cheaper handsets to consumers. "If the Commission mandates a uniform unlocking policy, it is consumers—not providers—who stand to lose the most," T-Mobile alleged in an <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/ecfs/document/1017178290200/1">October 17 filing</a> with the Federal Communications Commission.</p>
<p>The proposed rule has support from consumer advocacy groups who say it will give users more choice and lower their costs. T-Mobile has been criticized for locking phones for up to a year, which makes it impossible to use a phone on a rival's network. T-Mobile claims that with a 60-day unlocking rule, "consumers risk losing access to the benefits of free or heavily subsidized handsets because the proposal would force providers to reduce the line-up of their most compelling handset offers."</p>
<p>If the proposed rule is enacted, "T-Mobile estimates that its prepaid customers, for example, would see subsidies reduced by 40 percent to 70 percent for both its lower and higher-end devices, such as the Moto G, Samsung A15, and iPhone 12," the carrier said. "A handset unlocking mandate would also leave providers little choice but to limit their handset offers to lower cost and often lesser performing handsets."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/t-mobile-att-oppose-unlocking-rule-claim-locked-phones-are-good-for-users/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/t-mobile-att-oppose-unlocking-rule-claim-locked-phones-are-good-for-users/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>215</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/phone-locking-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/phone-locking-500x500-1729540365.jpg" width="500"/>
</media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Basecamp-maker 37Signals says its “cloud exit” will save it $10M over 5 years</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/10/basecamp-maker-37signals-says-its-cloud-exit-will-save-it-10m-over-5-years/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/10/basecamp-maker-37signals-says-its-cloud-exit-will-save-it-10m-over-5-years/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Kevin Purdy]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 19:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[37signals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citrix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david heinemeier hansson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red hat]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/10/basecamp-maker-37signals-says-its-cloud-exit-will-save-it-10m-over-5-years/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Co-founder thinks other companies should consider a "swim against the stream."]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>37Signals is not a company that makes its policy or management decisions quietly.</p>
<p>The productivity software company was <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2006/10/5691/">an avowedly Mac-centric shop</a> until <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/02/apple-under-fire-for-disabling-iphone-web-apps-eu-asks-developers-to-weigh-in/">Apple's move to kill home screen web apps</a> (or Progressive Web Apps, or PWAs) led the firm and its very-public-facing co-founder, David Heinemeier Hansson, to declare a "<a href="https://x.com/dhh/status/1765412689130758313?prefetchTimestamp=1729528154263">Return to Windows</a>," followed by a <a href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/linux-as-the-new-developer-default-at-37signals-ef0823b7">stew of Windows/Mac/Linux</a>. The company <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/06/why-one-email-app-went-to-war-with-apple-and-why-neither-one-is-right/">waged a public battle with Apple</a> over its App Store subscription policies, and the resulting outcry helped <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2020/06/apple-opens-new-appeals-channel-for-devs-frustrated-by-app-store-guidelines/">nudge Apple a bit</a>. 37Signals has <a href="https://signalvnoise.com/">maintained an active blog for years</a>, its co-founders and employees have written <a href="https://37signals.com/books/">numerous business advice books</a>, and its blog and social media posts regularly hit the front pages of Hacker News.</p>
<p>So when 37Signals decided to pull its seven cloud-based apps off Amazon Web Services <a href="https://world.hey.com/dhh/why-we-re-leaving-the-cloud-654b47e0">in the fall of 2022</a>, it didn't do so quietly or without details. Back then, Hansson described his firm as paying "an at times almost absurd premium" for defense against "wild swings or towering peaks in usage." In early 2023, Hansson wrote that 37Signals expected to save $7 million over five years by buying more than $600,000 worth of Dell server gear and hosting its own apps.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/10/basecamp-maker-37signals-says-its-cloud-exit-will-save-it-10m-over-5-years/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/10/basecamp-maker-37signals-says-its-cloud-exit-will-save-it-10m-over-5-years/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>128</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-1358638792-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-1358638792-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Studies of migraine’s many triggers offer paths to new therapies</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/studies-of-migraines-many-triggers-offer-paths-to-new-therapies/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/studies-of-migraines-many-triggers-offer-paths-to-new-therapies/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Amber Dance, Knowable Magazine]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[migraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[migraines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/studies-of-migraines-many-triggers-offer-paths-to-new-therapies/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[One class of drugs has already found success in treating the painful, common attacks.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>For Cherise Irons, chocolate, red wine, and aged cheeses are dangerous. So are certain sounds, perfumes and other strong scents, cold weather, and thunderstorms. Stress and lack of sleep, too.</p>
<p>She suspects all of these things can trigger her migraine attacks, which manifest in a variety of ways: pounding pain in the back of her head, exquisite sensitivity to the slightest sound, even blackouts and partial paralysis.</p>
<p>Irons, 48, of Coral Springs, Florida, once worked as a school assistant principal. Now, she’s on disability due to her migraine. Irons has tried so many migraine medications she’s lost count—but none has helped for long. Even a few of the much-touted new drugs that have quelled episodes for many people with migraine have failed for Irons.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/studies-of-migraines-many-triggers-offer-paths-to-new-therapies/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/10/studies-of-migraines-many-triggers-offer-paths-to-new-therapies/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>79</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-2132184395-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-2132184395-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>skynesher via Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>It’s the Enterprise vs. the Gorn in Strange New Worlds clip</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/paramount-drops-new-clip-for-strange-new-worlds-at-nycc/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/paramount-drops-new-clip-for-strange-new-worlds-at-nycc/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 17:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York Comic Con]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek Section 31]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star trek strange new worlds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek: Lower Decks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek: Starfleet Academy]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/paramount-drops-new-clip-for-strange-new-worlds-at-nycc/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Also: a new clip for <em>Lower Decks</em> and premiere date for <em>Section 31</em> with Michelle Yeoh.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<div class="ars-video"><div class="relative" allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/llvMv5-ydyQ?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent"></div><div class="caption mt-1 inline-flex flex-row items-stretch gap-1 text-lg leading-tight text-gray-300">
    <div class="caption-icon bg-[left_top_5px] w-[10px] shrink-0"></div>
    <div class="caption-content">
      Sneak peek at S3 of <em>Star Trek: Strange New Worlds</em>.

          </div>
  </div>
</div>
<p>The Star Trek franchise made its presence known with a special panel during New York City Comic-Con this past weekend. Among the highlights: Paramount unveiled a three-minute preview clip from the third season of <em>Star Trek: Strange New Worlds</em> and a clip from the upcoming final season of <em>Star Trek: Lower Decks</em>.</p>
<p>In other news, while the first season of new series <em>Star Trek: Starfleet Academy</em> is still in production, Paramount has already renewed it for a second season and revealed that <em>Orphan Black</em> star Tatiana Maslany will be a recurring guest on the series. Tig Notaro, Oded Fehr, and Mary Wiseman will reprise their <em>Discovery</em> roles as Jett Reno, Admiral Vance, and Sylvia Tilly, respectively. And Robert Picardo of<em> Star Trek: Voyager</em> will be back as The Doctor—in a show set 900 years after the hologram physician first appeared.</p>
<p>The studio also announced an official premiere date and poster art for the <em>Star Trek: Discovery</em> spinoff film <em>Section 31</em> starring Michelle Yeoh: January 24, 2025. Miku Martineau plays a young Phillipa Georgiou in the film, which will give us the backstory for Georgiou's evil Mirror Universe counterpart, where she was a despotic emperor who murdered millions of her own people. Meanwhile, Yeoh's older Georgiou is tasked with protecting the United Federation of Planets as part of a black ops group called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Section_31_(Star_Trek)">Section 31</a> while dealing with all the blood she's spilled in her past.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/paramount-drops-new-clip-for-strange-new-worlds-at-nycc/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/10/paramount-drops-new-clip-for-strange-new-worlds-at-nycc/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>162</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/trek1-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/trek1-500x500-1729527888.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Paramount+</media:credit><media:text>&lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Strange New Worlds&lt;/em&gt; returns for a third season next year.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>ByteDance intern fired for planting malicious code in AI models</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/bytedance-intern-fired-for-planting-malicious-code-in-ai-models/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/bytedance-intern-fired-for-planting-malicious-code-in-ai-models/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chinese community party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generative ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large language models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LLMs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TikTok ban]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/bytedance-intern-fired-for-planting-malicious-code-in-ai-models/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Sabotage supposedly cost tens of millions, but TikTok owner ByteDance denies it.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>After rumors swirled that TikTok owner ByteDance had lost tens of millions after an intern sabotaged its AI models, ByteDance issued a statement this weekend hoping to silence all the social media chatter in China.</p>
<p>In a social media <a href="https://www.toutiao.com/w/1813324433807370/?target_app=4916">post</a> translated and reviewed by Ars, ByteDance clarified "facts" about "interns destroying large model training" and confirmed that one intern was fired in August.</p>
<p>According to ByteDance, the intern had held a position in the company's commercial technology team but was fired for committing "serious disciplinary violations." Most notably, the intern allegedly "maliciously interfered with the model training tasks" for a ByteDance research project, ByteDance said.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/bytedance-intern-fired-for-planting-malicious-code-in-ai-models/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/bytedance-intern-fired-for-planting-malicious-code-in-ai-models/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>79</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="432" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-845006454-768x432.jpg" width="768">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/GettyImages-845006454-500x500-1729527542.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>ilyakalinin | iStock / Getty Images Plus</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
      </channel>
</rss>