<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
        <atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
        <description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:17:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <sy:updatePeriod>
            hourly        </sy:updatePeriod>
        <sy:updateFrequency>
            1        </sy:updateFrequency>
        
<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
            <item>
                <title>Unless users take action, Android will let Gemini access third-party apps</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/unless-users-take-action-android-will-let-gemini-access-third-party-apps/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/unless-users-take-action-android-will-let-gemini-access-third-party-apps/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 23:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/unless-users-take-action-android-will-let-gemini-access-third-party-apps/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Important changes to Android devices took effect starting Monday.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Starting today, Google is implementing a change that will enable its Gemini AI engine to interact with third-party apps, such as WhatsApp, even when users previously configured their devices to block such interactions. Users who don't want their previous settings to be overridden may have to take action.</p>
<p>An email Google sent recently informing users of the change linked to a <a href="https://support.google.com/gemini/answer/13594961?hl=en&amp;visit_id=638842317183560022-880737628&amp;p=e_live_data&amp;rd=1#extensions">notification page</a> that said that “human reviewers (including service providers) read, annotate, and process” the data Gemini accesses. The email provides no useful guidance for preventing the changes from taking effect. The email said users can block the apps that Gemini interacts with, but even in those cases, data is stored for 72 hours.</p>
<img width="1024" height="930" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/android-gemini-email-notification-1024x930.jpg" class="center large" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/android-gemini-email-notification-1024x930.jpg 1024w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/android-gemini-email-notification-640x581.jpg 640w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/android-gemini-email-notification-768x697.jpg 768w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/android-gemini-email-notification-980x890.jpg 980w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/android-gemini-email-notification.jpg 1372w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px">
      An email Google recently sent to Android users.
    
<h2>No, Google, it’s <em>not</em> good news</h2>
<p>The email never explains how users can fully extricate Gemini from their Android devices and seems to contradict itself on how or whether this is even possible. At one point, it says the changes “will automatically start rolling out” today and will give Gemini access to apps such as WhatsApp, Messages, and Phone “whether your Gemini apps activity is on or off.” A few sentences later, the email says, “If you have already turned these features off, they will remain off.” Nowhere in the email or the support pages it links to are Android users informed how to remove Gemini integrations completely.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/unless-users-take-action-android-will-let-gemini-access-third-party-apps/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/unless-users-take-action-android-will-let-gemini-access-third-party-apps/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/gemini-android-1152x648.png" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/gemini-android-500x500-1751929202.png" width="500"/>
</media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>What would a cheap, Apple A18-powered MacBook actually be good at?</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/apple/2025/07/what-would-a-cheap-apple-a18-powered-macbook-actually-be-good-at/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/apple/2025/07/what-would-a-cheap-apple-a18-powered-macbook-actually-be-good-at/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 21:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook Air]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/apple/2025/07/what-would-a-cheap-apple-a18-powered-macbook-actually-be-good-at/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Op-ed: A Mac with an iPhone chip inside could be great—for the right audience.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Some Apple rumors just don't go away, hanging around in perpetuity either because they reflect things that Apple is actually testing in its labs or because hope springs eternal. A HomePod-like device with a screen? A replacement for the dear, departed 27-inch iMac? Touchscreen MacBooks? The return of TouchID fingerprint scanning via a sensor located beneath a screen? Maybe these things are coming, but they ain't here yet.</p>
<p>However, few rumors have had the longevity or staying power of "Apple is planning a low-cost MacBook," versions of which have been circulating since at least the late-2000s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netbook">netbook craze</a>. And yet, despite seismic shifts in just about everything—three distinct processor instruction sets, two CEOs, innumerable design changes, and global trade upheaval—Apple's cheapest modern laptops have started around $1,000 for <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2004/10/19Apple-Unveils-Fastest-Most-Affordable-iBook-G4-Ever/">more than two decades</a>.</p>
<p>Last week, supply chain analyst Ming-Chi Kuo (whose Apple predictions aren't always correct, but whose track record <em>is</em> better than your garden variety broken-clock prognosticators) kicked up another round of these rumors, claiming that Apple was preparing to manufacture a new low-cost MacBook based on the iPhone’s A18 Pro chip. Kuo claims it will come in multiple colors, similar to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/apple/2025/03/apples-349-ipad-11-is-missing-a-lot-but-its-still-all-the-ipad-most-people-need/">Apple's lower-cost A16 iPad</a>, and will use a 13-inch screen.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/apple/2025/07/what-would-a-cheap-apple-a18-powered-macbook-actually-be-good-at/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/apple/2025/07/what-would-a-cheap-apple-a18-powered-macbook-actually-be-good-at/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>61</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/DSC_5669-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/DSC_5669-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Valentina Palladino</media:credit><media:text>The 2018 MacBook Air, which still lives on today as the low-cost M1 MacBook Air. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Samsung and Epic Games call a truce in app store lawsuit</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/samsung-and-epic-games-call-a-truce-in-app-store-lawsuit/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/samsung-and-epic-games-call-a-truce-in-app-store-lawsuit/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 20:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic Games]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/samsung-and-epic-games-call-a-truce-in-app-store-lawsuit/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Epic's Tim Sweeney says Samsung will make changes, but no one has specifics.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Epic Games, buoyed by the massive success of Fortnite, has spent the last few years throwing elbows in the mobile industry to get its app store on more phones. It scored an antitrust win against Google in late 2023, and the following year it <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/09/epic-lawsuit-says-samsung-coordinated-with-google-to-get-around-trial-verdict/">went after Samsung</a> for deploying "Auto Blocker" on its Android phones, which would make it harder for users to install the Epic Games Store. Now, the parties have settled the case just days before Samsung will unveil its latest phones.</p>
<p>The Epic Store drama began several years ago when the company defied Google and Apple rules about accepting outside payments in the mega-popular <em>Fortnite</em>. Both stores pulled the app, and Epic sued. Apple emerged victorious, with <em>Fortnite</em> only returning to the iPhone recently. Google, however, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/12/googles-android-app-store-monopoly-violates-antitrust-law-jury-finds/">lost the case</a> after Epic showed it worked behind the scenes to stymie the development of app stores like Epic's.</p>
<p>Google is still working to avoid penalties in that long-running case, but Epic thought it smelled a conspiracy last year. It filed a similar lawsuit against Samsung, accusing it of implementing a feature to block third-party app stores. The issue comes down to the addition of a feature to Samsung phones called Auto Blocker, which is similar to Google's new <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/android-16-review-post-hype/">Advanced Protection in Android 16</a>. It protects against attacks over USB, disables link previews, and scans apps more often for malicious activity. Most importantly, it blocks app sideloading. Without sideloading, there's no way to install the Epic Games Store or any of the content inside it.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/samsung-and-epic-games-call-a-truce-in-app-store-lawsuit/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/samsung-and-epic-games-call-a-truce-in-app-store-lawsuit/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Samsung-back-1-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Samsung-back-1-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Ryan Whitwam</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Ancient skull may have been half human, half Neanderthal child</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/ancient-skull-may-have-been-half-human-half-neanderthal-child/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/ancient-skull-may-have-been-half-human-half-neanderthal-child/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 20:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/ancient-skull-may-have-been-half-human-half-neanderthal-child/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[CT scans hint at hybridization, but it will take extracting and analyzing a DNA sample to be certain.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Back in 1929, archaeologists unearthed several human skeletons (seven adults and three children) while excavating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skhul_Cave">Skuhl Cave</a> just south of Haifa, Israel. Dating back 140,000 years to the end of the Middle Pleistocene, most were classified as early <em>Homo sapiens</em>. But one skeleton was that of a child, between the age of 3 and 5 years old whose features seemed to show a mix of early human and Neanderthal characteristics. A new analysis involving CT scanning may resolve the long-standing debate, according to <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0003552125000366">a new paper</a> published in the journal L’Anthropologie.</p>
<p>Neanderthals and <em>Homo sapiens</em> traded genes frequently during the period when their populations overlapped. "The two came in contact as modern humans began their major expansion out of Africa, which occurred roughly 60,000 years ago," Ars Science Editor John Timmer <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/07/much-of-neanderthal-genetic-diversity-came-from-modern-humans/">previously reported</a>. "Humans picked up some Neanderthal DNA through interbreeding, while the Neanderthal population, always fairly small, was swept away by the waves of new arrivals."</p>
<p>Nor is this the first case of a possible hybrid hominid species. <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-018-0455-x">In 2018</a>, scientists analyzed a sliver of bone excavated from a cave site in Russia. The findings made global headlines when the team concluded that the individual to whom it belonged—a young girl of about 13, dubbed "Denny"—was the offspring of a Neanderthal mother and a Denisovan father. This suggested that rather than dying out, Neanderthals may have been absorbed by other species; such inbreeding may have been more common than previously thought.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/ancient-skull-may-have-been-half-human-half-neanderthal-child/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/ancient-skull-may-have-been-half-human-half-neanderthal-child/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/hybrid1-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/hybrid1-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Israel Hershkovitz</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Measles cases reach 33-year high as RFK Jr. pursues anti-vaccine agenda</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/07/measles-cases-reach-33-year-high-as-rfk-jr-pursues-anti-vaccine-agenda/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/07/measles-cases-reach-33-year-high-as-rfk-jr-pursues-anti-vaccine-agenda/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[measles]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/07/measles-cases-reach-33-year-high-as-rfk-jr-pursues-anti-vaccine-agenda/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[There have been at least 1,281 cases since the start of the year.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend, the tally of measles cases reached 1,281, setting a new case record since the highly contagious viral disease was declared eliminated from the country in 2000. The previous record was set in 2019, when there were 1,274 cases and officials warned that the US had narrowly avoided losing the elimination status.</p>
<p>Overall, the current case tally is a 33-year high for the preventable infection, and the outlook for the country is bleak. Vaccination rates have <a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2024/10/us-vaccinations-fall-again-as-more-parents-refuse-lifesaving-shots-for-kids/">only fallen since the pandemic</a>, and the top health official in the country—Robert F. Kennedy Jr.—is an unswerving anti-vaccine activist who has spent his short time in the position so far spreading <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2025/03/14/rfk-jr-measles-vaccine-death-claims-scientists-disagree/">dangerous misinformation</a> about the <a href="https://www.politifact.com/factchecks/2025/may/16/robert-f-kennedy-jr/measles-vaccine-safety-testing-immunity-fetal-debr/">measles vaccine</a>—as well as peddling <a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/cod-liver-oil-embraced-amid-texas-measles-outbreak-doctors-fight-misinfo/">unproven treatments</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/measles-outbreak-hits-208-cases-as-federal-outbreak-response-goes-off-the-rails/">downplaying the infection</a>.</p>
<p>Experts expect that the US will lose its elimination status, which will occur if the virus spreads uninterrupted for 12 months. To block transmission, experts say populations must maintain vaccination rates of 95 percent or higher. But, nationally, the vaccination rate among kindergartners has fallen to <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/73/wr/mm7341a3.htm?s_cid=mm7341a3_w">92.7 percent in the latest data</a>, with some communities having vaccination rates far lower, leaving them vulnerable to widespread outbreaks.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/07/measles-cases-reach-33-year-high-as-rfk-jr-pursues-anti-vaccine-agenda/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/07/measles-cases-reach-33-year-high-as-rfk-jr-pursues-anti-vaccine-agenda/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>104</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/GettyImages-2053751760-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/GettyImages-2053751760-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Povorozniuk Liudmyla</media:credit><media:text>Measles rash on the body of a child.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Trump and Congress finalize law that could hurt your Wi-Fi</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trump-and-congress-finalize-law-that-could-hurt-your-wi-fi/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trump-and-congress-finalize-law-that-could-hurt-your-wi-fi/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 18:33:28 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spectrum Auction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wi-fi]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trump-and-congress-finalize-law-that-could-hurt-your-wi-fi/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[FCC to auction spectrum that could include 6 GHz band used for next-gen Wi-Fi.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The Federal Communications Commission has regained its authority to hold spectrum auctions and could use that power to take spectrum away from Wi-Fi networks and license it to mobile carriers AT&amp;T, Verizon, and T-Mobile.</p>
<p>As we <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/senate-gop-budget-bill-has-little-noticed-provision-that-could-hurt-your-wi-fi/">previously wrote</a>, the Senate budget bill pitched by Ted Cruz (R-Texas) called for at least 800 MHz to be auctioned and allowed part of it to be taken from the 6 GHz band that's being used to boost speeds in the new generation of Wi-Fi networks. The House previously voted to exclude the entire 6 GHz band from spectrum auctions but ultimately adopted the Senate's language in a <a href="https://clerk.house.gov/Votes/2025190">218-214 vote</a> when it approved the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/house-bill/1/text">final budget bill</a> on July 3. It was signed into law by President Trump on July 4.</p>
<p>The new law also allows spectrum to be taken from the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/ex-fcc-chair-ajit-pai-is-now-a-wireless-lobbyist-and-enemy-of-cable-companies/">Citizens Broadband Radio Service (CBRS)</a>, which goes from 3.55 to 3.7 GHz. While other spectrum bands could be targeted too, advocates say it would be hard for the FCC to fulfill the congressional mandate without taking spectrum from Wi-Fi, CBRS, or both.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trump-and-congress-finalize-law-that-could-hurt-your-wi-fi/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trump-and-congress-finalize-law-that-could-hurt-your-wi-fi/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/wi-fi-data-1152x648-1751912403.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/wi-fi-data-500x500-1751912395.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | mattjeacock</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Fubo pays $3.4M to settle claims it illegally shared user data with advertisers</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/fubo-pays-3-4m-to-settle-claims-it-illegally-shared-user-data-with-advertisers/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/fubo-pays-3-4m-to-settle-claims-it-illegally-shared-user-data-with-advertisers/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 18:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[class action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fubo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/fubo-pays-3-4m-to-settle-claims-it-illegally-shared-user-data-with-advertisers/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Fubo was accused of giving advertisers customers' PII without their consent. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Fubo has agreed to pay $3.4 million to settle a class-action lawsuit that accused the sports-streaming service provider of unlawfully distributing customers' personally identifiable information (PII) without their consent.</p>
<p>In December 2023, Ne’Tosha Burdette filed a complaint [<a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/burdette-v-fubotv-inc.-complaint.pdf">PDF</a>] against Fubo with the stated goal of stopping Fubo’s "unlawful disclosure of its customers'" PII. The complaint argued that Fubo violated the Video Privacy Protection Act (VPPA), “which prohibits the disclosure of consumers’ video viewing history without their informed, written consent." The filing added:</p>
<blockquote><p>Critically, Defendant utilizes sophisticated tracking technology that collects its subscribers’ personally identifiable information… including information which identifies a person as having viewed specific videos on Defendant’s streaming service. Defendant knowingly discloses this information to third party advertisers so that they can target specific users with specifically tailored advertisements based on their viewing history.</p></blockquote>
<p>Fubo’s privacy policy at the time stated that Fubo collected various data from its users, such as location information—including “precise or near-precise geolocation” and the use of “GPS coordinates”—as well as device and usage information (including “pages and content viewed and order of those pages" and "content recorded on FuboTV,”) per the complaint.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/fubo-pays-3-4m-to-settle-claims-it-illegally-shared-user-data-with-advertisers/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/fubo-pays-3-4m-to-settle-claims-it-illegally-shared-user-data-with-advertisers/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-2022925606-1152x648-1751910061.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-2022925606-500x500-1751910050.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Gabby Jones/Bloomberg via Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>“No honor among thieves”: M&amp;S hacking group starts turf war</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/no-honor-among-thieves-ms-hacking-group-starts-turf-war/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/no-honor-among-thieves-ms-hacking-group-starts-turf-war/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kieran Smith, Financial Times]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 18:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercrime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cybercriminals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extortion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/no-honor-among-thieves-ms-hacking-group-starts-turf-war/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[A clash between criminal ransomware groups could result in victims being extorted twice.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The ransomware group linked to the recent cyberattacks on UK retailers Marks and Spencer, Harrods, and the Co-Op has begun a turf war with its rivals, triggering a battle within the industry that could bring more hacks and further fallout for corporate victims.</p>
<p>DragonForce, a group of largely Russian-speaking cyber criminals behind a spate of high-profile attacks this year, has clashed with one of its biggest competitors RansomHub, according to cybersecurity experts tracking the battle to dominate the booming criminal ransomware sector.</p>
<p>They warn that the conflict between the two groups, which operate in the ransomware-as-a-service (RaaS) market, could increase risks for companies, including the potential of being extorted twice.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/no-honor-among-thieves-ms-hacking-group-starts-turf-war/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/no-honor-among-thieves-ms-hacking-group-starts-turf-war/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-758313915-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-758313915-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Mehau Kulyk/Science Photo Library via Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>US may get its own glitchy version of TikTok if Trump’s deal works out</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trumps-shaky-plan-to-save-tiktok-may-push-users-to-buggy-version-of-app/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trumps-shaky-plan-to-save-tiktok-may-push-users-to-buggy-version-of-app/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 16:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bytedance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tariffs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TikTok ban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us-china trade war]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trumps-shaky-plan-to-save-tiktok-may-push-users-to-buggy-version-of-app/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Here’s why Trump is “not confident” he can sell China on his TikTok deal.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Could Donald Trump possibly follow through on his campaign promise to save TikTok by finally making a deal that keeps the app operating in the US without compromising America's national security?</p>
<p>Outlook not so good.</p>
<p>Despite <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/tiktok-building-new-version-app-ahead-expected-u-s-sale">The Information reporting</a> that a new version of TikTok is being prepped to launch in the US market this September, even Trump can't be sure the deal is imminent.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trumps-shaky-plan-to-save-tiktok-may-push-users-to-buggy-version-of-app/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trumps-shaky-plan-to-save-tiktok-may-push-users-to-buggy-version-of-app/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>83</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-2208643167-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-2208643167-500x500-1751904265.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>VCG / Contributor | Visual China Group</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Oldest wooden tools in East Asia may have come from any of three species</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/did-denisovans-or-homo-erectus-make-the-oldest-wooden-tools-in-east-asia/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/did-denisovans-or-homo-erectus-make-the-oldest-wooden-tools-in-east-asia/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kiona N. Smith]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 16:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancient people did stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denisovans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hominins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homo erectus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homo heidelbergensis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wooden tools]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/did-denisovans-or-homo-erectus-make-the-oldest-wooden-tools-in-east-asia/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[The find may require rethinking the so-called "Bamboo Hypothesis."]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Someone made very sophisticated wooden tools in China 300,000 years ago, and it might have been Denisovans or even <em>Homo erectus</em>.</p>
<p>The digging sticks, curved root-slicers, and a handful of somewhat puzzling implements were all found at a lakeshore site called Gantangqing. They are the oldest wooden tools from East Asia so far. All the previous Pleistocene tools found in the area were made from harder material like stone, bone, or antler. But logic suggests that hominins must have prepared and used softer materials as well. That thought led archaeologists to what is called the Bamboo Hypothesis: the idea that during the Pleistocene, hominins (including our own species) might have used bamboo the way wood gets used elsewhere.</p>
<p>The jury is still out on bamboo, because there is no actual evidence of bamboo tools yet. What we now have, it turns out, are nearly three dozen tools made of wood.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/did-denisovans-or-homo-erectus-make-the-oldest-wooden-tools-in-east-asia/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/did-denisovans-or-homo-erectus-make-the-oldest-wooden-tools-in-east-asia/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/topphoto-1152x648.png" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/topphoto-500x500.png" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Liu et al. 2025</media:credit><media:text>These tools, with their tips carefully whittled into chisel-like shapes, may have helped ancient hominins forage on the shores of what's now Lake Fuxian in China.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>F1 in Britain: Terrible English summer weather equals entertaining race</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/f1-in-britain-terrible-english-summer-weather-equals-entertaining-race/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/f1-in-britain-terrible-english-summer-weather-equals-entertaining-race/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 15:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[F1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Formula 1]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/f1-in-britain-terrible-english-summer-weather-equals-entertaining-race/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Maybe Bernie Ecclestone was right about fitting racetracks with sprinklers.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The heat dome that oppressed much of Europe has broken. Not a drop of rain marred the 24 hour races at Le Mans, the Nürburgring, or Spa-Francorchamps, held unusually over consecutive weekends this June. Similarly, last weekend's Austrian Grand Prix took place under scorching skies that were baking the Tyrolean mountains. No such luck for the vast crowds at Silverstone attending the British Grand Prix this past weekend, who definitely needed their waterproofs. On the plus side, the addition of rain certainly made things interesting.</p>
<p>Like many British race circuits, Silverstone was a former World War II airbase. Originally home to Wellington Bombers, it's very exposed to the wind, which was gusting at times during practice and qualifying, making life complicated for the drivers. Lewis Hamilton made the home crowd smile by topping the time charts during FP1. Hamilton has struggled to get to grips with his new Ferrari for much of this season, but at Silverstone he looked much more comfortable, finishing FP2 less than a 10th of a second behind his teammate, Charles Leclerc, although neither could match McLaren's Lando Norris for outright speed.</p>
<p>On Saturday, it was Red Bull's Max Verstappen who rose to the top, snatching pole position from the McLarens of Oscar Piastri and Norris by about a 10th of a second. George Russell's Mercedes was competitive in the colder temperatures, securing fourth on the grid ahead of the Ferraris of Hamilton and Leclerc. Mercedes' young rookie, Kimi Antonelli, qualified seventh but would start 10th as a result of a penalty acquired in Austria, and Haas rookie Oliver Bearman put in the eighth-fastest time, but ignoring a red flag during Saturday's final practice session landed him with a 10-place grid penalty. As it was, Aston Martin's Fernando Alonso lined up seventh for the race, followed by Pierre Gasly's Alpine, Carlos Sainz in the first Williams, and then Antonelli rounding out the top 10.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/f1-in-britain-terrible-english-summer-weather-equals-entertaining-race/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/f1-in-britain-terrible-english-summer-weather-equals-entertaining-race/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>55</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-2223835103-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-2223835103-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Clive Mason/Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Oscar Piastri's McLaren emerges from the spray during the 2025 British Grand Prix at Silverstone in England.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>How a big shift in training LLMs led to a capability explosion</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/how-a-big-shift-in-training-llms-led-to-a-capability-explosion/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/how-a-big-shift-in-training-llms-led-to-a-capability-explosion/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Timothy B. Lee]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 11:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[explainers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imitation learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reinforcement learning]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/how-a-big-shift-in-training-llms-led-to-a-capability-explosion/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Reinforcement learning, explained with a minimum of math and jargon.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>In April 2023, a few weeks after the launch of GPT-4, the Internet went wild for two new software projects with the audacious names BabyAGI and AutoGPT.</p>
<p>“Over the past week, developers around the world have begun building ‘autonomous agents’ that work with large language models (LLMs) such as OpenAI’s GPT-4 to solve complex problems,” Mark Sullivan <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90880294/auto-gpt-and-babyagi-how-autonomous-agents-are-bringing-generative-ai-to-the-masses" rel="">wrote</a> for Fast Company. “Autonomous agents can already perform tasks as varied as conducting web research, writing code, and creating to-do lists.”</p>
<p>BabyAGI and AutoGPT repeatedly prompted GPT-4 in an effort to elicit agent-like behavior. The first prompt would give GPT-4 a goal (like “create a 7-day meal plan for me”) and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FeIIaJUN-4A" rel="">ask it</a> to come up with a to-do list (it might generate items like “Research healthy meal plans,” “plan meals for the week,” and “write the recipes for each dinner in diet.txt”).</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/how-a-big-shift-in-training-llms-led-to-a-capability-explosion/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/how-a-big-shift-in-training-llms-led-to-a-capability-explosion/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>77</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/ai-towers-hanoi-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/ai-towers-hanoi-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Aurich Lawson | Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Figuring out why a nap might help people see things in new ways</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/figuring-out-why-a-nap-might-help-people-see-things-in-new-ways/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/figuring-out-why-a-nap-might-help-people-see-things-in-new-ways/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jacek Krywko]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 11:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neurobiology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sleep]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/figuring-out-why-a-nap-might-help-people-see-things-in-new-ways/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[An EEG signal of sleep is associated with better performance on a mental task.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Dmitri Mendeleev famously saw the complete arrangement of the periodic table after falling asleep on his desk. He claimed in his dream he saw a table where all the elements fell into place, and he wrote it all down when he woke up. By having a eureka moment right after a nap, he joined a club full of rather talented people: Mary Shelley, Thomas Edison, and Salvador Dali.</p>
<p>To figure out if there’s a grain of truth to all these anecdotes, a team of German scientists at the Hamburg University, led by cognitive science researcher Anika T. Löwe, conducted an experiment designed to trigger such nap-following strokes of genius—and catch them in the act with EEG brain monitoring gear. And they kind of succeeded.</p>
<h2>Catching Edison’s cup</h2>
<p>“Thomas Edison had this technique where he held a cup or something like that when he was napping in his chair,” says Nicolas Schuck, a professor of cognitive science at the Hamburg University and senior author of the study. “When he fell asleep too deeply, the cup falling from his hand would wake him up—he was convinced that was the way to trigger these eureka moments.” While dozing off in a chair with a book or a cup doesn’t seem particularly radical, a number of cognitive scientists got serious about re-creating Edison’s approach to insights and testing it in their experiments.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/figuring-out-why-a-nap-might-help-people-see-things-in-new-ways/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/figuring-out-why-a-nap-might-help-people-see-things-in-new-ways/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>69</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-1054583202-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-1054583202-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>XAVIER GALIANA</media:credit><media:text>The guy in the back may be doing a more useful activity.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>The curious rise of giant tablets on wheels</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/the-curious-rise-of-giant-tablets-on-wheels/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/the-curious-rise-of-giant-tablets-on-wheels/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monitors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tablet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TVs]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/the-curious-rise-of-giant-tablets-on-wheels/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Hands-on with KTC's 32-inch Android tablet on a rolling pedestal, the A32Q7 Pro. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Over the past few years, LG has set off a strange tech trend that’s been rolling onto devices sold across Amazon and other online electronics retailers.</p>
<p>In 2022, the company launched the <a href="https://www.lg.com/us/lifestyle-products/lg-27art10akpl-lifestyle-screen">StanbyME</a>, which is essentially a $1,000 27-inch tablet running LG's smart TV operating system (OS), webOS, but lacking a tuner. LG's press release announcing the device described it as a “wireless private TV screen with a built-in battery” that is easily portable and ideal for watching shows and movies, in addition to  “video conferencing with family and coworkers and viewing online lectures.”</p>
<p>Today, the StanbyME competes against a slew of similar devices, including some <a href="https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10489126">from Samsung</a>, but mostly from smaller brands and running Android.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/the-curious-rise-of-giant-tablets-on-wheels/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/07/the-curious-rise-of-giant-tablets-on-wheels/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>120</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/20250626_163545-1152x648-1751912015.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/20250626_163545-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Scharon Harding</media:credit><media:text>KTC's MegPad 32-inch Android Tablet (A32Q7 Pro).</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Rocket Report: Japan’s workhorse booster takes a bow; you can invest in SpaceX now</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/07/rocket-report-japans-workhorse-booster-takes-a-bow-you-can-invest-in-spacex-now/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/07/rocket-report-japans-workhorse-booster-takes-a-bow-you-can-invest-in-spacex-now/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Eric Berger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shuttle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/07/rocket-report-japans-workhorse-booster-takes-a-bow-you-can-invest-in-spacex-now/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA["We will be able to industrialize Zephyr production up to 50 units per year."]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Edition 8.01 of the Rocket Report! Today's edition will be a little shorter than normal because, for one day only, we celebrate fake rockets—fireworks—rather than the real thing. For our American readers, we hope you have a splendid Fourth of July holiday weekend. For our non-American readers, you may be wondering what the heck is happening in our country right now. Alas, making sense of &lt;waves hands&gt; all this is beyond the scope of this humble little newsletter.</p>
<p>As always, we <a href="https://arstechnica.wufoo.com/forms/launch-stories/">welcome reader submissions</a>, and if you don't want to miss an issue, please subscribe using the box below (the form will not appear on AMP-enabled versions of the site). Each report will include information on small-, medium-, and heavy-lift rockets as well as a quick look ahead at the next three launches on the calendar.</p>
<figure class="ars-img-shortcode id-1314289 align-center">
    <div>
                        <img decoding="async" width="560" height="81" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png" class="center full" alt="" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png 560w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll-300x43.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
                  </div>
      </figure>

<p><strong>Will Orbex ever launch an orbital rocket</strong>? Orbex, a launch services company based in the United Kingdom, has announced the postponement of its first orbital launch to 2026 due to infrastructure limitations and other issues, <a href="https://orbitaltoday.com/2025/06/24/uks-orbex-delays-first-launch-to-2026-cites-infrastructure-and-funding-challenges/">Orbital Today reports</a>. At the Paris Air Show at Le Bourget, Orbex chief executive Miguel Bello Mora announced that the company is now targeting next year for the liftoff of its Prime rocket from SaxaVord in Scotland. He said the delay is partly due to the limited launch infrastructure at SaxaVord and a "bottleneck" in site operations.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/07/rocket-report-japans-workhorse-booster-takes-a-bow-you-can-invest-in-spacex-now/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/07/rocket-report-japans-workhorse-booster-takes-a-bow-you-can-invest-in-spacex-now/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>231</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Themis_on_the_way_to_Kiruna-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Themis_on_the_way_to_Kiruna-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>ESA/ArianeGroup</media:credit><media:text>Europe’s first reusable rocket main stage demonstrator, Themis, is being transported to its launch pad at Esrange Space Centre, Sweden.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Provider of covert surveillance app spills passwords for 62,000 users</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/provider-of-covert-surveillance-app-spills-passwords-for-62000-users/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/provider-of-covert-surveillance-app-spills-passwords-for-62000-users/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveillance]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/provider-of-covert-surveillance-app-spills-passwords-for-62000-users/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Creators say app is intended for parental monitoring. So why the emphasis on stealth?]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The maker of a phone app that is advertised as providing a stealthy means for monitoring all activities on an Android device spilled email addresses, plain-text passwords, and other sensitive data belonging to 62,000 users, a researcher discovered recently.</p>
<p>A security flaw in the app, branded Catwatchful, allowed researcher Eric Daigle to download a <a href="https://ericdaigle.ca/posts/taking-over-60k-spyware-user-accounts/">trove of sensitive data</a>, which belonged to account holders who used the covert app to monitor phones. The leak, made possible by a SQL injection vulnerability, allowed anyone who exploited it to access the accounts and all data stored in them.</p>
<h2>Unstoppable</h2>
<p>Catwatchful creators emphasize the app's stealth and security. While the promoters claim the app is legal and intended for parents monitoring their children's online activities, the emphasis on stealth has raised concerns that it's being aimed at people with other agendas.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/provider-of-covert-surveillance-app-spills-passwords-for-62000-users/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/07/provider-of-covert-surveillance-app-spills-passwords-for-62000-users/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>81</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/getty-surveillance-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/getty-surveillance-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | kontekbrothers</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Judge: You can’t ban DEI grants without bothering to define DEI</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/doge-told-the-nih-which-grants-to-cancel-with-no-scientific-review/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/doge-told-the-nih-which-grants-to-cancel-with-no-scientific-review/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[John Timmer]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 17:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NIH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/doge-told-the-nih-which-grants-to-cancel-with-no-scientific-review/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[A written ruling details why a judge restored funding for many NIH grants.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>In mid-June, a federal judge <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/judge-slams-nih-grant-cuts-as-racist-appalling-white-house-attacks-judge/">issued a stinging rebuke</a> to the Trump administration, declaring that its decision to cancel the funding for many grants issued by the National Institutes of Health was illegal, and suggesting that the policy was likely animated by racism. But the detailed reasoning behind his decision wasn't released at the time. The <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mad.282917/gov.uscourts.mad.282917.163.0.pdf">written portion</a> of the decision was finally issued on Wednesday, and it has a number of notable features.</p>
<p>For starters, the judge who issued the decision felt compelled to respond to a pair of Supreme Court decisions that were issued in the intervening weeks, which could have potentially limited the scope of his earlier decision.  Regardless, the court continues to find that the government's actions were arbitrary and capricious, in part because the government never bothered to define the problems that would get a grant canceled. As a result, officials within the NIH simply canceled lists of grants they received from DOGE without bothering to examine their scientific merit, and then struggled to retroactively describe a policy that justified the actions afterward—a process that led several of them to resign.</p>
<h2>A limited verdict</h2>
<p>The issue before Judge William Young of the District of Massachusetts was whether the government had followed the law in terminating grants funded by the National Institutes of Health. After a short trial, Young issued a verbal ruling that the government hadn't, and that he had concluded that its actions were the product of "racial discrimination and discrimination against America’s LGBTQ. community." But the details of his decisions and the evidence that motivated them had to wait for a written ruling, which is now available.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/doge-told-the-nih-which-grants-to-cancel-with-no-scientific-review/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/07/doge-told-the-nih-which-grants-to-cancel-with-no-scientific-review/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>340</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-2214393807-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/GettyImages-2214393807-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Kayla Bartkowski</media:credit><media:text>An anti-DOGE protestor in front of an NIH building.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Meta’s “AI superintelligence” effort sounds just like its failed “metaverse”</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/metas-ai-superintelligence-effort-sounds-just-like-its-failed-metaverse/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/metas-ai-superintelligence-effort-sounds-just-like-its-failed-metaverse/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 17:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superhuman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superinteilligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zuckerberg]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/metas-ai-superintelligence-effort-sounds-just-like-its-failed-metaverse/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Zuckerberg and company talked up another supposed tech revolution four short years ago.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>In <a href="https://x.com/MikeIsaac/status/1939758599653532121">a memo to employees earlier this week</a>, Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg shared a vision for a near-future in which "personal [AI] superintelligence for everyone" forms "the beginning of a new era for humanity." The newly formed Meta Superintelligence Labs—freshly staffed with multiple high-level acquisitions from OpenAI and other AI companies—will spearhead the development of "our next generation of models to get to the frontier in the next year or so," Zuckerberg wrote.</p>
<p>Reading that memo, I couldn't help but think of another "vision for the future" Zuckerberg shared not that long ago. At his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0294iXEPO4Y">2021 Facebook Connect keynote</a>, Zuckerberg laid out <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/11/everyone-pitching-the-metaverse-has-a-different-idea-of-what-it-is/">his plan for the metaverse</a>, a virtual place where “you're gonna be able to do almost anything you can imagine" and which would form the basis of "the next version of the Internet."</p>
<img width="780" height="439" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/metabound1.png" class="fullwidth full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/metabound1.png 780w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/metabound1-300x169.png 300w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/metabound1-640x360.png 640w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/metabound1-768x432.png 768w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/metabound1-384x216.png 384w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px">
      "The future of the Internet" of the recent past.
        Credit:
          <a href="https://www.oculus.com/blog/introducing-a-personal-boundary-for-horizon-worlds-and-venues/?utm_source=rakuten&amp;utm_medium=affiliate&amp;utm_campaign=TnL5HPStwNw-3c42SNkFWH48Zyd_i35Tjg&amp;MID=43993&amp;LSNSUBSITE=Omitted_TnL5HPStwNw&amp;utm_term=exclusive&amp;utm_content=ad" target="_blank">Meta</a>
      
<p>Zuckerberg believed in that vision so much at the time that he abandoned the well-known Facebook corporate brand <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/10/facebooks-rebrands-as-meta-amid-a-new-metaverse-first-outlook/">in favor of the new name "Meta."</a> "I'm going to keep pushing and giving everything I've got to make this happen now," Zuckerberg said at the time. Less than four years later, Zuckerberg seems to now be “giving everything [he's] got" for a vision of AI “superintelligence," reportedly <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/mark-zuckerberg-meta-offer-top-ai-talent-300-million/">offering pay packages of up to $300 million over four years</a> to attract top talent from other AI companies (Meta has since <a href="https://nypost.com/2025/07/02/business/meta-denies-report-ceo-mark-zuckerberg-offered-ai-talent-up-to-300m/">denied those reports</a>, saying, “The size and structure of these compensation packages have been misrepresented all over the place").</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/metas-ai-superintelligence-effort-sounds-just-like-its-failed-metaverse/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/07/metas-ai-superintelligence-effort-sounds-just-like-its-failed-metaverse/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>241</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/zuckmetaverse.jpg">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/zuckmetaverse-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Facebook</media:credit><media:text>Artist's conception of Mark Zuckerberg looking into our glorious AI-powered future.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>The Last of Us co-creator Neil Druckmann exits HBO show</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/07/the-last-of-us-co-creator-neil-druckmann-exits-hbo-show/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/07/the-last-of-us-co-creator-neil-druckmann-exits-hbo-show/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 17:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halley gross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Naughty Dog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neil Druckmann]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the last of us]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/07/the-last-of-us-co-creator-neil-druckmann-exits-hbo-show/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Halley Gross, another prominent writer for the game and show, also departed.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Two key writers of HBO's series <em>The Last of Us</em> are moving on, according to announcements on Instagram yesterday. Neil Druckmann, co-creator of the franchise, and Halley Gross, co-writer of <em>The Last of Us Part 2</em> and frequent writer on the show, are both leaving before work begins on season 3.</p>
<p>Both were credited as executive producers on the show; Druckmann frequently contributed writing to episodes, as did Gross, and Druckmann also directed. Druckmann and Gross co-wrote the second game, <em>The Last of Us Part 2</em>.</p>
<p>Druckmann said in his announcement <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DLnTt7ZPVbJ/">post</a>:</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/07/the-last-of-us-co-creator-neil-druckmann-exits-hbo-show/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/07/the-last-of-us-co-creator-neil-druckmann-exits-hbo-show/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>96</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/pedro-pascal-kaitlyn-dever-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/pedro-pascal-kaitlyn-dever-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>HBO</media:credit><media:text>A still from the second season of HBO's &lt;em&gt;The Last of Us&lt;/em&gt;.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>2025 VW ID Buzz review: If you want an electric minivan, this is it</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/2025-vw-id-buzz-acres-of-space-but-being-electric-comes-at-a-premium/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/2025-vw-id-buzz-acres-of-space-but-being-electric-comes-at-a-premium/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 16:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VW ID. Buzz]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/2025-vw-id-buzz-acres-of-space-but-being-electric-comes-at-a-premium/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[The three-row Buzz is defined by its big battery, which has its plusses and minuses.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>If you had asked me a few years ago, I would have told you that the review you're about to read would be one of the most-read car reviews of the year. For a while—quite a long while, in fact—the Volkswagen ID Buzz was the hottest electric vehicle you couldn't buy. Starting in 2001, VW began teasing concept after concept that called back to its various Transporters and Kombis, classic microbuses reimagined as modern minivans. When the electric Buzz was greenlit for production after wowing crowds in 2017, it caught the attention of the kind of people who don't normally care about such things. Early coverage of the Buzz showed plenty of interest, and it looked like VW might have a real hit on its hands.</p>
<p>At least, that's how things looked for the first couple of years. It actually took seven years for a version of the ID Buzz to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/10/driving-the-2025-vw-id-buzz-was-worth-the-seven-year-wait/">go on sale in North America</a>, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2022/09/weve-driven-volkswagens-retro-cool-id-buzz-electric-minivan/">two years after Europe</a>. Much of the optimism about EV adoption has now gone. Rather than reaching price parity with regular cars as battery prices dropped, everything just got more expensive during the pandemic. Add in recent worries about import tariffs and clean vehicle tax credits (available if you lease), and you start to understand why they remain a rare sight on the roads. Expect stares, glances, and even people taking out their phones as you drive past.</p>
<p>Some of the wait was for VW's more powerful rear drive unit, which provides this 2025 ID Buzz Pro S Plus with 282 hp (210 kW) and 413 lb-ft (560 Nm), paired with a 91 kWh battery pack. The official EPA range is 234 miles, which sounds disappointingly low, but it's <a href="https://www.fueleconomy.gov/feg/PowerSearch.do?action=noform&amp;path=1&amp;year1=2025&amp;year2=2025&amp;make=Volkswagen&amp;baseModel=ID.%20Buzz&amp;srchtyp=ymm&amp;pageno=1&amp;rowLimit=50">correct</a>. It does seem like a very conservative estimate based on a week with the Buzz. 3.1 miles/kWh (20 kWh 100/km) was possible if I drove carefully, with high-twos possible when I didn't, and with 89 percent state of charge in the battery, the Buzz's onboard brain figured we had 255 miles (410 km) of range.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/2025-vw-id-buzz-acres-of-space-but-being-electric-comes-at-a-premium/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/2025-vw-id-buzz-acres-of-space-but-being-electric-comes-at-a-premium/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>184</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/2025-VW-ID.Buzz-01-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/2025-VW-ID.Buzz-01-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Jonathan Gitlin</media:credit><media:text>VW's ID. Buzz has been on sale for a while—have you seen one?</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>