<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
        <atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
        <description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:11:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <sy:updatePeriod>
            hourly        </sy:updatePeriod>
        <sy:updateFrequency>
            1        </sy:updateFrequency>
        
<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
            <item>
                <title>Rocket Report: China launches with no advance warning; Europe’s drone ship</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/rocket-report-a-nearly-perfect-flight-for-starship-chinas-surprise-launch/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/rocket-report-a-nearly-perfect-flight-for-starship-chinas-surprise-launch/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Stephen Clark]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket report]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/rocket-report-a-nearly-perfect-flight-for-starship-chinas-surprise-launch/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Starlink, Kuiper, and the US military all saw additions to their mega-constellations this week.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Edition 8.15 of the Rocket Report! This year has been, at best, one of mixed results for SpaceX’s Starship program. There have been important steps forward, including the successful reuse of the rocket’s massive Super Heavy booster. Clearly, SpaceX is getting really good at launching and recovering the 33-engine booster stage. But Starship itself, part spacecraft and part upper stage, hasn’t fared as well<span class="s1">—at </span>least it hadn’t until the last couple of months. After four Starships were destroyed in flight and on the ground in the first half of 2025, the last two missions ended with pinpoint splashdowns in the Indian Ocean. The most recent mission this week was arguably the most successful yet for Starship, which returned to Earth with little damage, suggesting SpaceX’s improvements to the heat shield are working.</p>
<p>As always, we <a href="https://arstechnica.wufoo.com/forms/launch-stories/">welcome reader submissions</a>. If you don’t want to miss an issue, please subscribe using the box below (the form will not appear on AMP-enabled versions of the site). Each report will include information on small-, medium-, and heavy-lift rockets, as well as a quick look ahead at the next three launches on the calendar.</p>
<figure class="ars-img-shortcode id-1314289 align-center">
    <div>
                        <img decoding="async" width="560" height="81" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png" class="center full" alt="" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png 560w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll-300x43.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
                  </div>
      </figure>

<p><b>SpaceX vet will fly with Blue Origin. </b>Hans Koenigsmann is one of SpaceX’s earliest, longest-tenured, and most-revered employees. He worked at Elon Musk’s space company for nearly two decades, rising to the role of vice president for mission assurance and safety before leaving SpaceX in 2021. He led the investigations into every Falcon rocket failure, mentored young engineers, and became a public face for SpaceX through numerous presentations and press conferences. And now he has announced he is going to space on a future suborbital flight on Blue Origin’s New Shepard vehicle, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/one-of-spacexs-earliest-employees-is-going-to-space-via-blue-origin/">Ars reports</a>.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/rocket-report-a-nearly-perfect-flight-for-starship-chinas-surprise-launch/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/rocket-report-a-nearly-perfect-flight-for-starship-chinas-surprise-launch/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/starshipflight11-presplash-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/starshipflight11-presplash-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>SpaceX</media:credit><media:text>SpaceX's Starship descends toward the Indian Ocean at the conclusion of Flight 11.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Yes, everything online sucks now—but it doesn’t have to</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/yes-everything-online-sucks-now-but-it-doesnt-have-to/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/yes-everything-online-sucks-now-but-it-doesnt-have-to/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cory Doctorow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enshittification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online culture]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/yes-everything-online-sucks-now-but-it-doesnt-have-to/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Ars chats with Cory Doctorow about his new book <em>Enshittification</em>.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>We all feel it: Our once-happy digital spaces have become increasingly less user-friendly and more toxic, cluttered with extras nobody asked for and hardly anybody wants. There’s even a word for it: “enshittification,” named 2023 Word of the Year by the American Dialect Society. The term was coined by tech journalist/science fiction author <a href="https://craphound.com">Cory Doctorow</a>, a longtime advocate of digital rights. Doctorow has spun his analysis of what’s been ailing the tech industry into an eminently readable new book, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/0374619328"><em>Enshittification: Why Everything Suddenly Got Worse and What To Do About It</em></a>.</p>
<p>As Doctorow tells it, he was on vacation in Puerto Rico, staying in a remote cabin nestled in a cloud forest with microwave Internet service—i.e., very bad Internet service, since microwave signals struggle to penetrate through clouds. It was a 90-minute drive to town, but when they tried to consult TripAdvisor for good local places to have dinner one night, they couldn’t get the site to load. “All you would get is the little TripAdvisor logo as an SVG filling your whole tab and nothing else,” Doctorow told Ars. “So I tweeted, ‘Has anyone at TripAdvisor ever been on a trip? This is the most enshittified website I’ve ever used.'”</p>
<p>Initially, he just got a few “haha, that’s a funny word” responses. “It was when I married that to this technical critique, at a moment when things were quite visibly bad to a much larger group of people, that made it take off,” Doctorow said. “I didn’t deliberately set out to do it. I bought a million lottery tickets and one of them won the lottery. It only took two decades.”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/yes-everything-online-sucks-now-but-it-doesnt-have-to/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/yes-everything-online-sucks-now-but-it-doesnt-have-to/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/cory1-1152x648-1759765718.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/cory1-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Julia Galdo and Cody Cloud (JUCO)/CC-BY 3.0</media:credit><media:text>Cory Doctorow.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>RFK Jr.’s MAHA wants to make chemtrail conspiracy theories great again</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/rfk-jr-s-maha-wants-to-make-chemtrail-conspiracy-theories-great-again/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/rfk-jr-s-maha-wants-to-make-chemtrail-conspiracy-theories-great-again/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 22:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/rfk-jr-s-maha-wants-to-make-chemtrail-conspiracy-theories-great-again/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[It's unclear if Kennedy will follow through, but he supports the conspiracy theory.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>A prominent voice in the Make America Healthy Again movement is pushing for health secretary and anti-vaccine activist Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to make the topic of chemtrail conspiracy theories a federal priority, according to a report by KFF News.</p>
<p><a href="https://kffhealthnews.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/10/MAHA-Memo-Armour-Delany-Means.pdf">KFF obtained a memo</a>, written by MAHA influencer Gray Delany in July, presenting the topic to Calley Means, a White House health advisor. The memo lays out a series of unsubstantiated and far-fetched claims that academic researchers and federal agencies are secretively spreading toxic substances from airplanes, poisoning Americans and spurring large-scale weather events, such as the devastating flooding in Texas last summer.</p>
<p>“It is unconscionable that anyone should be allowed to spray known neurotoxins and environmental toxins over our nation’s citizens, their land, food and water supplies,” Delany writes in the memo.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/rfk-jr-s-maha-wants-to-make-chemtrail-conspiracy-theories-great-again/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/rfk-jr-s-maha-wants-to-make-chemtrail-conspiracy-theories-great-again/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>212</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-1182820491-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-1182820491-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Malorny</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>AI-powered features begin creeping deeper into the bedrock of Windows 11</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/microsofts-vision-for-ai-pcs-looks-a-lot-like-another-crack-at-cortana/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/microsofts-vision-for-ai-pcs-looks-a-lot-like-another-crack-at-cortana/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11 24h2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11 25h2]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/microsofts-vision-for-ai-pcs-looks-a-lot-like-another-crack-at-cortana/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Copilot expands with an emphasis on creating and editing files, voice input.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Like virtually every major Windows announcement in the last three years, the spate of features that Microsoft <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windowsexperience/2025/10/16/making-every-windows-11-pc-an-ai-pc/">announced for the operating system today</a> all revolve around generative AI. In particular, they’re concerned with the company’s more recent preoccupation with “agentic” AI, an industry buzzword for “telling AI-powered software to perform a task, which it then does in the background while you move on to other things.”</p>
<p>But the overarching impression I got, both from reading the announcement and sitting through a press briefing earlier this month, is that Microsoft is using language models and other generative AI technologies to try again with Cortana, Microsoft’s failed and discontinued entry in the voice assistant wars of the 2010s.</p>
<p>According to Microsoft’s Consumer Chief Marketing Officer Yusuf Mehdi, “AI PCs” should be able to recognize input “naturally, in text or voice,” to be able to guide users based on what’s on their screens at any given moment, and that AI assistants “should be able to take action on your behalf.”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/microsofts-vision-for-ai-pcs-looks-a-lot-like-another-crack-at-cortana/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/microsofts-vision-for-ai-pcs-looks-a-lot-like-another-crack-at-cortana/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>126</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Windows-Blog-Hero-Image_High-Res-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Windows-Blog-Hero-Image_High-Res-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Microsoft</media:credit><media:text>Microsoft is hoping that Copilot will succeed as a voice-driven assistant where Cortana failed.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Nation-state hackers deliver malware from “bulletproof” blockchains</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/hackers-bullet-proof-hosts-deliver-malware-from-blockchains/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/hackers-bullet-proof-hosts-deliver-malware-from-blockchains/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[malware]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/hackers-bullet-proof-hosts-deliver-malware-from-blockchains/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Malicious payloads stored on Ethereum and BNB blockchains are immune to takedowns.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Hacking groups—at least one of which works on behalf of the North Korean government—have found a new and inexpensive way to distribute malware from “bulletproof” hosts: stashing them on public cryptocurrency blockchains.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/dprk-adopts-etherhiding/">Thursday post</a>, members of the Google Threat Intelligence Group said the technique provides the hackers with their own “bulletproof” host, a term that describes cloud platforms that are largely immune from takedowns by law enforcement and pressure from security researchers. More traditionally, these hosts are located in countries without treaties agreeing to enforce criminal laws from the US and other nations. These services often charge hefty sums and cater to criminals spreading malware or peddling child sexual abuse material and wares sold in crime-based flea markets.</p>
<h2>Next-gen, DIY hosting that can’t be tampered with</h2>
<p>Since February, Google researchers have observed two groups turning to a newer technique to infect targets with credential stealers and other forms of malware. The method, known as EtherHiding, embeds the malware in smart contracts, which are essentially apps that reside on blockchains for Ethereum and other cryptocurrencies. Two or more parties then enter into an agreement spelled out in the contract. When certain conditions are met, the apps enforce the contract terms in a way that, at least theoretically, is immutable and independent of any central authority.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/hackers-bullet-proof-hosts-deliver-malware-from-blockchains/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/hackers-bullet-proof-hosts-deliver-malware-from-blockchains/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/malware-threat-1000x648.jpg" width="1000">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/malware-threat-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Ars Live recap: Is the AI bubble about to pop? Ed Zitron weighs in.</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/ars-live-recap-is-the-ai-bubble-about-to-pop-ed-zitron-weighs-in/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/ars-live-recap-is-the-ai-bubble-about-to-pop-ed-zitron-weighs-in/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI agents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI chips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI criticism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bubble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cerebras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[datacenters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ed Zitron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial losses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generative ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GPU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large language models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Power consumption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam altman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stargate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/ars-live-recap-is-the-ai-bubble-about-to-pop-ed-zitron-weighs-in/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Despite connection hiccups, we covered OpenAI's finances, nuclear power, and Sam Altman.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>On Tuesday of last week, Ars Technica <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/ars-live-is-the-ai-bubble-about-to-pop-ed-zitron-is-on-with-ars-at-330pm-edt-today/">hosted</a> a live conversation with Ed Zitron, host of the <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/better-offline/id1730587238">Better Offline</a> podcast and one of tech’s most vocal AI critics, to discuss whether the generative AI industry is experiencing a bubble and when it might burst. My Internet connection had other plans, though, dropping out multiple times and forcing Ars Technica’s Lee Hutchinson to jump in as an excellent emergency backup host.</p>
<p>During the times my connection cooperated, Zitron and I covered OpenAI’s financial issues, lofty infrastructure promises, and why the AI hype machine keeps rolling despite some arguably shaky economics underneath. Lee’s probing questions about per-user costs revealed a potential flaw in AI subscription models: Companies can’t predict whether a user will cost them $2 or $10,000 per month.</p>
<p>You can <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1nEph7-Viyc">watch a recording</a> of the event on YouTube or in the window below.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/ars-live-recap-is-the-ai-bubble-about-to-pop-ed-zitron-weighs-in/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/ars-live-recap-is-the-ai-bubble-about-to-pop-ed-zitron-weighs-in/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>85</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/ai_bubble_hero2-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/ai_bubble_hero2-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Wong Yu Liang via Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>OnePlus unveils OxygenOS 16 update with deep Gemini integration</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/10/oneplus-unveils-oxygenos-16-update-with-deep-gemini-integration/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/10/oneplus-unveils-oxygenos-16-update-with-deep-gemini-integration/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/10/oneplus-unveils-oxygenos-16-update-with-deep-gemini-integration/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Does your phone even have a Mind Space?]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>OnePlus is expected to take the wraps off the OnePlus 15 in the next few weeks, but before that, it’s giving us a look at the software that will run on it. OxygenOS 16, which is based on Android 16, will also come to the company’s other supported phones, and it’s going to include a heaping helping of AI features. OnePlus was <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/oneplus-plans-huge-expansion-of-ai-features-on-its-phones-starting-with-13s/">slower than most</a> smartphone makers to embrace AI, but it’s full-steam ahead now with new Gemini integrations.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.oneplus.com/us/oxygenos16">OxygenOS 16</a> is described by OnePlus in grandiose terms as “a defiant rebellion for authenticity.” In the real world, this update is doing a lot of the same things as other AI-heavy smartphones. It’s not <em>all </em>AI—OnePlus notes that OxygenOS 16 will include revamped animations that have been carefully designed for smoothness, as well as the O+ remote app that gives you remote access to Windows and Mac PCs. The lock screen is also more customizable, borrowing a page from the likes of Apple and Samsung.</p>
<p>OnePlus began embracing AI in June, when it launched a feature called Mind Space on the OnePlus 13S. That phone was only for the Indian market, but the rest of the world will get this and more with OxygenOS 16. At launch, Mind Space would collect your screenshots and brief voice messages. Mind Space would analyze the screenshots to create calendar entries and not much else.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/10/oneplus-unveils-oxygenos-16-update-with-deep-gemini-integration/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/10/oneplus-unveils-oxygenos-16-update-with-deep-gemini-integration/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/OP-mind-space-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/OP-mind-space-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>OnePlus</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Sony tells SCOTUS that people accused of piracy aren’t “innocent grandmothers”</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/sony-tells-scotus-that-people-accused-of-piracy-arent-innocent-grandmothers/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/sony-tells-scotus-that-people-accused-of-piracy-arent-innocent-grandmothers/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[record labels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supreme Court]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/sony-tells-scotus-that-people-accused-of-piracy-arent-innocent-grandmothers/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Music companies want ISPs to terminate repeat infringers or pay big damages.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Record labels Sony, Warner, and Universal yesterday asked the Supreme Court to help it boot pirates off the Internet.</p>
<p>Sony and the other labels filed their <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24-171/379664/20251015121635831_24-171%20Sony%20Response%20Brief.pdf">brief</a> in <em>Cox Communications v. Sony Music Entertainment</em>, a case involving the cable Internet service provider that rebuffed labels’ demands for mass terminations of broadband subscribers accused of repeat copyright infringement. The Supreme Court’s <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/supreme-court-to-decide-whether-isps-must-disconnect-users-accused-of-piracy/">eventual decision in the case</a> may determine whether Internet service providers must terminate the accounts of alleged pirates in order to avoid massive financial liability.</p>
<p>Cox has <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24-171/373201/20250829115733612_250829a%20Brief%20for%20efiling.pdf">argued</a> that copyright-infringement notices—which are generated by bots and flag users based on their IP addresses—sent by record labels are unreliable. Cox said ISPs can’t verify whether the notices are accurate and that terminating an account would punish every user in a household where only one person may have illegally downloaded copyrighted files.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/sony-tells-scotus-that-people-accused-of-piracy-arent-innocent-grandmothers/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/sony-tells-scotus-that-people-accused-of-piracy-arent-innocent-grandmothers/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>83</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/music-pirate-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/music-pirate-500x500-1732568013.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | OcusFocus</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Apple TV and Peacock bundle starts at $15/month, available on Oct. 20</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/apple-tv-gets-rare-discount-in-peacock-streaming-bundle/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/apple-tv-gets-rare-discount-in-peacock-streaming-bundle/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nbcuniversal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peacock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/apple-tv-gets-rare-discount-in-peacock-streaming-bundle/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[The bundle starts at $15/month, compared to $21/month if purchased separately. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>In a rarity for Apple’s streaming service, users will be able to buy bundled subscriptions to Apple TV and Peacock for a discount, starting on October 20.</p>
<p>On its own, the Apple TV streaming service (which was <a href="https://arstechnica.com/apple/2025/10/apple-tv-streaming-service-is-renamed-to-just-apple-tv/">called Apple TV+ until Monday</a>) is $13 per month. NBCUniversal’s Peacock starts at $8/month with ads and $11/month without ads. With the upcoming bundle, people can subscribe to both for a total of $15/month or $20/month, depending on whether Peacock has ads or not (Apple TV never has ads).</p>
<p>People can buy the bundles through either Apple’s or Peacock’s websites and apps.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/apple-tv-gets-rare-discount-in-peacock-streaming-bundle/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/apple-tv-gets-rare-discount-in-peacock-streaming-bundle/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-2239767414-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-2239767414-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Nikolas Kokovlis/NurPhoto via Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Open source GZDoom community splinters after creator inserts AI-generated code</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/10/civil-war-gzdoom-fan-developers-split-off-over-use-of-chatgpt-generated-code/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/10/civil-war-gzdoom-fan-developers-split-off-over-use-of-chatgpt-generated-code/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 16:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disagreement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gzdoom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[id Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/10/civil-war-gzdoom-fan-developers-split-off-over-use-of-chatgpt-generated-code/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[<em>UZDoom</em> fork promises to fix other top-down leadership problems with the decades-old mod.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>If you’ve even idly checked in on the robust world of <em>Doom</em> fan development in recent years, you’ve probably encountered one of the hundreds of <a href="https://forum.zdoom.org/viewforum.php?f=43">gameplay mods</a>, <a href="https://doomwiki.org/wiki/Category:GZDoom_WADs">WAD files</a>, or <a href="https://www.doomworld.com/forum/topic/136771-every-gzdoom-game-on-steam/">entire commercial games</a> based on <em>GZDoom</em>. The <a href="https://github.com/ZDoom/gzdoom">open source <em>Doom</em> port</a>—which can trace its lineage back to the <a href="https://zdoom.org/wiki/ZDoom_version_history/1.x#1.11_(March_6_1998)">original launch of <em>ZDoom</em> back in 1998</a>—adds modern graphics rendering, quality-of-life additions, and incredibly deep modding features to <a href="https://github.com/id-Software/DOOM">the original <em>Doom</em> source code</a> that John Carmack released in 1997.</p>
<p>Now, though, the community behind <em>GZDoom</em> is publicly fracturing, with a large contingent of developers uniting behind a new fork <a href="https://github.com/UZDoom/UZDoom">called UZDoom</a>. The move is in apparent protest of the leadership of <em>GZDoom</em> creator and maintainer <a href="https://doomwiki.org/wiki/Christoph_Oelckers_(Graf_Zahl)">Cristoph Oelckers (aka Graf Zahl)</a>, who recently admitted to inserting untested AI-generated code into the <em>GZDoom</em> codebase.</p>
<p>“Due to some disagreements—some recent; some tolerated for close to 2 decades—with how collaboration should work, we’ve decided that the best course of action was to fork the project,” developer Nash Muhandes <a href="https://www.doomworld.com/forum/topic/155567-uzdoom/">wrote on the DoomWorld forums Wednesday</a>. “I don’t want to see the <em>GZDoom</em> legacy die, as do most all of us, hence why I think the best thing to do is to continue development through a fork, while introducing a different development model that highly favors transparent collaboration between multiple people.”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/10/civil-war-gzdoom-fan-developers-split-off-over-use-of-chatgpt-generated-code/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/10/civil-war-gzdoom-fan-developers-split-off-over-use-of-chatgpt-generated-code/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>96</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/gzdoom-1152x648.png" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/gzdoom-500x500.png" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Prodigal's GZDOoom WADs</media:credit><media:text>Artist's conception of &lt;em&gt;GZDoom&lt;/em&gt; developers going off to create their own fork of the game.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>OpenAI thinks Elon Musk funded its biggest critics—who also hate Musk</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/openai-thinks-elon-musk-funded-its-biggest-critics-who-also-hate-musk/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/openai-thinks-elon-musk-funded-its-biggest-critics-who-also-hate-musk/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 16:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xAI]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/openai-thinks-elon-musk-funded-its-biggest-critics-who-also-hate-musk/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[“Cutthroat” OpenAI accused of exploiting Musk fight to intimidate and silence critics.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Over the past week, OpenAI has faced backlash over subpoenas it sent to nonprofits accused of conspiring with Elon Musk to amplify public criticism of OpenAI as it <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/openai-scraps-controversial-plan-to-become-for-profit-after-mounting-pressure/">sought to shift from a nonprofit to for-profit structure.</a></p>
<p>The subpoenas are supposed to support OpenAI’s defense in a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/openai-wouldnt-exist-without-me-elon-musk-says-reviving-lawsuit/">lawsuit Musk’s X Corp filed</a> to block the for-profit transition. Seeking a “wide variety of documents”—including a sweeping request for all communications regarding Musk and all information on nonprofits’ funders and donations—OpenAI claimed that the subpoenas are intended to probe if Musk was involved in the actions or paid nonprofits to make critical comments, NBC News <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/openai-chatgpt-accused-using-subpoenas-silence-nonprofits-rcna237348">wrote</a> in a report exhaustively documenting the controversy.</p>
<p>But nonprofits have alleged it’s obvious that OpenAI is using the lawsuit to harass, silence, and intimidate its critics—most glaringly when it comes to targeting nonprofits that are even more publicly critical of Musk’s companies than they are of OpenAI.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/openai-thinks-elon-musk-funded-its-biggest-critics-who-also-hate-musk/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/10/openai-thinks-elon-musk-funded-its-biggest-critics-who-also-hate-musk/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>55</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-2198388525-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-2198388525-500x500-1760629376.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>NurPhoto / Contributor | NurPhoto</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>SpaceX has plans to launch Falcon Heavy from California—if anyone wants it to</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/spacex-has-plans-to-launch-falcon-heavy-from-california-if-anyone-wants-it-to/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/spacex-has-plans-to-launch-falcon-heavy-from-california-if-anyone-wants-it-to/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Stephen Clark]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 15:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Commercial space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falcon 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falcon heavy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slc-6]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space force]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vandenberg space force base]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/spacex-has-plans-to-launch-falcon-heavy-from-california-if-anyone-wants-it-to/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[There's no big rush to bring SpaceX's Falcon Heavy to Vandenberg Space Force Base.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The Department of the Air Force has approved SpaceX’s plans to launch up to 100 missions per year from Vandenberg Space Force Base in California.</p>
<p>This would continue the tectonic turnaround at the spaceport on California’s Central Coast. Five years ago, Vandenberg hosted just a single orbital launch. This year’s number stands at 51 orbital flights, or 53 launches if you count a pair of Minuteman missile tests, the most in a single calendar year at Vandenberg since the early 1970s.</p>
<p>Vandenberg is used for missions launching into polar orbits, paths oriented north-south that, over time, cover most of the Earth’s surface area. These orbits are popular for Earth observation satellites.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/spacex-has-plans-to-launch-falcon-heavy-from-california-if-anyone-wants-it-to/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/spacex-has-plans-to-launch-falcon-heavy-from-california-if-anyone-wants-it-to/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>67</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-2211835625-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-2211835625-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>George Rose/Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket soars into orbit from Vandenberg Space Force Base, California, with multiple satellites for the National Reconnaissance Office on April 20, 2025. The rocket lifted off just before sunrise, and its exhaust plume was illuminated by the Sun as it climbed to higher altitudes.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Antarctica is starting to look a lot like Greenland—and that isn’t good</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/antarctica-is-starting-to-look-a-lot-like-greenland-and-that-isnt-good/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/antarctica-is-starting-to-look-a-lot-like-greenland-and-that-isnt-good/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Bob Berwyn, Inside Climate News]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Antarctica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glaciers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/antarctica-is-starting-to-look-a-lot-like-greenland-and-that-isnt-good/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Global warming is awakening sleeping giants of ice at the South Pole.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>As recently as the 1990s, when the Greenland Ice Sheet and the rest of the Arctic region were measurably thawing under the climatic blowtorch of human-caused global warming, most of Antarctica’s vast ice cap still seemed securely frozen.</p>
<p>But not anymore. Physics is physics. As the planet heats up, more ice will melt at both poles, and recent research shows that Antarctica’s ice caps, glaciers, and floating ice shelves, as well as its sea ice, are just as vulnerable to warming as the Arctic.</p>
<p>Both satellite data and field observations in Antarctica reveal alarming signs of a Greenland-like meltdown, with increased surface melting of the ice fields, faster-moving glaciers, and dwindling sea ice. Some scientists are sounding the alarm, warning that the rapid “Greenlandification” of Antarctica will have serious consequences, including an accelerated rise in sea levels and significant shifts in rainfall and drought patterns.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/antarctica-is-starting-to-look-a-lot-like-greenland-and-that-isnt-good/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/antarctica-is-starting-to-look-a-lot-like-greenland-and-that-isnt-good/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>120</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shoesmith-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shoesmith-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Sebnem Coskun/Anadolu via Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>A view of the Shoesmith Glacier on Horseshoe Island on Feb. 21. 
</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Inside the web infrastructure revolt over Google’s AI Overviews</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/inside-the-web-infrastructure-revolt-over-googles-ai-overviews/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/inside-the-web-infrastructure-revolt-over-googles-ai-overviews/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloudflare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matthew Prince]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RAG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retrieval augmented generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robots.txt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search engines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web crawlers]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/inside-the-web-infrastructure-revolt-over-googles-ai-overviews/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Cloudflare CEO Matthew Prince is making sweeping changes to force Google's hand.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>It could be a consequential act of quiet regulation. Cloudflare, a web infrastructure company, has updated millions of websites’ robots.txt files in an effort to force Google to change how it crawls them to fuel its AI products and initiatives.</p>
<p>We spoke with Cloudflare CEO Matthew Prince about what exactly is going on here, why it matters, and what the web might soon look like. But to get into that, we need to cover a little background first.</p>
<p>The new change, which Cloudflare calls its <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/content-signals-policy/">Content Signals Policy</a>, happened after publishers and other companies that depend on web traffic have cried foul over Google’s AI Overviews and similar AI answer engines, saying they are sharply cutting those companies’ path to revenue because they don’t send traffic back to the source of the information.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/inside-the-web-infrastructure-revolt-over-googles-ai-overviews/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/inside-the-web-infrastructure-revolt-over-googles-ai-overviews/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>117</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Co-founder_and_CEO_of_Cloudflare_Matthew_Prince-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Co-founder_and_CEO_of_Cloudflare_Matthew_Prince-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Noam Galai for TechCrunch (CC BY 2.0)</media:credit><media:text>Cloudflare CEO Matthew Prince.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Army general says he’s using AI to improve “decision-making”</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/army-general-says-hes-using-ai-to-improve-decision-making/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/army-general-says-hes-using-ai-to-improve-decision-making/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 21:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[army]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decision making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weapons]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/army-general-says-hes-using-ai-to-improve-decision-making/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA["AI is one thing that, as a commander, it’s been very, very interesting for me."]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Last month, OpenAI <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/09/seven-things-we-learned-from-openais-first-study-on-chatgpt-usage/">published a usage study</a> showing that nearly 15 percent of work-related conversations on ChatGPT had to deal with “making decisions and solving problems.” Now comes word that at least one high-level member of the US military is using LLMs for the same purpose.</p>
<p>At the Association of the US Army Conference in Washington, DC, this week, Maj. Gen. William “Hank” Taylor reportedly said that “Chat and I are really close lately,” using a distressingly familiar diminutive nickname to refer to an unspecified AI chatbot. “AI is one thing that, as a commander, it’s been very, very interesting for me.”</p>
<p>Military-focused news site DefenseScoop <a href="https://defensescoop.com/2025/10/13/eighth-army-commander-eyes-generative-ai-to-inform-how-he-leads/">reports</a> that Taylor told a roundtable group of reporters that he and <a href="https://8tharmy.korea.army.mil/site/index.asp">the Eighth Army</a> he commands out of South Korea are “regularly using” AI to modernize their <a href="https://www.amu.apus.edu/area-of-study/intelligence/resources/forecasting-threats/">predictive analysis</a> for logistical planning and operational purposes. That is helpful for paperwork tasks like “just being able to write our weekly reports and things,” Taylor said, but it also aids in informing their overall direction.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/army-general-says-hes-using-ai-to-improve-decision-making/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/army-general-says-hes-using-ai-to-improve-decision-making/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>146</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-2219849110-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-2219849110-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Team of army experts in data center analyzing missiles flight paths with deep learning tools.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Rice weevil on a grain of rice wins 2025 Nikon Small World contest</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/meet-the-2025-nikon-photomicrography-winners/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/meet-the-2025-nikon-photomicrography-winners/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nikon Small World Photo Microscopy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photomicrography]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/meet-the-2025-nikon-photomicrography-winners/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Nikon Small World photomicrography contest is an annual reminder that science can be beautiful as well as informative.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>A stunning image of a rice weevil on a single grain of rice has won the 2025 Nikon Small World photomicrography contest, yielding valuable insight into the structure and behavior of—and providing a fresh perspective on—this well-known agricultural pest. The image was taken by Zhang You of Yunnan, China. Another of You’s photographs placed 15th in this year’s contest.</p>
<p>“It pays to dive deep into entomology: understanding insects’ behaviors and mastering lighting,” You said in a statement. “A standout work blends artistry with scientific rigor, capturing the very essence, energy, and spirit of these creatures.”</p>
<p>There was an element of luck in creating his winning image, too. “I had observed rice weevils in grains before, but never one with its wings spread,” You said. “This one was naturally preserved on a windowsill, perhaps in a final attempt to escape. Its tiny size makes manually preparing spread-wing specimens extremely difficult, so encountering it was both serendipitous and inspiring.”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/meet-the-2025-nikon-photomicrography-winners/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/10/meet-the-2025-nikon-photomicrography-winners/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/nikon1-1152x648-1760544093.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/nikon1-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Zhang You/Nikon Small World</media:credit><media:text>Winning image: Rice weevil (&lt;em&gt;Sitophilus oryzae&lt;/em&gt;) on a grain of rice</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Once unthinkable, NASA and Lockheed now consider launching Orion on other rockets</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/once-unthinkable-nasa-and-lockheed-now-consider-launching-orion-on-other-rockets/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/once-unthinkable-nasa-and-lockheed-now-consider-launching-orion-on-other-rockets/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Eric Berger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sls rocket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/once-unthinkable-nasa-and-lockheed-now-consider-launching-orion-on-other-rockets/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA["We're trying to crawl, then walk, then run into our reuse strategy."]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The Orion spacecraft and Space Launch System rocket have been attached at the hip for the better part of two decades. The big rocket lifts, the smaller spacecraft flies, and Congress keeps the money rolling in.</p>
<p>But now there are signs that the twain may, in the not too distant future, split.</p>
<p>This is because Lockheed Martin has begun to pivot toward a future in which the Orion spacecraft—thanks to increasing reusability, a focus on cost, and openness to flying on different rockets—fits into commercial space applications. In interviews, company officials said that if NASA wanted to buy Orion missions as a “service,” rather than owning and operating the spacecraft, they were ready to work with the space agency.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/once-unthinkable-nasa-and-lockheed-now-consider-launching-orion-on-other-rockets/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/10/once-unthinkable-nasa-and-lockheed-now-consider-launching-orion-on-other-rockets/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>125</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/jsc2025e016293large-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/jsc2025e016293large-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>NASA/Rad Sinyak</media:credit><media:text>The Orion spacecraft for the Artemis II mission, seen here with its solar arrays installed for flight, just prior to their enclosure inside aerodynamic fairings to protect them during launch.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Thousands of customers imperiled after nation-state ransacks F5’s network</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/breach-of-f5-requires-emergency-action-from-big-ip-users-feds-warn/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/breach-of-f5-requires-emergency-action-from-big-ip-users-feds-warn/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big-ip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[f5]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/breach-of-f5-requires-emergency-action-from-big-ip-users-feds-warn/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Risks to BIG-IP users include supply-chain attacks, credential loss, and vulnerability exploits.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Thousands of networks—many of them operated by the US government and Fortune 500 companies—face an “imminent threat” of being breached by a nation-state hacking group following the breach of a major maker of software, the federal government warned Wednesday.</p>
<p>F5, a Seattle-based maker of networking software, <a href="https://my.f5.com/manage/s/article/K000154696">disclosed the breach</a> on Wednesday. F5 said a “sophisticated” threat group working for an undisclosed nation-state government had surreptitiously and persistently dwelled in its network over a “long-term.” Security researchers who have responded to similar intrusions in the past took the language to mean the hackers were inside the F5 network <a href="https://cyberplace.social/@GossiTheDog/115378445416288653">for years</a>.</p>
<h2>Unprecedented</h2>
<p>During that time, F5 said, the hackers took control of the network segment the company uses to create and distribute updates for BIG IP, a line of server appliances that F5 <a href="https://www.f5.com/c/emea-2020/event/f5-myforum">says</a> is used by 48 of the world’s top 50 corporations. Wednesday’s disclosure went on to say the threat group downloaded proprietary BIG-IP source code information about vulnerabilities that had been privately discovered but not yet patched. The hackers also obtained configuration settings that some customers used inside their networks.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/breach-of-f5-requires-emergency-action-from-big-ip-users-feds-warn/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/10/breach-of-f5-requires-emergency-action-from-big-ip-users-feds-warn/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>97</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-1202018501-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/GettyImages-1202018501-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Sundry Photography</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>CDC tormented: HR workers summoned from furlough to lay off themselves, others</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/cdc-tormented-hr-workers-summoned-from-furlough-to-lay-off-themselves-others/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/cdc-tormented-hr-workers-summoned-from-furlough-to-lay-off-themselves-others/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/cdc-tormented-hr-workers-summoned-from-furlough-to-lay-off-themselves-others/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Traumatized CDC has lost 33% of its workforce this year, union says.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The dust is still settling at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention after a mass layoff on Friday, which former employees at the beleaguered agency are describing as a massacre.</p>
<p>In separate press briefings on Tuesday, a network of terminated CDC staff that goes by the name the National Public Health Coalition, and the union representing employees at the agency discussed what the wide-scale cuts mean for the American people, as well as the trauma, despair, and damage they have wreaked on the workers of the once-premier public health agency.</p>
<p>In a normal federal layoff—called a reduction in force, or RIF—the agency would be given a full outline of the roles and branches or divisions affected, as well as some explanation for the cuts, such as alleged fraud, abuse, or redundancy. However, the Trump administration has provided no such information or explanation, leaving current and former employees to essentially crowdsource what has been lost and only guess at the possible reasons.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/cdc-tormented-hr-workers-summoned-from-furlough-to-lay-off-themselves-others/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/10/cdc-tormented-hr-workers-summoned-from-furlough-to-lay-off-themselves-others/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>168</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GettyImages-2228551722-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GettyImages-2228551722-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Elijah Nouvelage</media:credit><media:text>ATLANTA, GEORGIA - AUGUST 9: Bullet holes are seen in windows at the Centers For Disease Control (CDC) Global Headquarters following a shooting that left two dead, on August 9, 2025 in Atlanta, Georgia. On August 8, a gunman opened fire near the headquarters of the Centers for Disease Control, killing a DeKalb County Police Department officer before being found dead by gunfire. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Anthropic’s Claude Haiku 4.5 matches May’s frontier model at fraction of cost</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/anthropics-claude-haiku-4-5-matches-mays-frontier-model-at-fraction-of-cost/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/anthropics-claude-haiku-4-5-matches-mays-frontier-model-at-fraction-of-cost/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI alignment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI benchmarks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI development tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Bedrock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anthropic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[API]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Claude Haiku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Claude Sonnet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code agents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GitHub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large language models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertex AI]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/anthropics-claude-haiku-4-5-matches-mays-frontier-model-at-fraction-of-cost/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Tiny, fast model hits coding scores similar to GPT-5 and Sonnet 4.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>On Wednesday, Anthropic <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/claude-haiku-4-5">released</a> Claude Haiku 4.5, a small AI language model that reportedly delivers performance similar to what its frontier model <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/anthropic-calls-new-claude-4-worlds-best-ai-coding-model/">Claude Sonnet 4</a> achieved five months ago but at one-third the cost and more than twice the speed. The new model is available now to all Claude app, web, and API users.</p>
<p>If the benchmarks for Haiku 4.5 reported by Anthropic hold up to independent testing, the fact that the company can match some capabilities of its cutting-edge coding model from only five months ago (and GPT-5 in coding) while providing a dramatic speed increase and cost cut is notable.</p>
<p>As a recap, Anthropic ships the Claude family in three model sizes: Haiku (small), Sonnet (medium), and Opus (large). The larger models are based on larger neural networks and typically include deeper contextual knowledge but are slower and more expensive to run. Due to a technique called <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/03/ai-firms-follow-deepseeks-lead-create-cheaper-models-with-distillation/">distillation</a>, companies like Anthropic have been able to craft smaller AI models that match the capability of larger, older models at functional tasks like coding, although it typically comes at the cost of omitting stored knowledge.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/anthropics-claude-haiku-4-5-matches-mays-frontier-model-at-fraction-of-cost/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/10/anthropics-claude-haiku-4-5-matches-mays-frontier-model-at-fraction-of-cost/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/haiku45_hero.jpg">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/haiku45_hero-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
</media:content>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>