<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
        <atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
        <description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 01:20:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <sy:updatePeriod>
            hourly        </sy:updatePeriod>
        <sy:updateFrequency>
            1        </sy:updateFrequency>
        
<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
            <item>
                <title>Colon cancer recurrence and deaths cut 28% by simple exercise, trial finds</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/06/exercise-improves-colon-cancer-survival-high-quality-trial-finds/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/06/exercise-improves-colon-cancer-survival-high-quality-trial-finds/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 22:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerobic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clinical trial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colon cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEJM]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/06/exercise-improves-colon-cancer-survival-high-quality-trial-finds/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Any type of aerobic exercise works for the improvements, study finds.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Exercise is generally good for you, but a new high-quality clinical trial finds that it's so good, it can even knock back colon cancer—and, in fact, rival some chemotherapy treatments.</p>
<p>The finding comes from a phase 3, randomized clinical trial led by researchers in Canada, who studied nearly 900 people who had undergone surgery and chemotherapy for colon cancer. After those treatments, patients were evenly split into groups that either bulked up their regular exercise routines in a three-year program that included coaching and supervision or were simply given health education. The researchers found that the exercise group had a 28 percent lower risk of their colon cancer recurring, new cancers developing, or dying over eight years compared with the health education group.</p>
<p>The benefits of exercise, <a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa2502760">published in the New England Journal of Medicine</a>, became visible after just one year and increased over time, the researchers found. The rate of people who survived for five years and remained cancer-free was 80.3 percent among the exercise group. That's a 6.4 percentage-point survival boost over the education group, which had a 73.9 percent cancer-free survival rate. The overall survival rate (with or without cancer) during the study's eight-year follow-up was 90.3 percent in the exercise group compared with 83.2 percent in the education group—a 7.1 percentage point difference. Exercise reduced the relative risk of death by 37 percent (41 people died in the exercise group compared with 66 in the education group).</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/06/exercise-improves-colon-cancer-survival-high-quality-trial-finds/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/06/exercise-improves-colon-cancer-survival-high-quality-trial-finds/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-588283543-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-588283543-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Oli Kellett</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Broadcom ends business with VMware’s lowest-tier channel partners</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/06/broadcom-ends-business-with-vmwares-lowest-tier-channel-partners/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/06/broadcom-ends-business-with-vmwares-lowest-tier-channel-partners/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 21:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Broadcom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vmware]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/06/broadcom-ends-business-with-vmwares-lowest-tier-channel-partners/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Broadcom claims many eliminated partners weren't doing any VMware business. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Broadcom has cut the lowest tier in its VMware partner program. The move allows the enterprise technology firm to continue its focus on customers with larger VMware deployments, but it also risks more migrations from VMware users and partners.</p>
<h2>Broadcom ousts low-tier VMware partners</h2>
<p>In a <a href="https://news.broadcom.com/partners/fueling-customer-success-through-deep-partner-collaboration">blog post</a> on Sunday, Broadcom executive Brian Moats announced that the Broadcom Advantage Partner Program for VMware Resellers, which became the VMware partner program after <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/01/broadcom-killing-vmware-partner-program-could-disrupt-thousands-of-businesses/">Broadcom eliminated the original one</a> in January 2024, would now offer three tiers instead of four. Broadcom is killing the Registered tier, leaving the Pinnacle, Premier, and Select tiers.</p>
<p>The reduction is a result of Broadcom's "strategic direction" and a "comprehensive partner review" and affects VMware's Americas, Asia-Pacific, and Japan geographies, Moats wrote. Affected partners are receiving 60 days' notice, Laura Falko, Broadcom’s head of global partner programs, marketing, and experience, told <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/06/01/vmware_channel_changes/">The Register</a>.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/06/broadcom-ends-business-with-vmwares-lowest-tier-channel-partners/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/06/broadcom-ends-business-with-vmwares-lowest-tier-channel-partners/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-114396654-1152x648-1748890824.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-114396654-500x500-1748890809.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Microsoft wants a version of USB-C that “just works” consistently across all PCs</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/microsoft-belatedly-attempts-to-tame-usb-c-confusion-with-its-rules-for-pc-oems/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/microsoft-belatedly-attempts-to-tame-usb-c-confusion-with-its-rules-for-pc-oems/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 21:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USB-C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11 24h2]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/microsoft-belatedly-attempts-to-tame-usb-c-confusion-with-its-rules-for-pc-oems/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[USB-C ports have always supported different capabilities on different systems.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>We've been covering the small, reversible USB Type-C connector since the days when it was just <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2014/09/reversible-tiny-faster-hands-on-with-the-usb-type-c-plug/">a USB Implementers Forum tech demo</a>, and in the decade-plus since then, the port has gradually taken over the world. It gradually migrated from laptops to game consoles, to PC accessories, to Android phones, to e-readers, and to iPhones. Despite some hiccups and shortcomings, we're considerably closer to a single connector that does <em>everything</em> than we were a decade ago.</p>
<p>But some of that confusion persists. A weakness built into the USB-C from the very beginning was that the specification for the physical connector was always separate from the specifications for the USB protocol itself (that is, the data transfer speed a given port is capable of), the USB Power Delivery specification for charging, and the USB-C Alt Mode specification for carrying non-USB signals like DisplayPort or HDMI.</p>
<p>All of these specifications were frequently grouped together so that individual USB-C ports could handle charging, display output, and data transfers (or some combination of all three at once), but they weren't <em>required</em> to go together, so occasionally users will still run into physical USB-C ports that fall short of the port's do-everything promise.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/microsoft-belatedly-attempts-to-tame-usb-c-confusion-with-its-rules-for-pc-oems/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/microsoft-belatedly-attempts-to-tame-usb-c-confusion-with-its-rules-for-pc-oems/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>66</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1367572559-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1367572559-500x500-1748897767.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>kate_sept2004 via Getty</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Google settles shareholder lawsuit, will spend $500M on being less evil</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/google-settles-shareholder-lawsuit-will-spend-500m-on-being-less-evil/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/google-settles-shareholder-lawsuit-will-spend-500m-on-being-less-evil/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shareholders]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/google-settles-shareholder-lawsuit-will-spend-500m-on-being-less-evil/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Google could also be liable for legal fees in the case. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>It has become a common refrain during Google's antitrust saga: What happened to "don't be evil?" Google's unofficial motto has haunted it as it has grown ever larger, but a shareholder lawsuit sought to rein in some of the company's excesses. And it might be working. The plaintiffs in the case have reached a settlement with Google parent company Alphabet, which will spend a boatload of cash on "comprehensive" reforms. The goal is to steer Google away from the kind of anticompetitive practices that got it in hot water.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the settlement, obtained by <a href="https://www.bloomberglaw.com/public/desktop/document/InreAlphabetIncShareholderDerivativeLitigationDocketNo321cv09388N/1?doc_id=X6L5I3F7H479DQB4STTU3JAG8JV">Bloomberg Law</a>, Alphabet will spend $500 million over the next 10 years on systematic reforms. The company will have to form a board-level committee devoted to overseeing the company's regulatory compliance and antitrust risk, a rarity for US firms. This group will report directly to CEO Sundar Pichai. There will also be reforms at other levels of the company that allow employees to identify potential legal pitfalls before they affect the company. Google has also agreed to preserve communications. Google's propensity to use auto-deleting chats drew condemnation from several judges overseeing its antitrust cases.</p>
<p>The agreement still needs approval from US District Judge Rita Lin in San Francisco, but that's mainly a formality at this point. Naturally, Alphabet does not admit to any wrongdoing under the terms of the settlement, but it may have to pay tens of millions in legal fees on top of the promised $500 million investment.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/google-settles-shareholder-lawsuit-will-spend-500m-on-being-less-evil/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/google-settles-shareholder-lawsuit-will-spend-500m-on-being-less-evil/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/google-logo-big-g-grooves-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/google-logo-big-g-grooves-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Aurich Lawson</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Analysis: Trump’s “Gold Standard Science” is already wearing thin</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/analysis-trumps-gold-standard-science-is-already-wearing-thin/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/analysis-trumps-gold-standard-science-is-already-wearing-thin/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[John Timmer]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[covid vaccines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scientific practice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trump administration]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/analysis-trumps-gold-standard-science-is-already-wearing-thin/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[FDA head uses great-sounding science standards to dismiss COVID vaccine benefits.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>On May 23, President Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/05/restoring-gold-standard-science/">issued an executive order</a> entitled "Restoring Gold Standard Science." And, in news that may surprise our readers, it sounds remarkably good, focusing on issues like reproducibility and conflicts of interest. While there were a few things that could be phrased better, when it comes to basic scientific practices, the language was remarkably reasonable.</p>
<p>So, why didn't we report on what appeared to be a rare bit of good news? I'd considered doing so, but the situation is complicated by the fact that the order is structured in a way that makes it very sensitive to who's responsible for implementing it, a situation that's subtle enough that I couldn't figure out how to handle it well. Fortunately, I only had to wait a week for a member of the Trump administration to show just how dangerous it could be and highlight its biggest problem.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Food and Drug Administration Commissioner Marty Makary appeared on one of the weekend news programs, where he was asked about the decision to limit <a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/anti-vaccine-advocate-rfk-jr-axes-covid-shot-guidance-for-pregnant-people-kids/">pregnant people's access to the COVID-19 vaccines</a>. The host mentioned that aggregation of studies involving a total of over 1.8 million women had shown the vaccine was safe and effective.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/analysis-trumps-gold-standard-science-is-already-wearing-thin/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/analysis-trumps-gold-standard-science-is-already-wearing-thin/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>50</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-177137103-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-177137103-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>manfredxy</media:credit><media:text>Iron pyrite, often called fool's gold.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Samsung could drop Google Gemini in favor of Perplexity for Galaxy S26</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/samsung-could-drop-google-gemini-in-favor-of-perplexity-for-galaxy-s26/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/samsung-could-drop-google-gemini-in-favor-of-perplexity-for-galaxy-s26/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 18:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perplexity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/samsung-could-drop-google-gemini-in-favor-of-perplexity-for-galaxy-s26/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[This move would reduce Samsung's reliance on Google.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Every smartphone maker is racing to find a way to put AI in your pocket, but no one has cracked the code yet. Samsung was an early supporter of Google's Gemini AI, which has largely supplanted its little-used Bixby assistant. However, a new report claims Samsung is planning a big AI shakeup by partnering with Perplexity on the Galaxy S26.</p>
<p>Perplexity pitches itself as an AI-powered search service, running on the same generative AI technology behind ChatGPT, Gemini, and all the others. However, it cites its sources around the web more prominently than a pure chatbot. Perplexity made waves during the Google <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/google-and-doj-tussle-over-how-ai-will-remake-the-web-in-antitrust-closing-arguments/">search antitrust trial</a> when executive Dmitry Shevelenko testified that Google <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/04/perplexity-will-come-to-moto-phones-after-exec-testified-google-blocked-access/">blocked Motorola from using Perplexity</a> on its 2024 phones. The company got its wish this year, though, with Perplexity finding a place on 2025 Razr phones.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-06-01/samsung-nears-wide-ranging-deal-with-perplexity-for-ai-features">report from Bloomberg</a> says Samsung will be the next to leverage Perplexity's AI. The companies are apparently close to signing a deal that will make this AI model a core part of the Galaxy S26 lineup. Motorola uses Perplexity for search functionality inside its Moto AI system, but the Samsung deal would be more comprehensive.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/samsung-could-drop-google-gemini-in-favor-of-perplexity-for-galaxy-s26/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/samsung-could-drop-google-gemini-in-favor-of-perplexity-for-galaxy-s26/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/galaxy_ai-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/galaxy_ai-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Samsung</media:credit><media:text>Samsung already includes a plethora of AI features on Galaxy phones. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Unlicensed law clerk fired after ChatGPT hallucinations found in filing</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/law-clerk-fired-over-chatgpt-use-after-firms-filing-used-ai-hallucinations/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/law-clerk-fired-over-chatgpt-use-after-firms-filing-used-ai-hallucinations/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 18:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChatGPT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctions]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/law-clerk-fired-over-chatgpt-use-after-firms-filing-used-ai-hallucinations/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Law school grad’s firing is a bad omen for college kids overly reliant on ChatGPT.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>College students who have <a href="https://www.404media.co/teachers-are-not-ok-ai-chatgpt/">reportedly</a> grown too dependent on ChatGPT are starting to face consequences after graduating and joining the workforce for placing too much trust in chatbots.</p>
<p>Last month, a recent law school graduate lost his job after using ChatGPT to help draft a court filing that ended up being riddled with errors.</p>
<p>The consequences arrived after a court in Utah <a href="https://legacy.utcourts.gov/opinions/appopin/Garner%20v.%20Kadince20250522_20250188_80.pdf">ordered</a> sanctions after the filing included the first fake citation ever discovered in the state hallucinated by artificial intelligence.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/law-clerk-fired-over-chatgpt-use-after-firms-filing-used-ai-hallucinations/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/law-clerk-fired-over-chatgpt-use-after-firms-filing-used-ai-hallucinations/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>112</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-520166596-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-520166596-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>the-lightwriter | iStock / Getty Images Plus</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>ISP settles with record labels that demanded mass termination of Internet users</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/isp-settles-with-record-labels-that-demanded-mass-termination-of-internet-users/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/isp-settles-with-record-labels-that-demanded-mass-termination-of-internet-users/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frontier Communications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piracy]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/isp-settles-with-record-labels-that-demanded-mass-termination-of-internet-users/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[One piracy case is over, but the biggest one could be decided by Supreme Court.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Internet service provider Frontier Communications agreed to settle a lawsuit filed by major record labels that demanded mass disconnections of broadband users accused of piracy.</p>
<p>Universal, Sony, and Warner <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2021/06/record-labels-sue-another-isp-demanding-mass-disconnections-of-internet-users/">sued Frontier in 2021</a>. In a <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nysd.561609/gov.uscourts.nysd.561609.59.0.pdf">notice of settlement</a> filed last week in US District Court for the Southern District of New York, the parties agreed to dismiss the case with prejudice, with each side to pay its own fees and costs.</p>
<p>The record labels and Frontier simultaneously <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nysb.301895/gov.uscourts.nysb.301895.2556.0.pdf">announced a settlement</a> of similar claims in a Bankruptcy Court case in the same district. Frontier also <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nysb.301895/gov.uscourts.nysb.301895.2538.1.pdf">settled with movie companies</a> in April of this year, just before a trial was scheduled to begin. (Frontier exited bankruptcy in 2021.)</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/isp-settles-with-record-labels-that-demanded-mass-termination-of-internet-users/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/isp-settles-with-record-labels-that-demanded-mass-termination-of-internet-users/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/getty-pirate-flag-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/getty-pirate-flag-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | Priscila Zambotto</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>New federal employees must praise Trump EOs, submit to continuous vetting</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/new-federal-employees-must-praise-trump-eos-submit-to-continuous-vetting/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/new-federal-employees-must-praise-trump-eos-submit-to-continuous-vetting/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 16:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of government efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[executive order]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/new-federal-employees-must-praise-trump-eos-submit-to-continuous-vetting/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Trump will continuously monitor all federal workers for "trustworthiness."]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>With the federal hiring freeze lifting in mid-July, the Trump administration has rolled out a controversial <a href="https://chcoc.gov/sites/default/files/Merit%20Hiring%20Plan%205-29-2025%27.pdf">federal hiring plan</a> that critics warn will politicize and likely slow down the process rather than increase government efficiency.</p>
<p>De-emphasizing degree requirements and banning DEI initiatives—as well as any census tracking of gender, race, ethnicity, or religion to assess the composition of government—the plan requires every new hire to submit essays explaining which executive orders or policy initiatives they will help advance.</p>
<p>These essays must be limited to 200 words and cannot be generated by a chatbot, the guidance noted. While some applicants may point to policies enacted by prior presidents under their guidance, the president appears to be seeking to ensure that only Trump supporters are hired and that anyone who becomes disillusioned with Trump is weeded out over time. In addition to asking for a show of loyalty during the interview process, all federal workers will also be continuously vetted and must agree to submit to "checks for post-appointment conduct that may impact their continued trustworthiness," the guidance noted, referencing required patriotism repeatedly.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/new-federal-employees-must-praise-trump-eos-submit-to-continuous-vetting/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/06/new-federal-employees-must-praise-trump-eos-submit-to-continuous-vetting/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>298</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2217159011-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2217159011-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Jeff Swensen / Stringer | Getty Images News</media:credit><media:text>US President Donald Trump speaks during a rally at the US Steel-Irvin Works on May 30, 2025 in West Mifflin, Pennsylvania. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Could floating solar panels on a reservoir help the Colorado River?</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/can-floating-solar-panels-on-a-reservoir-help-the-colorado-river/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/can-floating-solar-panels-on-a-reservoir-help-the-colorado-river/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jake Bolster, Inside Climate News]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 15:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water conservation]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/can-floating-solar-panels-on-a-reservoir-help-the-colorado-river/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Floating solar panels appear to conserve water while generating green electricity.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>GILA RIVER INDIAN RESERVATION, Ariz.—About 33 miles south of Phoenix, Interstate 10 bisects a line of solar panels traversing the desert like an iridescent snake. The solar farm’s shape follows the path of a canal, with panels serving as awnings to shade the gently flowing water from the unforgiving heat and wind of the Sonoran Desert.</p>
<p>The panels began generating power last November for the Akimel O’otham and Pee Posh tribes—known together as the Gila River Indian Community, or GRIC—on their reservation in south-central Arizona, and they are the first of their kind in the US. The community is studying the effects of these panels on the water in the canal, hopeful that they will protect a precious resource from the desert’s unflinching sun and wind.</p>
<p>In September, GRIC is planning to break ground on another experimental effort to conserve water while generating electricity: floating solar. Between its canal canopies and the new project that would float photovoltaic panels on a reservoir it is building, GRIC hopes to one day power all of its canal and irrigation operations with solar electricity, transforming itself into one of the most innovative and closely watched water users in the West in the process.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/can-floating-solar-panels-on-a-reservoir-help-the-colorado-river/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/06/can-floating-solar-panels-on-a-reservoir-help-the-colorado-river/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>61</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/gila-1-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/gila-1-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Jake Bolster/Inside Climate News</media:credit><media:text>The Gila River Indian Community in Arizona has lined 3,000 feet of their canals with solar panels. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>F1 in Spain: Now that was a lapse in judgment</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/06/f1-in-spain-now-that-was-a-lapse-in-judgement/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/06/f1-in-spain-now-that-was-a-lapse-in-judgement/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 14:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[F1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Formula 1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spanish Grand Prix]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/06/f1-in-spain-now-that-was-a-lapse-in-judgement/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[The cars got new front wings, but there's only one story that matters.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Formula 1 held its annual Spanish Grand Prix this past weekend at the Catalunya circuit near Barcelona. It's a good place to test a modern F1 car, as you need <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/09/how-a-day-driving-high-downforce-cars-at-vir-taught-me-im-ok-being-slow/">great aerodynamics</a> to be fast around here, especially now that the awkward chicanes are gone. You also need good mechanical grip. Races used to be processional here, but the re-profiled turn 10 and the flat-out nature of the last turn have changed all that.</p>
<p>This was to be the weekend of new front wings, the result of a "technical directive" meant to stop excessive flexing as part of the sport's ongoing antipathy toward creatively movable aerodynamics <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/06/lighter-nimbler-more-hybrid-power-he-f1-car-of-2026/">outside a tightly described domain</a>. The competitive order would be reset, some hoped, as their rivals would be forced to give up unfair advantages. In fact, the new wings turned out to be a nothingburger. McLaren's advantage remains, and that was clear on a circuit that tests every aspect of a racing car.</p>
<p>But there's only one story that anyone really cares about after Spain, and it's the one about Red Bull's Max Verstappen. For much of the race, Verstappen held onto third place, behind the too-fast McLarens. This required using one more set of tires than they did, and for his last stint, all that was left for the Red Bull driver was a set of the too-hard compound, giving him little in the way of grip.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/06/f1-in-spain-now-that-was-a-lapse-in-judgement/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/06/f1-in-spain-now-that-was-a-lapse-in-judgement/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>111</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2217540100-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2217540100-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Joan Valls/Urbanandsport/NurPhoto via Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Max Verstappen's Red Bull in Spain.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Squid Game trailer anchors Netflix Tudum event</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/06/netflix-drops-squid-game-s3-trailer/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/06/netflix-drops-squid-game-s3-trailer/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 19:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frankenstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knives Out series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix Tudum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Squid Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stranger Things S5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trailers]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/06/netflix-drops-squid-game-s3-trailer/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Also: <em>Wednesday</em> S2 sneak peek, <em>Stranger Things</em> S5 premiere date, <em>Frankenstein</em> teaser, more Benoit Blanc.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Netflix held its Tudum Global Fan Event in Los Angeles this weekend to showcase its upcoming slate of programming. Among the highlights: the official trailer for the third and final season of <em>Squid Game</em>, the first six minutes of <em>Wednesday</em> S2, a teaser for Guillermo del Toro's <em>Frankenstein</em>, and date announcements for the fifth and final season of <em>Stranger Things,</em> as well as <em>Wake Up Dead Man: A Knives Out Mystery</em>.</p>
<p><strong>(Some spoilers below.)</strong></p>
<h2><em>Squid Game</em> S3</h2>
<div class="ars-video"><div class="relative" allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zgGTVaG2UiQ?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent"></div></div>
<p>As <a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/11/player-456-is-back-for-revenge-in-squid-game-s2-trailer/">previously reported</a>, S<em>quid Game</em>'s first season followed Seong Gi-hun (Lee Jung-Jae), a down-on-his-luck gambler who has little left to lose when he agrees to play children's playground games against 455 other players for money. The twist? If you lose a game, you die. If you cheat, you die. And if you win, you might also die. In the S1 finale, Gi-hun faced off against fellow finalist and childhood friend Cho Sang-woo (Park Hae-soo) in the titular "squid game." He won their fight but refused to kill his friend. Sang-woo instead stabbed himself in the neck, leaving Gi-hun the guilt-ridden winner.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/06/netflix-drops-squid-game-s3-trailer/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/06/netflix-drops-squid-game-s3-trailer/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/squid1-1152x648-1748798290.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/squid1-500x500-1748798299.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Netflix</media:credit><media:text>&lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt; returns this month for its third and final season.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Breaking down why Apple TVs are privacy advocates’ go-to streaming device</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/all-the-ways-apple-tv-boxes-do-and-mostly-dont-track-you/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/all-the-ways-apple-tv-boxes-do-and-mostly-dont-track-you/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 11:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TVs]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/all-the-ways-apple-tv-boxes-do-and-mostly-dont-track-you/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Using the Apple TV app or an Apple account means giving Apple more data, though.
]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Every time I write an article about the escalating <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/tv-industrys-ads-tracking-obsession-is-turning-your-living-room-into-a-store/">advertising and tracking</a> on <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/12/buying-a-tv-in-2025-expect-lower-prices-more-ads-and-an-os-war/">today's TVs</a>, someone brings up Apple TV boxes. Among smart TVs, streaming sticks, and other streaming devices, Apple TVs are largely viewed as a safe haven.</p>
<p>"Just disconnect your TV from the Internet and use an Apple TV box."</p>
<p>That's the common guidance you'll hear from Ars readers for those seeking the joys of streaming without giving up too much privacy. Based on our research and the experts we've consulted, that advice is pretty solid, as Apple TVs offer significantly more privacy than other streaming hardware providers.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/all-the-ways-apple-tv-boxes-do-and-mostly-dont-track-you/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/06/all-the-ways-apple-tv-boxes-do-and-mostly-dont-track-you/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>221</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/examining-the-apple-tv-1152x648-1747771489.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/examining-the-apple-tv-500x500-1747771483.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Aurich Lawson | Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Research roundup: 7 stories we almost missed</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/research-roundup-ping-pong-bots-the-genetic-key-for-ginger-cats-and-more/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/research-roundup-ping-pong-bots-the-genetic-key-for-ginger-cats-and-more/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 21:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acoustics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[primates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/research-roundup-ping-pong-bots-the-genetic-key-for-ginger-cats-and-more/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Ping-pong bots, drumming chimps, picking styles of two jazz greats, and an ancient underground city's soundscape. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>It's a regrettable reality that there is never time to cover all the interesting scientific stories we come across each month. In the past, we've featured year-end roundups of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/12/ten-cool-science-stories-we-almost-missed/">cool science stories</a> we (almost) missed. This year, we're experimenting with a monthly collection. May's list includes a nifty experiment to make a predicted effect of special relativity visible; a ping-pong playing robot that can return hits with 88 percent accuracy; and the discovery of the rare genetic mutation that makes orange cats orange, among other highlights.</p>
<h2>Special relativity made visible</h2>
<p><img width="640" height="427" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Low-Res_TerrellPenrose-640x427.jpg" class="none medium" alt="The Terrell-Penrose-Effect: Fast objects appear rotated" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Low-Res_TerrellPenrose-640x427.jpg 640w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Low-Res_TerrellPenrose.jpg 700w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px">
        Credit:
          TU Wien
      </p>
<p>Perhaps the most well-known feature of Albert Einstein's special theory of relativity is time dilation and length contraction. In 1959, two physicists predicted another feature of relativistic motion: An object moving near the speed of light should also appear to be rotated. It has not been possible to demonstrate this experimentally, however—until now. Physicists at the Vienna University of Technology figured out how to reproduce this rotational effect in the lab using laser pulses and precision cameras, according to <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42005-025-02003-6">a paper</a> published in the journal Communications Physics.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/research-roundup-ping-pong-bots-the-genetic-key-for-ginger-cats-and-more/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/research-roundup-ping-pong-bots-the-genetic-key-for-ginger-cats-and-more/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/pingpong1-1152x648-1748366739.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/pingpong1-500x500-1748366724.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit> David Nguyen, Kendrick Cancio and Sangbae Kim</media:credit><media:text>Time lapse photos show a new ping-pong-playing robot performing a top spin.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Trump pulls Isaacman nomination for space. Source: “NASA is f***ed.”</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/trump-pulls-isaacman-nomination-for-space-source-nasa-is-fed/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/trump-pulls-isaacman-nomination-for-space-source-nasa-is-fed/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Eric Berger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 21:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isaacman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/trump-pulls-isaacman-nomination-for-space-source-nasa-is-fed/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA["NASA's budget request is just a going-out-of-business mode" without Isaacman.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The Trump administration has confirmed that it is pulling the nomination of private astronaut Jared Isaacman to lead NASA.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/05/31/2025/white-house-expected-to-pull-nasa-nominee-isaacman">First reported</a> by Semafor, the decision appears to have been made because Isaacman was not politically loyal enough to the Trump administration.</p>
<p>"The Administrator of NASA will help lead humanity into space and execute President Trump’s bold mission of planting the American flag on the planet Mars," Liz Huston, a White House Spokesperson, said in a statement released Saturday. "It's essential that the next leader of NASA is in complete alignment with President Trump’s America First agenda and a replacement will be announced directly by President Trump soon."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/trump-pulls-isaacman-nomination-for-space-source-nasa-is-fed/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/trump-pulls-isaacman-nomination-for-space-source-nasa-is-fed/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>621</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/52225129791_a35f106c0a_k-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/52225129791_a35f106c0a_k-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>SpaceX</media:credit><media:text>Jared Isaacman during training at SpaceX before the Polaris Dawn mission.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Ransomware kingpin “Stern” apparently IDed by German law enforcement</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/german-police-say-theyve-identified-trickbot-ransomware-kingpin/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/german-police-say-theyve-identified-trickbot-ransomware-kingpin/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Lily Hay Newman, wired.com]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 13:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ransomware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndicated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TrickBot]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/german-police-say-theyve-identified-trickbot-ransomware-kingpin/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[BSA names Vi­ta­ly Ni­ko­lae­vich Kovalev is "Stern," the leader of Trickbot.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>For years, members of the Russian cybercrime cartel <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/trickbot-malware-group-internal-messages/">Trickbot</a> unleashed a relentless hacking spree on the world. The group attacked thousands of victims, including businesses, schools, and hospitals. “Fuck clinics in the usa this week,” one member wrote in <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/trickbot-malware-group-internal-messages/">internal Trickbot messages</a> in 2020 about a list of 428 hospitals to target. Orchestrated by an enigmatic leader using the online moniker “Stern,” the group of around 100 cybercriminals stole hundreds of millions of dollars over the course of roughly six years.</p>
<p>Despite a wave of <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/cyber-command-hackers-trickbot-botnet-precedent/">law enforcement</a> <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/conti-trickbot-ransomware-sanctions-uk-us/">disruptions</a> and a <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/costa-rica-ransomware-conti/">damaging</a> <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/conti-leaks-ransomware-work-life/">leak of more than 60,000 internal chat messages</a> from Trickbot and the closely associated counterpart group Conti, the identity of Stern has remained a mystery. Last week, though, Germany’s federal police agency, the Bundeskriminalamt or BKA, and local prosecutors <a href="https://www.bka.de/DE/IhreSicherheit/Fahndungen/Personen/BekanntePersonen/Endgame_2/KVN/Sachverhalt.html">alleged that Stern’s real-world name is Vi­ta­ly Ni­ko­lae­vich Kovalev</a>, a 36-year-old, 5-foot-11-inch Russian man who cops believe is in his home country and thus shielded from potential extradition.</p>
<p>A recently issued Interpol <a href="https://www.interpol.int/en/How-we-work/Notices/Red-Notices/View-Red-Notices#2025-39252">red notice</a> says that Kovalev is wanted by Germany for allegedly being the “ringleader” of a “criminal organisation.”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/german-police-say-theyve-identified-trickbot-ransomware-kingpin/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/german-police-say-theyve-identified-trickbot-ransomware-kingpin/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/stern-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/stern-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Tim Robberts/Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Real TikTokers are pretending to be Veo 3 AI creations for fun, attention</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/real-tiktokers-are-pretending-to-be-veo-3-ai-creations-for-fun-attention/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/real-tiktokers-are-pretending-to-be-veo-3-ai-creations-for-fun-attention/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veo 3]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/real-tiktokers-are-pretending-to-be-veo-3-ai-creations-for-fun-attention/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[From music videos to "Are you a prompt?" stunts, "real" videos are presenting as AI.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Since Google released its Veo 3 AI model last week, social media users have been having fun with its ability to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/ai-video-just-took-a-startling-leap-in-realism-are-we-doomed/">quickly generate highly realistic eight-second clips complete with sound and lip-synced dialogue</a>. TikTok's algorithm has been serving me plenty of Veo-generated videos featuring <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZP8MrUDpt/">impossible challenges</a>, <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@echofueltv/video/7510331996917304622?">fake news reports</a>, and even <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZP8MrCJNm/">surreal short narrative films</a>, to name just a few popular archetypes.</p>
<p>However, among all the AI-generated video experiments spreading around, I've also noticed a surprising counter-trend on my TikTok feed. Amid all the videos of Veo-generated avatars pretending to be real people, there are now also a bunch of videos of real people pretending to be Veo-generated avatars.</p>
<h2>“This has to be real. There’s no way it’s AI.”</h2>
<p>I stumbled across this trend when the TikTok algorithm fed me <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@kongosmusic/video/7509895663065500974">this video</a> topped with the extra-large caption "Google VEO 3 THIS IS 100% AI." As I watched and listened to the purported AI-generated band that appeared to be playing in the crowded corner of someone's living room, I read the caption containing the supposed prompt that had generated the clip: "a band of brothers with beards playing rock music in 6/8 with an accordion."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/real-tiktokers-are-pretending-to-be-veo-3-ai-creations-for-fun-attention/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/real-tiktokers-are-pretending-to-be-veo-3-ai-creations-for-fun-attention/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-667311229-1152x648-1748642421.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-667311229-500x500-1748642414.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Of course I'm an AI creation! Why would you even doubt it?</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Google and DOJ tussle over how AI will remake the web in antitrust closing arguments</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/google-and-doj-tussle-over-how-ai-will-remake-the-web-in-antitrust-closing-arguments/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/google-and-doj-tussle-over-how-ai-will-remake-the-web-in-antitrust-closing-arguments/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 21:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antitrust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/google-and-doj-tussle-over-how-ai-will-remake-the-web-in-antitrust-closing-arguments/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Google and the DOJ get one last chance to make their cases. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>From its humble beginnings in the late 20th century, Google has come to dominate online searches, putting it squarely in the US government's antitrust crosshairs. The ongoing search antitrust case threatens to upend Google's dominance, giving smaller players a chance to thrive and possibly wiping others out. After <a href="https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/05/googles-search-antitrust-trial-is-wrapping-up-heres-what-we-learned/">wrapping up testimony</a> in the case earlier this month, lawyers for Google and the Department of Justice have now made their closing arguments.</p>
<p>The DOJ won the initial trial, securing a ruling that Google used anticompetitive practices to maintain its monopoly in general search. During the time this case has taken to meander its way through the legal system, the online landscape has been radically altered, making it harder than ever to envision a post-Google Internet.</p>
<p>To address Google's monopoly, the DOJ is asking United States District Judge Amit Mehta to impose limits on Google's business dealings and order a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/04/chrome-on-the-chopping-block-as-googles-search-antitrust-trial-moves-forward/">divestment of the Chrome browser</a>. Forcing the sale of Chrome would be a major penalty and a coup for the DOJ lawyers, but this issue has been overshadowed somewhat as the case drags on. During closing arguments, the two sides dueled over how Google's search deals and the rise of AI could change the Internet as we know it.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/google-and-doj-tussle-over-how-ai-will-remake-the-web-in-antitrust-closing-arguments/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/google-and-doj-tussle-over-how-ai-will-remake-the-web-in-antitrust-closing-arguments/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Google-sign-IO-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Google-sign-IO-500x500-1748638352.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Ryan Whitwam</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Amazon Fire Sticks enable “billions of dollars’” worth of streaming piracy</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/amazon-fire-sticks-enable-billions-of-dollars-worth-of-streaming-piracy/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/amazon-fire-sticks-enable-billions-of-dollars-worth-of-streaming-piracy/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 21:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/amazon-fire-sticks-enable-billions-of-dollars-worth-of-streaming-piracy/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Research firm blames outdated DRM tech, Facebook ads, Amazon hardware, and more.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Amazon Fire Sticks are enabling “billions of dollars'” worth of streaming piracy, according to a report today from Enders Analysis, a media, entertainment, and telecommunications research firm. Technologies from other media conglomerates, Microsoft, Google, and Facebook, are also enabling what the report’s authors deem an “industrial scale of theft."</p>
<p><a href="https://www.endersanalysis.com/reports/video-piracy-big-tech-clearly-unwilling-address-problem">The report</a>, "Video piracy: Big tech is clearly unwilling to address the problem," focuses on the European market but highlights the global growth of piracy of streaming services as they increasingly acquire rights to live programs, like sporting events.</p>
<p>Per the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp3n7dx2174o">BBC</a>, the report points to the availability of multiple, simultaneous illegal streams for big events that draw tens of thousands of pirate viewers.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/amazon-fire-sticks-enable-billions-of-dollars-worth-of-streaming-piracy/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/amazon-fire-sticks-enable-billions-of-dollars-worth-of-streaming-piracy/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>237</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Amazon-Fire-Stick-1152x648-1748636679.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Amazon-Fire-Stick-500x500-1748636655.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Amazon</media:credit><media:text>An Amazon Fire Stick and remote. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>CDC updates COVID vaccine recommendations, but not how RFK Jr. wanted</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-contradicts-rfk-jr-by-still-recommending-covid-vaccine-for-kids/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-contradicts-rfk-jr-by-still-recommending-covid-vaccine-for-kids/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 20:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[centers for disease control and prevention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rfk jr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccines]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-contradicts-rfk-jr-by-still-recommending-covid-vaccine-for-kids/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Mixed messages only add to uncertainty about vaccine access for kids, pregnant individuals. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention on Thursday updated its immunization schedules for children and adults to <em>partially</em> reflect the abrupt changes announced by health secretary and anti-vaccine advocate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. earlier this week.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/SecKennedy/status/1927368440811008138">a 58-second video</a> posted on social media on Tuesday, May 27, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/anti-vaccine-advocate-rfk-jr-axes-covid-shot-guidance-for-pregnant-people-kids/">Kennedy said he was unilaterally revoking the CDC's recommendations</a> that healthy children and pregnant people get COVID-19 vaccines.</p>
<p>"I couldn’t be more pleased to announce that, as of today, the COVID vaccine for healthy children and healthy pregnant women has been removed from the CDC recommended immunization schedule," Kennedy said in the video.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-contradicts-rfk-jr-by-still-recommending-covid-vaccine-for-kids/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-contradicts-rfk-jr-by-still-recommending-covid-vaccine-for-kids/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>127</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/GettyImages-1232965275-1152x648.jpeg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/GettyImages-1232965275-500x500.jpeg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Sopa images</media:credit><media:text>A nurse gives a 16-year-old a COVID-19 vaccine. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>