<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
        <atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
        <description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 15:40:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <sy:updatePeriod>
            hourly        </sy:updatePeriod>
        <sy:updateFrequency>
            1        </sy:updateFrequency>
        
<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
            <item>
                <title>200 mph for 500 miles: How IndyCar drivers prepare for the big race</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/features/2025/05/how-to-try-to-win-the-indianapolis-500/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/features/2025/05/how-to-try-to-win-the-indianapolis-500/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 15:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indianapolis 500]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indy 500]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IndyCar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Racing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simulation]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/features/2025/05/how-to-try-to-win-the-indianapolis-500/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Andretti Global's Kyle Kirkwood and Marcus Ericsson talk to us about the Indy 500.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>This coming weekend is a special one for most motorsport fans. There are Formula 1 races in Monaco and NASCAR races in Charlotte. And arguably towering over them both is the Indianapolis 500, being held this year for the 109th time. America's oldest race is also one of its toughest: The track may have just four turns, but the cars negotiate them going three times faster than you drive on the highway, inches from the wall. For hours. At least at Le Mans, you have more than one driver per car.</p>
<p>This year's race promises to be an exciting one. The track is sold out for the first time <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2016/05/the-greatest-spectacle-in-racing-turns-100-the-2016-indy-500/">since the centenary race in 2016</a>. A rookie driver and a team new to the series took pole position. Two very fast cars are <a href="https://racer.com/2025/05/19/newgarden-power-sent-to-the-back-of-indy-500-grid-after-component-violations">starting at the back</a> thanks to <a href="https://racer.com/2025/05/18/indycar-president-boles-explains-penske-qualifying-illegalities">another conflict-of-interest</a> scandal involving Team Penske, the second in two years for a team whose owner also owns the track and the series. And the cars are trickier to drive than they have been for many years, thanks to a new supercapacitor-based hybrid system that has added more than 100 lbs to the rear of the car, shifting the weight distribution further back.</p>
<p>Ahead of Sunday's race, I spoke with a couple of IndyCar drivers and some engineers to get a better sense of how they prepare and what to expect.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/features/2025/05/how-to-try-to-win-the-indianapolis-500/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/features/2025/05/how-to-try-to-win-the-indianapolis-500/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2214687733-1152x648-1748012210.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2214687733-500x500-1748012200.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Brandon Badraoui/Lumen via Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>#28, Marcus Ericsson, Andretti Global Honda prior to the NTT IndyCar Series 109th Running of the Indianapolis 500 at Indianapolis Motor Speedway on May 15, 2025 in Indianapolis, Indiana.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Penguin poop may help preserve Antarctic climate</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/penguin-poop-may-help-preserve-antarctic-climate/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/penguin-poop-may-help-preserve-antarctic-climate/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Bob Berwyn, Inside Climate News]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 11:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Antarctica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arctic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Penguins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poop talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/penguin-poop-may-help-preserve-antarctic-climate/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Ammonia aerosols from penguin guano likely play a part in the formation of heat-shielding clouds.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p><i>This article originally appeared on <a href="https://insideclimatenews.org/news/22052025/penguin-poop-could-preserve-antarctic-climate/">Inside Climate News</a>, a nonprofit, non-partisan news organization that covers climate, energy, and the environment. Sign up for their newsletter <a href="https://insideclimatenews.org/newsletter/">here</a>.</i></p>
<p>New research shows that penguin guano in Antarctica is an important source of ammonia aerosol particles that help drive the formation and persistence of low clouds, which cool the climate by reflecting some incoming sunlight back to space.</p>
<p>The findings reinforce the growing awareness that Earth’s intricate web of life plays a significant role in shaping the planetary climate. Even at the small levels measured, the ammonia particles from the guano interact with sulfur-based aerosols from ocean algae to start a chemical chain reaction that forms billions of tiny particles that serve as nuclei for water vapor droplets.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/penguin-poop-may-help-preserve-antarctic-climate/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/penguin-poop-may-help-preserve-antarctic-climate/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GettyImages-169475683-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GettyImages-169475683-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Feds charge 16 Russians allegedly tied to botnets used in cyberattacks and spying</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/feds-charge-16-russians-allegedly-tied-to-botnets-used-in-cyberattacks-and-spying/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/feds-charge-16-russians-allegedly-tied-to-botnets-used-in-cyberattacks-and-spying/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Andy Greenberg, WIRED.com]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 19:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[botnet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russian hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/feds-charge-16-russians-allegedly-tied-to-botnets-used-in-cyberattacks-and-spying/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[An example of how a single malware operation can enable both criminal and state-sponsored hacking.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The hacker ecosystem in Russia, more than perhaps anywhere else in the world, has <a href="https://www.wired.com/2017/03/russian-hacker-spy-botnet/">long blurred the lines</a> between cybercrime, state-sponsored cyberwarfare, and espionage. Now an <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/media/1401356/dl?inline">indictment</a> of a group of Russian nationals and the takedown of their sprawling botnet offers the clearest example in years of how a single malware operation allegedly enabled hacking operations as varied as ransomware, wartime cyberattacks in Ukraine, and spying against foreign governments.</p>
<p>The US Department of Justice today announced criminal charges today against 16 individuals law enforcement authorities have linked to a malware operation known as DanaBot, which according to a <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-cdca/media/1401356/dl?inline">complaint</a> infected at least 300,000 machines around the world. The DOJ’s announcement of the charges describes the group as “Russia-based,” and names two of the suspects, Aleksandr Stepanov and Artem Aleksandrovich Kalinkin, as living in Novosibirsk, Russia. Five other suspects are named in the indictment, while another nine are identified only by their pseudonyms. In addition to those charges, the Justice Department says the Defense Criminal Investigative Service (DCIS)—a criminal investigation arm of the Department of Defense—carried out seizures of DanaBot infrastructure around the world, including in the US.</p>
<p>Aside from alleging how DanaBot was used in for-profit criminal hacking, the indictment also makes a rarer claim—it describes how a second variant of the malware it says was used in espionage against military, government, and NGO targets. “Pervasive malware like DanaBot harms hundreds of thousands of victims around the world, including sensitive military, diplomatic, and government entities, and causes many millions of dollars in losses,” US attorney Bill Essayli wrote in a statement.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/feds-charge-16-russians-allegedly-tied-to-botnets-used-in-cyberattacks-and-spying/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/feds-charge-16-russians-allegedly-tied-to-botnets-used-in-cyberattacks-and-spying/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/russia-state-hacking.jpg">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/russia-state-hacking-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>College Board keeps apologizing for screwing up digital SAT and AP tests</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/05/college-board-keeps-apologizing-for-screwing-up-digital-sat-and-ap-tests/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/05/college-board-keeps-apologizing-for-screwing-up-digital-sat-and-ap-tests/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Nate Anderson]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 19:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ap exams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SAT]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/05/college-board-keeps-apologizing-for-screwing-up-digital-sat-and-ap-tests/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[AP Psych is the latest casualty of digital snafus.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Don't worry about the "mission-driven not-for-profit" College Board—it's drowning in cash. The US group, which administers the SAT and AP tests to college-bound students, <a href="https://projects.propublica.org/nonprofits/organizations/131623965/202433139349302223/full">paid its CEO $2.38 million</a> in total compensation in 2023 (the most recent year data is available). The senior VP in charge of AP programs made $694,662 in total compensation, while the senior VP for Technology Strategy made $765,267 in total compensation.</p>
<p>Given such eye-popping numbers, one would have expected the College Board's transition to digital exams to go smoothly, but it continues to have issues.</p>
<p>Just last week, the group's AP Psychology exam was disrupted nationally when the required "Bluebook" testing app couldn't be accessed by many students. Because the College Board shifted to digital-only exams for 28 of its 36 AP courses beginning this year, no paper-based backup options were available. The only "solution" was to wait quietly in a freezing gymnasium, surrounded by a hundred other stressed-out students, to see if College Board could get its digital act together.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/05/college-board-keeps-apologizing-for-screwing-up-digital-sat-and-ap-tests/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/05/college-board-keeps-apologizing-for-screwing-up-digital-sat-and-ap-tests/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>81</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-183958940-1152x648-1748029018.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-183958940-500x500-1748029039.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Researchers cause GitLab AI developer assistant to turn safe code malicious</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/researchers-cause-gitlab-ai-developer-assistant-to-turn-safe-code-malicious/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/researchers-cause-gitlab-ai-developer-assistant-to-turn-safe-code-malicious/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 19:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chatbots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large language models]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/researchers-cause-gitlab-ai-developer-assistant-to-turn-safe-code-malicious/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[AI assistants can't be trusted to produce safe code.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Marketers promote AI-assisted developer tools as workhorses that are essential for today’s software engineer. Developer platform GitLab, for instance, claims its Duo chatbot can “instantly generate a to-do list” that eliminates the burden of “wading through weeks of commits.” What these companies don’t say is that these tools are, by temperament if not default, easily tricked by malicious actors into performing hostile actions against their users.</p>
<p>Researchers from security firm Legit on Thursday <a href="https://www.legitsecurity.com/blog/remote-prompt-injection-in-gitlab-duo">demonstrated</a> an attack that induced Duo into inserting malicious code into a script it had been instructed to write. The attack could also leak private code and confidential issue data, such as zero-day vulnerability details. All that’s required is for the user to instruct the chatbot to interact with a merge request or similar content from an outside source.</p>
<h2>AI assistants’ double-edged blade</h2>
<p>The mechanism for triggering the attacks is, of course, prompt injections. Among the most common forms of chatbot exploits, prompt injections are embedded into content a chatbot is asked to work with, such as an email to be answered, a calendar to consult, or a webpage to summarize. Large language model-based assistants are so eager to follow instructions that they’ll take orders from just about anywhere, including sources that can be controlled by malicious actors.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/researchers-cause-gitlab-ai-developer-assistant-to-turn-safe-code-malicious/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/researchers-cause-gitlab-ai-developer-assistant-to-turn-safe-code-malicious/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/chatbot-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/chatbot-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Illustration</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Google Home is getting deeper Gemini integration and a new widget</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/05/google-home-is-getting-deeper-gemini-integration-and-a-new-widget/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/05/google-home-is-getting-deeper-gemini-integration-and-a-new-widget/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 18:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart home]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/05/google-home-is-getting-deeper-gemini-integration-and-a-new-widget/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Smart homes can be dumb, but maybe Gemini can help. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>As Google moves the last remaining Nest devices into the Home app, it's also looking at ways to make this smart home hub easier to use. Naturally, Google is doing that by ramping up Gemini integration. The company has announced new automation capabilities with generative AI, as well as better support for third-party devices via the Home API. Google AI will also plug into a new Android widget that can keep you updated on what the smart parts of your home are up to.</p>
<p>The Google Home app is where you interact with all of Google's smart home gadgets, like cameras, thermostats, and smoke detectors—some of which have been discontinued, but <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-discontinues-nest-protect-smoke-alarm-and-nest-x-yale-lock/">that's another story</a>. It also accommodates smart home devices from other companies, which can make managing a mixed setup feasible if not exactly intuitive. A dash of AI might actually help here.</p>
<p>Google began testing Gemini integrations in Home last year, and now it's opening that up to third-party devices via the Home API. Google has worked with a few partners on API integrations before general availability. The previously announced First Alert smoke/carbon monoxide detector and Yale smart lock that are replacing Google's Nest devices are among the first, along with Cync lighting, Motorola Tags, and iRobot vacuums.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/05/google-home-is-getting-deeper-gemini-integration-and-a-new-widget/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/05/google-home-is-getting-deeper-gemini-integration-and-a-new-widget/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/montage_large_v3.original-1152x648.png" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/montage_large_v3.original-500x500.png" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Google</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Have we finally solved mystery of magnetic moon rocks?</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/have-we-finally-solved-mystery-of-magnetic-moon-rocks/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/have-we-finally-solved-mystery-of-magnetic-moon-rocks/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 18:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asteroids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astrophysics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[core dynamo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magnetism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moon rocks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleomagnetism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Moon]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/have-we-finally-solved-mystery-of-magnetic-moon-rocks/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Simulations show how effects of asteroid impact could amplify the early Moon's weak magnetic field.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>NASA's Apollo missions brought back moon rock samples for scientists to study. We've learned a great deal over the ensuing decades, but one enduring mystery remains. Many of those lunar samples show signs of exposure to strong magnetic fields comparable to Earth's, yet the Moon doesn't have such a field today. So, how did the moon rocks get their magnetism?</p>
<p>There have been many attempts to explain this anomaly. The latest comes from MIT scientists, who argue in <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adr7401">a new paper</a> published in the journal Science Advances that a large asteroid impact briefly boosted the Moon's early weak magnetic field—and that this spike is what is recorded in some lunar samples.</p>
<p>Evidence gleaned from orbiting spacecraft observations, as well as <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adp3333">results announced</a> earlier this year from China's Chang'e 5 and <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-08870-x">Chang'e 6</a> missions, is largely consistent with the existence of at least a weak magnetic field on the early Moon. But where did this field come from? These usually form in planetary bodies as a result of a dynamo, in which molten metals in the core start to convect thanks to slowly dissipating heat. The problem is that the early Moon's small core had a mantle that wasn't much cooler than its core, so there would not have been significant convection to produce a sufficiently strong dynamo.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/have-we-finally-solved-mystery-of-magnetic-moon-rocks/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/have-we-finally-solved-mystery-of-magnetic-moon-rocks/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/moonrock1-1152x648-1747839801.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/moonrock1-500x500-1747839791.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>OptoMechEngineer/CC BY-SA 4.0</media:credit><media:text>NASA Lunar sample 60015 on display at Space Center Houston Lunar Samples Vault, at NASA's Johnson Space Center</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Google’s Will Smith double is better at eating AI spaghetti … but it’s crunchy?</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/googles-will-smith-double-is-better-at-eating-ai-spaghetti-but-its-crunchy/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/googles-will-smith-double-is-better-at-eating-ai-spaghetti-but-its-crunchy/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 17:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ai video generator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deepfakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Veo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spaghetti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veo 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video synthesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[will smith]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/googles-will-smith-double-is-better-at-eating-ai-spaghetti-but-its-crunchy/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Veo 3 is a major leap in AI video synthesis, but the sound effects need more cooking time.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>On Tuesday, Google <a href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/generative-media-models-io-2025/#veo-3">launched Veo 3</a>, a new AI video synthesis model that can do something no major AI video generator has been able to do before: create a synchronized audio track. While from 2022 to 2024, we saw early steps in AI video generation, each video was silent and usually very short in duration. Now you can hear voices, dialog, and sound effects in eight-second high-definition video clips.</p>
<p>Shortly after the new launch, people began asking the most obvious benchmarking question: How good is Veo 3 at faking Oscar-winning actor Will Smith at eating spaghetti?</p>
<p>First, a brief recap. The spaghetti benchmark in AI video traces its origins back to March 2023, when <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/03/yes-virginia-there-is-ai-joy-in-seeing-fake-will-smith-ravenously-eat-spaghetti/">we first covered</a> an early example of horrific AI-generated video using an open source video synthesis model called ModelScope. The spaghetti example later became well-known enough that Smith <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/02/will-smith-parodies-viral-ai-generated-video-by-actually-eating-spaghetti/">parodied it</a> almost a year later in February 2024.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/googles-will-smith-double-is-better-at-eating-ai-spaghetti-but-its-crunchy/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/googles-will-smith-double-is-better-at-eating-ai-spaghetti-but-its-crunchy/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/spaghetii_2025_veo3_header-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/spaghetii_2025_veo3_header-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:text>A still frame of "Will Smith eating spaghetti" in Google's Veo 3 AI video generator.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Desktop Survivors 98 is more than just a retro Windows nostalgia trip</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/desktop-survivors-98-is-more-than-just-a-retro-windows-nostalgia-trip/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/desktop-survivors-98-is-more-than-just-a-retro-windows-nostalgia-trip/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 16:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[survivors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vamprie Survivors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 95]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 98]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/desktop-survivors-98-is-more-than-just-a-retro-windows-nostalgia-trip/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Tight mouse controls and inventive weapons build on a loving old-school computing homage.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[
<p>Is it weird to have nostalgia for an operating system? I don't mean missing a particular feature that's been removed from modern versions or a specific productivity setting that's no longer supported. I mean a sense of longing for the vibes of the computer interface you grew up with, an ache for the aesthetics of user interfaces past.</p>
<p>I would have thought I was immune to this particular brand of nostalgia. Then I happened upon <em>Desktop Survivors 98</em>, a new <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/10/vampire-survivors-a-cheap-minimalistic-indie-game-is-my-game-of-the-year/"><em>Vampire Survivors</em></a>-style "bullet heaven" autoshooter that leans hard into the aesthetics of the late '90s Windows machines I grew up with. And while that low-res, 256-color presentation is what drew me in, it was the intriguing mouse-controlled gameplay underneath that has kept me coming back for more retro-styled action all week.</p>
<h2>Start me up</h2>
<p>When it comes to capturing the feel of the '90s computer environment, <em>Desktop Survivors 98</em> gets everything just right. This is in large part due to rampant theft of familiar old-school icons; items like My Computer, Calculator, <em>Minesweeper</em>, Search, and more look like they were taken directly from a classic Microsoft tile set. The game's low-res desktop backgrounds and Windows also look like they came out of a years-old Microsoft style book.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/desktop-survivors-98-is-more-than-just-a-retro-windows-nostalgia-trip/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/desktop-survivors-98-is-more-than-just-a-retro-windows-nostalgia-trip/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ss_f84031b7aa9a335c956a5f63c8f7c131a0b0b522-1152x648-1748017396.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ss_f84031b7aa9a335c956a5f63c8f7c131a0b0b522-500x500-1748017385.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:text>Help, my Windows 98 machine is being invaded!</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>CDC can no longer help prevent lead poisoning in children, state officials say</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-can-no-longer-help-prevent-lead-poisoning-in-children-state-officials-say/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-can-no-longer-help-prevent-lead-poisoning-in-children-state-officials-say/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 15:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[applesauce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lead]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert F. Kennedy]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-can-no-longer-help-prevent-lead-poisoning-in-children-state-officials-say/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Under Trump, the CDC's Childhood Lead Poisoning Prevention Program was cut.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Amid the brutal cuts across the federal government under the Trump administration, perhaps one of the most gutting is the loss of experts at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention who respond to lead poisoning in children.</p>
<p>On April 1, the staff of the CDC's Childhood Lead Poisoning Prevention Program was terminated as part of the agency's reduction in force, <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2025/05/21/nx-s1-5405551/lead-poisoning-cdc-hhs-rfk-jr-trump-baldwin-senate">according to NPR</a>. The staff included epidemiologists, statisticians, and advisors who specialized in lead exposures and responses.</p>
<p>The cuts were immediately consequential to health officials in Milwaukee, who are currently dealing with a lead exposure crisis in public schools. Six schools have had to close, displacing 1,800 students. In April, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/05/20/health/kennedy-lead-contamination-milwaukee">the city requested help from the CDC's lead experts</a>, but the request was denied—there was no one left to help.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-can-no-longer-help-prevent-lead-poisoning-in-children-state-officials-say/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/cdc-can-no-longer-help-prevent-lead-poisoning-in-children-state-officials-say/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>177</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/lead-apple-11032023.png">
<media:thumbnail height="430" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/lead-apple-11032023-500x430.png" width="500"/>
<media:credit>FDA</media:credit><media:text>The three recalled pouches linked to lead poisonings.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>US solar keeps surging, generating more power than hydro in 2025</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/us-solar-keeps-surging-generating-more-power-than-hydro-in-2025/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/us-solar-keeps-surging-generating-more-power-than-hydro-in-2025/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[John Timmer]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 15:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hydro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[natural gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wind]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/us-solar-keeps-surging-generating-more-power-than-hydro-in-2025/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Continued rising demand still outpacing growth of renewables in the US.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>In the US, many newly constructed generating facilities are brought online at the end of the year to qualify for tax incentives. Since much of the US's new generating capacity is solar power, that has led to a boom in solar production to start the year in recent years. With the first three months of data in for 2025, it's clear this year is no exception: Solar power is up a staggering 44 percent compared to the prior year.</p>
<p>That's the good news. The bad news is that, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/analysis-shows-that-chinas-emissions-are-dropping-due-to-renewables/">in contrast to China</a>, solar's growth hasn't been enough to offset rising demand. Instead, the US also saw significant growth in coal use, which rose by 23 percent compared to the year prior, after years of steady decline.</p>
<p>Short-term fluctuations in demand are normal, generally driven by weather-induced demand for heating or cooling. Despite those changes, demand for electricity in the US has been largely flat for over a decade, largely thanks to gains in efficiency. But 2024 saw demand go up by nearly 3 percent, and the first quarter of 2025 saw another rise, this time of nearly 5 percent. It's a bit too early to say that we're seeing a shift to a period of rising demand, but one has been predicted for some time due to rising data center use and the increased electrification of transportation and appliances.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/us-solar-keeps-surging-generating-more-power-than-hydro-in-2025/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/05/us-solar-keeps-surging-generating-more-power-than-hydro-in-2025/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>95</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2155735205-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2155735205-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>gece33</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>SteamOS 3.7 brings Valve’s gaming OS to other handhelds and generic AMD PCs</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/steamos-3-7-brings-valves-gaming-os-to-other-handhelds-and-generic-amd-pcs/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/steamos-3-7-brings-valves-gaming-os-to-other-handhelds-and-generic-amd-pcs/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 15:28:43 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asus rog ally]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asus rog ally x]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lenovo legion go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steam deck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steamos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Valve]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/steamos-3-7-brings-valves-gaming-os-to-other-handhelds-and-generic-amd-pcs/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Focus is currently on AMD-based PCs with hardware similar to the Steam Deck.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Valve is releasing <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1675200/view/820329049655084700">version 3.7 of SteamOS to the general public</a>, and among the routine updates and changes is a big one: This is the SteamOS release that finally adds official support for some kinds of PC hardware other than Valve's Steam Deck.</p>
<p>Valve mentions certain specific handhelds as having either "official" or "improved support," including the Asus ROG Ally, the Lenovo Legion Go, and the Lenovo Legion Go S. It also includes directions for configuring the original Legion Go and ROG Ally for SteamOS installation. But Valve says that only the Steam Deck and Legion Go S have fully baked SteamOS support.</p>
<p>The release claims to run on "other AMD powered handhelds" more broadly, implying that most third-party handheld PCs with Ryzen Z1 or Z2-series processors ought to support at least some basic functionality. Other all-AMD desktops and laptops have a decent shot at being supported, too.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/steamos-3-7-brings-valves-gaming-os-to-other-handhelds-and-generic-amd-pcs/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/steamos-3-7-brings-valves-gaming-os-to-other-handhelds-and-generic-amd-pcs/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>76</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/steamos-logo.jpg">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/steamos-logo-500x500-1748012862.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Valve</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Uncertainty loomed as FDA advisors met to discuss this year’s COVID shot</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/fda-advisors-for-covid-shots-left-in-the-dark-over-how-theyll-be-regulated/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/fda-advisors-for-covid-shots-left-in-the-dark-over-how-theyll-be-regulated/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 15:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[annual shots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seasonal shots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccines]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/fda-advisors-for-covid-shots-left-in-the-dark-over-how-theyll-be-regulated/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[FDA advisors wanted to know what switching strains means. FDA couldn't answer.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Expert advisors for the Food and Drug Administration <a href="https://www.fda.gov/advisory-committees/advisory-committee-calendar/vaccines-and-related-biological-products-advisory-committee-may-22-2025-meeting-announcement">met Thursday</a> to discuss which virus strain this year's updated COVID-19 vaccines should target. The advisors have been meeting around this time each year for such a strain selection, a routine decision in the process of updating the lifesaving vaccines.</p>
<p>But this year's meeting was awkward and even a little tense. Earlier this week, new FDA leaders under health secretary and anti-vaccine advocate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. announced <a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/under-anti-vaccine-advocate-rfk-jr-fda-to-limit-access-to-covid-19-shots/">a sweeping new framework that would restrict access to the shots</a>, making them available only to people 65 and older and those with medical conditions that put them at risk of severe illness. For updated COVID-19 vaccines to be approved for healthy children and adults, vaccine makers would need to repeat large, randomized, placebo-controlled trials, which are expensive, ethically debatable at this point, and could easily take too much time to complete before the shots would need to be ready for fall vaccinations. The advisors weren't consulted on the new framework, and there is much uncertainty about its implementation.</p>
<p>Just 30 minutes into yesterday's nearly seven-hour meeting, one committee member broached one of the largest looming questions, saying, "If a different strain was selected for this season, would that require additional clinical trials, etc.?"</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/fda-advisors-for-covid-shots-left-in-the-dark-over-how-theyll-be-regulated/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/05/fda-advisors-for-covid-shots-left-in-the-dark-over-how-theyll-be-regulated/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>125</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/GettyImages-1238045983-1152x648.jpeg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/GettyImages-1238045983-500x500.jpeg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Marcos del Mazo</media:credit><media:text>The Comirnaty (Pfizer/BioNTech) and Moderna COVID-19 vaccines.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Trump threatens Apple with 25% tariff to force iPhone manufacturing into US</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/trump-threatens-apple-with-25-tariff-to-force-iphone-manufacturing-into-us/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/trump-threatens-apple-with-25-tariff-to-force-iphone-manufacturing-into-us/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 14:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital services tax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tariffs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Cook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us-china trade war]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/trump-threatens-apple-with-25-tariff-to-force-iphone-manufacturing-into-us/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Apple first US firm in Trump’s trade war crosshairs as tariff talks go sour.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump woke up Friday morning and threatened Apple with a 25 percent tariff on any iPhones sold in the US that are not manufactured in America.</p>
<p>In a Truth Social post, Trump claimed that he had "long ago" told Apple CEO Tim Cook that Apple's plan to manufacture iPhones for the US market in India was unacceptable. Only US-made iPhones should be sold here, he said.</p>
<p>"If that is not the case, a tariff of at least 25 percent must be paid by Apple to the US," Trump said.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/trump-threatens-apple-with-25-tariff-to-force-iphone-manufacturing-into-us/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/trump-threatens-apple-with-25-tariff-to-force-iphone-manufacturing-into-us/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>231</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-1098060106-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-1098060106-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Kira-Yan | iStock / Getty Images Plus</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Rocket Report: SpaceX’s expansion at Vandenberg; India’s PSLV fails in flight</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/rocket-report-spacexs-expansion-at-vandenberg-indias-pslv-fails-in-flight/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/rocket-report-spacexs-expansion-at-vandenberg-indias-pslv-fails-in-flight/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Stephen Clark]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 11:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket report]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/rocket-report-spacexs-expansion-at-vandenberg-indias-pslv-fails-in-flight/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[China's diversity in rockets was evident this week, with four types of launchers in action.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Edition 7.45 of the Rocket Report! Let's talk about spaceplanes. Since the Space Shuttle, spaceplanes have, at best, been a niche part of the space transportation business. The US Air Force's uncrewed X-37B and a similar vehicle operated by China's military are the only spaceplanes to reach orbit since the last shuttle flight in 2011, and both require a lift from a conventional rocket. Virgin Galactic's suborbital space tourism platform is also a spaceplane of sorts. A generation or two ago, one of the chief arguments in favor of spaceplanes was that they were easier to recover and reuse. Today, SpaceX routinely reuses capsules and rockets that look much more like conventional space vehicles than the winged designs of yesteryear. Spaceplanes are undeniably alluring in appearance, but they have the drawback of carrying extra weight (wings) into space that won't be used until the final minutes of a mission. So, do they have a future?</p>
<p>As always, we <a href="https://arstechnica.wufoo.com/forms/launch-stories/">welcome reader submissions</a>. If you don't want to miss an issue, please subscribe using the box below (the form will not appear on AMP-enabled versions of the site). Each report will include information on small-, medium-, and heavy-lift rockets, as well as a quick look ahead at the next three launches on the calendar.</p>
<figure class="ars-img-shortcode id-1314289 align-center">
    <div>
                        <img decoding="async" width="560" height="81" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png" class="center full" alt="" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png 560w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll-300x43.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
                  </div>
      </figure>

<p><b>One of China's commercial rockets returns to flight. </b>The Kinetica-1 rocket launched Wednesday for the first time since a failure doomed its previous attempt to reach orbit in December, according to the vehicle's developer and operator, CAS Space. The Kinetica-1 is one of several small Chinese solid-fueled launch vehicles managed by a commercial company, although with strict government oversight and support. CAS Space, a spinoff of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, said its Kinetica-1 rocket deployed multiple payloads with "excellent orbit insertion accuracy." This was the seventh flight of a Kinetica-1 rocket since its debut in 2022.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/rocket-report-spacexs-expansion-at-vandenberg-indias-pslv-fails-in-flight/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/rocket-report-spacexs-expansion-at-vandenberg-indias-pslv-fails-in-flight/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>88</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Mk-IIAuroraTakeoff-StockimageJuly2024-1152x648-1747956205.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Mk-IIAuroraTakeoff-StockimageJuly2024-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Dawn Aerospace</media:credit><media:text>Dawn Aerospace's Mk-II Aurora airplane in flight over New Zealand last year.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>In 3.5 years, Notepad.exe has gone from “barely maintained” to “it writes for you”</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/in-3-5-years-notepad-exe-has-gone-from-barely-maintained-to-it-writes-for-you/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/in-3-5-years-notepad-exe-has-gone-from-barely-maintained-to-it-writes-for-you/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 22:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copilot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11 24h2]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/in-3-5-years-notepad-exe-has-gone-from-barely-maintained-to-it-writes-for-you/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[AI features in Windows are gradually becoming more widespread and inescapable.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>By late 2021, major updates for Windows' built-in Notepad text editor had been so rare for so long that a gentle redesign and a handful of new settings were <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/10/the-latest-app-to-get-a-windows-11-redesign-the-humble-notepad/">rated as a major update</a>. New updates have become much more common since then, but like the rest of Windows, recent additions have been overwhelmingly weighted in the direction of generative AI.</p>
<p>In November, Microsoft <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/11/notepad-exe-now-an-actively-maintained-app-has-gotten-its-inevitable-ai-update/">began testing an update</a> that allowed users to rewrite or summarize text in Notepad using generative AI. Another preview update today <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2025/05/22/paint-snipping-tool-and-notepad-updates-with-new-features-begin-rolling-out-to-windows-insiders/">takes it one step further</a>, allowing you to write AI-generated text from scratch with basic instructions (the feature is called Write, to differentiate it from the earlier Rewrite).</p>
<p>Like Rewrite and Summarize, Write requires users to be signed into a Microsoft Account, because using it requires you to use your monthly allotment of Microsoft's AI credits. <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/understanding-ai-credits-68530f1a-4459-4d02-9818-8233c1f673b8">Per this support page</a>, users without a paid Microsoft 365 subscription get 15 credits per month. Subscribers with Personal and Family subscriptions get 60 credits per month instead.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/in-3-5-years-notepad-exe-has-gone-from-barely-maintained-to-it-writes-for-you/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/in-3-5-years-notepad-exe-has-gone-from-barely-maintained-to-it-writes-for-you/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>167</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/notepad-listing-1152x648.png" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/notepad-listing-500x500.png" width="500"/>
</media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>The Pentagon seems to be fed up with ULA’s rocket delays</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/the-pentagon-seems-to-be-fed-up-with-ulas-rocket-delays/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/the-pentagon-seems-to-be-fed-up-with-ulas-rocket-delays/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Eric Berger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 22:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Air Force]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ula]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulcan]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/the-pentagon-seems-to-be-fed-up-with-ulas-rocket-delays/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA["The ULA Vulcan program has performed unsatisfactorily this past year."]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>In recent written testimony to a US House of Representatives subcommittee that oversees the military, the senior official responsible for purchasing launches for national security missions blistered one of the country's two primary rocket providers.</p>
<p>The remarks from Major General Stephen G. Purdy, acting assistant secretary of the Air Force for Space Acquisition and Integration, concerned United Launch Alliance and its long-delayed development of the large Vulcan rocket.</p>
<p>"The ULA Vulcan program has performed unsatisfactorily this past year," Purdy said in <a href="https://armedservices.house.gov/uploadedfiles/14_may_on_fy26_national_security_space_programs_-_maj_gen_purdy_approved_for_release.pdf">written testimony</a> during a May 14 hearing before the House Armed Services Committee's Subcommittee on Strategic Forces. This portion of his testimony did not come up during the hearing, and it has not been reported publicly to date.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/the-pentagon-seems-to-be-fed-up-with-ulas-rocket-delays/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/05/the-pentagon-seems-to-be-fed-up-with-ulas-rocket-delays/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>68</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/54042580673_34b41b5a82_k-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/54042580673_34b41b5a82_k-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>United Launch Alliance</media:credit><media:text>The second flight of United Launch Alliance's Vulcan rocket took off in October. The test flight was successful despite a malfunction with one of its solid rocket boosters.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Why console makers can legally brick your game console</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/why-console-makers-can-legally-brick-your-game-console/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/why-console-makers-can-legally-brick-your-game-console/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 22:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EULA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Switch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XBox]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/why-console-makers-can-legally-brick-your-game-console/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA["If the ability [to brick a console] is there, someone will want to 'see how it goes.'"]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, Nintendo <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/nintendo-threatens-to-brick-switch-consoles-for-hacking-piracy/">received a lot of negative attention for an end-user license agreement </a>(EULA) update granting the company the claimed right to render Switch consoles "permanently unusable in whole or in part" for violations such as suspected hacking or piracy. As it turns out, though, Nintendo isn't the only console manufacturer that threatens to remotely brick systems in response to rule violations. And attorneys tell Ars Technica that they're probably well within their legal rights to do so.</p>
<p>Sony's <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/legal/ps5-ssla/">System Software License Agreement on the PS5</a>, for instance, contains the following paragraph of "remedies" it can take for "violations" such as use of modified hardware or pirated software (emphasis added).</p>
<blockquote><p>If SIE Inc determines that you have violated this Agreement's terms, SIE Inc may itself or may procure the taking of any action to protect its interests such as disabling access to or use of some or all System Software, <em>disabling use of this PS5 system online or offline</em>, termination of your access to PlayStation Network, denial of any warranty, repair or other services provided for your PS5 system, implementation of automatic or mandatory updates or devices <em>intended to discontinue unauthorized use</em>, or reliance on any other remedial efforts as reasonably necessary to prevent the use of modified or unpermitted use of System Software.</p></blockquote>
<p>The same exact clause appears in <a href="https://doc.dl.playstation.net/doc/ps4-eula/ps4_eula_en.html">the PlayStation 4 EULA</a> as well. The <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/legal/ps3-system-software-license-agreement/">PlayStation 3 EULA</a> was missing the "disabling use... online or offline" clause, but it does still warn that Sony can take steps to "discontinue unauthorized use" or "prevent the use of a modified PS3 system, or any pirated material or equipment."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/why-console-makers-can-legally-brick-your-game-console/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/why-console-makers-can-legally-brick-your-game-console/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>110</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-637736904-1152x648-1747949541.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-637736904-500x500-1747949658.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>The martial artist is a console maker. The brick is your console.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Musk’s DOGE used Meta’s Llama 2—not Grok—for gov’t slashing, report says</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/musks-doge-used-metas-llama-2-not-grok-for-govt-slashing-report-says/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/musks-doge-used-metas-llama-2-not-grok-for-govt-slashing-report-says/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 21:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[azure ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[department of government efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Llama 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xAI]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/musks-doge-used-metas-llama-2-not-grok-for-govt-slashing-report-says/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Grok apparently wasn't an option.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p style="font-weight: 400;">An outdated Meta AI model was apparently at the center of the Department of Government Efficiency's initial ploy to purge parts of the federal government.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/doge-used-meta-ai-model-review-fork-emails-from-federal-workers/">Wired reviewed materials</a> showing that affiliates of Elon Musk's DOGE working in the Office of Personnel Management "tested and used Meta’s Llama 2 model to review and classify responses from federal workers to the infamous 'Fork in the Road' email that was sent across the government in late January."</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The "Fork in the Road" memo <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/01/copying-musk-trump-admin-offers-federal-workers-buyouts-to-resign/">seemed to copy a memo that Musk sent to Twitter employees</a>, giving federal workers the choice to be "loyal"—and accept the government's return-to-office policy—or else resign. At the time, it was rumored that DOGE was feeding government employee data into AI, and Wired confirmed that records indicate <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/07/meta-launches-llama-2-an-open-source-ai-model-that-allows-commercial-applications/">Llama 2</a> was used to sort through responses and see how many employees had resigned.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/musks-doge-used-metas-llama-2-not-grok-for-govt-slashing-report-says/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/05/musks-doge-used-metas-llama-2-not-grok-for-govt-slashing-report-says/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2175352401-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2175352401-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Anadolu / Contributor | Anadolu</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Gouach wants you to insert and pluck the cells from its Infinite e-bike battery</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/gouach-wants-you-to-insert-and-pluck-the-cells-from-its-infinite-e-bike-battery/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/gouach-wants-you-to-insert-and-pluck-the-cells-from-its-infinite-e-bike-battery/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kevin Purdy]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 20:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bike battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-bike conversion kit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gouach]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/gouach-wants-you-to-insert-and-pluck-the-cells-from-its-infinite-e-bike-battery/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Tiny French firm wants to keep a few bad cells from spoiling a lot of e-bikes.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>E-bike batteries are, for the most part, a collection of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/18650_battery">18650 batteries</a>, <a href="https://www.ebikeschool.com/how-to-build-a-diy-electric-bicycle-lithium-battery-from-18650-cells/">packaged together and welded in series and parallel</a>, attached to a battery management system (BMS). A "dead" e-bike battery may only have two or three truly dead cells inside, while the remainder work fine. This is useful knowledge that, for the most part, very few e-bike owners can really use. Arc welders are not a common tool to own, and most e-bike batteries are not designed to be opened, safely or otherwise.</p>
<p>French firm Gouach, essentially a three-person company, is pitching its <a href="https://www.gouach.com/">Infinite Battery</a> as the opposite of this status quo. It's a <a href="https://gouach.com/blogs/blogs/harsh-tests-made-on-the-infinite-battery">durable, fireproof casing</a> into which you can place and replace 18650 batteries <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8q-EEXqXcCA">using only a screwdriver</a>. It keeps you updated on the status of cell performance and heat through a Bluetooth-connected app. And it's designed for <a href="https://gouach.com/blogs/blogs/universal-compatibility-will-infinite-work-with-your-ebike">compatibility</a> with "90% of existing e-bike brands," or you can upgrade an existing "acoustic" model.</p>
<p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach2.jpg"><img width="1024" height="711" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach2-1024x711.jpg" class="center large" alt="Gouach e-bike battery, with cells, circuit board connectors, and BMS exposed, with a few loose cells nearby." decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach2-1024x711.jpg 1024w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach2-640x444.jpg 640w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach2-768x533.jpg 768w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach2-1536x1067.jpg 1536w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach2-2048x1422.jpg 2048w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach2-980x681.jpg 980w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach2-1440x1000.jpg 1440w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px">
        Credit:
          Gouach
      </a></p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/gouach-wants-you-to-insert-and-pluck-the-cells-from-its-infinite-e-bike-battery/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/05/gouach-wants-you-to-insert-and-pluck-the-cells-from-its-infinite-e-bike-battery/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>101</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach3-1152x648.jpeg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/gouach3-500x500.jpeg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Gouach</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>