<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
	<atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:55:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>“Slapped cheek” virus is surging across Europe and US, CDC warns</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043044</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/slapped-cheek-virus-is-surging-across-europe-and-us-cdc-warns/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth Mole]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 22:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infectious disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parvovirus B19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It's often mild, but can be very dangerous in pregnancy and immunocompromised.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Parvovirus-B19-Slapped-Cheek-Rash-800x518.webp" alt='A child with a "slapped cheek" rash'>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Parvovirus-B19-Slapped-Cheek-Rash.webp" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1325" data-width="2048">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A child with a "slapped cheek" rash (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.cdc.gov/parvovirus-b19/about/index.html#cdc_disease_basics_compli-complications">CDC</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>A common seasonal respiratory virus that typically infects school-aged children is causing an unusually large spike in cases across Europe and the US this summer. The surge in transmission is a significant danger to certain vulnerable populations including pregnant people, according to <a href="https://emergency.cdc.gov/han/2024/han00514.asp">a health alert released by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention on Tuesday</a>.</p>
<p>The virus is parvovirus B19, aka B19V, which spreads via respiratory droplets and typically causes a mild, two-phased illness in children. The first phase is marked by flu-like symptoms that can include fever, headache, malaise, muscle aches, cough, sore throat, and joint pain. In the second phase, a characteristic "slapped cheek" rash develops, which is also called Fifth Disease or Erythema Infectiosum. By age 20, about 50 percent of people have been infected and have antibodies that can help fight reinfection. And by age 40, the figure rises to 70 percent.</p>
<p>But, for those who have compromised immune systems, are pregnant, or have certain conditions, such as sickle cell anemia, the virus can cause severe complications, such as severe anemia, myocarditis, hepatitis, or encephalitis. In pregnancy, the virus can infect the fetus and cause dangerous complications and miscarriage.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043044#p3">Read 6 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043044&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/slapped-cheek-virus-is-surging-across-europe-and-us-cdc-warns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk went judge shopping in ad lawsuit and didn’t get the judge he wanted</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043030</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/elon-musks-preferred-judge-recuses-himself-from-xs-case-against-advertisers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 22:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Judge who had stock in Tesla and Unilever drops X case over alleged ad boycott.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/elon-musk-satellite-conference-800x533.jpg" alt="Elon Musk frowns while sitting on stage during a conference interview.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/elon-musk-satellite-conference.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1667" data-width="2500">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Elon Musk speaks at the Satellite Conference and Exhibition on March 9, 2020 in Washington, DC. (credit: Getty Images | Win McNamee )</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>US District Judge Reed O'Connor today recused himself from Elon Musk's lawsuit alleging that advertisers targeted X with an illegal boycott.</p>
<p>O'Connor was apparently Musk's preferred judge in the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/elon-musk-declares-it-is-war-on-ad-industry-as-x-sues-over-illegal-boycott/">lawsuit</a> filed last week against the World Federation of Advertisers (WFA) and several large corporations. In order to land O'Connor, the Musk-owned X Corp. sued in the Wichita Falls division of the US District Court for the Northern District of Texas.</p>
<p>O'Connor purchased Tesla stock, a fact that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/07/no-judge-with-tesla-stock-should-handle-elon-musk-cases-watchdog-argues/">generated controversy</a> in a different X lawsuit that he is still overseeing. He also invested in Unilever, one of the defendants in X's advertising lawsuit. The Unilever investment appears to be what drove O'Connor's recusal decision.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043030#p3">Read 12 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2043030&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/elon-musks-preferred-judge-recuses-himself-from-xs-case-against-advertisers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NASA chief to scientists on budget cuts: “I feel your pain”</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042859</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/08/a-conversation-with-nasa-chief-bill-nelson-on-artemis-budget-holes-and-more/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Berger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 21:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bill nelson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["I can't go and print the dollars."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/11-Boeing-OFT-2-20210729-9963-800x1200.jpg" alt="Photo of Bill Nelson.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/11-Boeing-OFT-2-20210729-9963.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1600" data-width="1067">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Administrator Bill Nelson delivering remarks and answering questions from the media at the OFT-2 prelaunch press conference. (credit: Trevor Mahlmann)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Ars Technica recently had the opportunity to speak with NASA Administrator Bill Nelson, who has now led the US space agency for more than three years. We spoke about budget issues, Artemis Program timelines, and NASA's role as a soft power in global diplomacy. What follows is a very lightly edited transcript of the conversation between Senior Space Editor Eric Berger and Nelson.</p>
<p><strong>Ars Technica</strong>:<em> I wanted to start with NASA's budget for next year. <a href="https://www.planetary.org/space-policy/nasas-fy-2025-budget">We've now seen the numbers</a> from the House of Senate, and NASA is once again facing some cuts. And I'm just wondering, what are your big concerns as we get into the final budgeting process this fall</em>?</p>
<p><strong>Administrator Bill Nelson</strong>: Well, the big concern is that you can't put 10 pounds of potatoes in a five-pound sack. When you get cut $4.7 billion over two years, and when $2 billion of that over two years is just in science, then you have to start making some hard choices. Now, I understand the reasons for the cuts. Had I still been a member of the Senate I would've voted for it simply because they were held hostage by a small group in the House to get what they wanted. Which was reduced appropriations in order to raise the artificial, statutory budget debt ceiling in order for the government not to go into default. That's part of the legislative process. It's part of the compromises that go on. It happened over a year ago, and it was called the Fiscal Responsibility Act. The price for doing that wasn't cuts across the entire budget. Remember, two-thirds of the budget is entitlement programs like Social Security and Medicare, and it certainly wasn't in defense. So, all the cuts came out of everything left over, including NASA. I'm hoping that we're going to get a reprieve come fiscal year '26 when we will not be in the budgetary constraints of the Fiscal Responsibility Act. But who knows? Because lo and behold, they've got another artificial debt ceiling they're going to have to raise next January.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042859#p3">Read 31 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042859&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/08/a-conversation-with-nasa-chief-bill-nelson-on-artemis-budget-holes-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Classic PC game emulation is back on the iPhone with iDOS 3 release</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042868</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/classic-pc-game-emulation-is-back-on-the-iphone-with-idos-3-release/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samuel Axon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App Store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DOS games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emulator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iDOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iDOS 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MS-DOS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042868</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple amended its App Store rules to allow PC emulators, not just console ones.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/DOS-prompt-800x450-1.jpg" alt="An MS-DOS command line prompt showing the C drive">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/DOS-prompt-800x450-1.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="450" data-width="800">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The start of any journey in MS-DOS. (credit: Samuel Axon)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>After a 14-year journey of various states of availability and usefulness amid the shifting policies of Apple's App Store approval process, MS-DOS game emulator iDOS is <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/idos-3/id1580768213">back</a> on the iPhone and iPad. It's hopefully here to stay this time.</p>
<p>iDOS allows you to run applications made for MS-DOS via DOSBox, with a nice retro-styled interface. Its main use case is definitely playing DOS games, but it has seen a rocky road to get to this point. Initially released over a decade ago, it existed quietly for its niche audience, though it saw some changes that made it more or less useful in the developer's quest to avoid removal from the App Store after it violated Apple's rules. That culminated in it being removed altogether in 2021 after some tweets and articles brought attention to it.</p>
<p>But earlier this year, Apple made <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/04/apple-now-allows-retro-game-emulators-on-its-app-store-but-with-big-caveats/">big changes</a> to its App Store rules, officially allowing "retro game emulators" for the first time. That cleared the way for a wave of working console game emulators like Delta and RetroArch, which mostly work as you might expect them to on any other platform now. But when iDOS developer Chaoji Li and other purveyors of classic PC emulator software attempted to do the same for old PC games for MS-DOS and other non-console computing platforms, they <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/06/apple-rejects-pc-emulators-on-the-ios-app-store/">were stymied</a>. Apple told them that it didn't consider their apps to be retro game console emulators and that they violated rules intended to prevent people from circumventing the App Store by running applications from other sources.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042868#p3">Read 4 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042868&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/classic-pc-game-emulation-is-back-on-the-iphone-with-idos-3-release/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Researchers figure out how to keep clocks on the Earth, Moon in sync</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042977</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/researchers-figure-out-how-to-keep-clocks-on-the-earth-moon-in-sync/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Timmer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A single standardized Earth/Moon time would aid communications, enable lunar GPS.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/image-2-800x600.jpeg" alt="Image of a full Moon behind a dark forest of fir trees.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/image-2.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="900" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Without adjustments for relativity, clocks here and on the Moon would rapidly diverge. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://science.nasa.gov/moon/">NASA</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Timing is everything these days. Our communications and GPS networks all depend on keeping careful track of the precise timing of signals—including accounting for the effects of relativity. The deeper into a gravitational well you go, the slower time moves, and we've reached the point where we can detect differences in altitude of <a href="https://www.nist.gov/news-events/news/2022/02/jila-atomic-clocks-measure-einsteins-general-relativity-millimeter-scale#:~:text=JILA%20physicists%20have%20measured%20Albert,tip%2C%20tick%20at%20different%20rates.">a single millimeter</a>. Time literally flows faster at the altitude where GPS satellites are than it does for clocks situated on Earth's surface. Complicating matters further, those satellites are moving at high velocities, an effect that slows things down.</p>
<p>It's relatively easy to account for that on the Earth, where we're dealing with a single set of adjustments that can be programmed into electronics that need to keep track of these things. But plans are in place to send a large array of hardware to the Moon, which has a considerably lower gravitational field (faster clocks!), which means that objects can stay in orbit despite moving more slowly (also faster clocks!).</p>
<p>It would be easy to set up an equivalent system to track time on the Moon, but that would inevitably see the clocks run out of sync with those on Earth—a serious problem for things like scientific observations. So, the International Astronomical Union <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1vUc8tSFe4VjzocLVf6dlEZyDSA8NhOFE/view">has a resolution</a> that calls for a "Lunar Celestial Reference System" and "Lunar Coordinate Time" to handle things there. On Monday, two researchers at the National institute of Standards and Technology, Neil Ashby and Bijunath Patla, did the math to show how this might work.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042977#p3">Read 9 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042977&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/researchers-figure-out-how-to-keep-clocks-on-the-earth-moon-in-sync/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>63</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5th Circuit rules geofence warrants illegal in win for phone users’ privacy</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042955</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/5th-circuit-rules-geofence-warrants-illegal-in-win-for-phone-users-privacy/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5th circuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geofence warrants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Court rules geofence warrants are illegal searches under Fourth Amendment.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/city-network-800x533.jpg" alt="Illustration of map pins on a cityscape in an abstract representation of network connections">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/city-network.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1667" data-width="2500">Enlarge</a> (credit: Getty Images | )</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>A federal appeals court ruled on Friday that geofence warrants, which are used to identify all users or devices in a geographic area, are prohibited by the Fourth Amendment's protection against unreasonable searches.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.ca5.uscourts.gov/opinions/pub/23/23-60321-CR0.pdf">ruling</a> was issued by the US Court of Appeals for the 5th Circuit, which is generally regarded as the most conservative appeals court. The 5th Circuit holding creates a circuit split with the 4th Circuit, which last month rejected a different Fourth Amendment challenge to geofence warrants.</p>
<p>"This court 'cannot forgive the requirements of the Fourth Amendment in the name of law enforcement.' Accordingly, we hold that geofence warrants are general warrants categorically prohibited by the Fourth Amendment," the August 9 ruling from the 5th Circuit said.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042955#p3">Read 27 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042955&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/5th-circuit-rules-geofence-warrants-illegal-in-win-for-phone-users-privacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-driving Waymo cars keep SF residents awake all night by honking at each other</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042921</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/08/self-driving-waymo-cars-keep-sf-residents-awake-all-night-by-honking-at-each-other/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 19:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nbc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-driving car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waymo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Haunted by glitching algorithms, self-driving cars disturb the peace in San Francisco.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/waymo_getty-800x450.jpg" alt="A Waymo self-driving car in front of Google's San Francisco headquarters, San Francisco, California, June 7, 2024.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/waymo_getty.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="675" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A Waymo self-driving car in front of Google's San Francisco headquarters, San Francisco, California, June 7, 2024. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/waymo-self-driving-car-in-front-of-googles-san-francisco-news-photo/2157160824">Getty Images</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Silicon Valley's latest disruption? Your sleep schedule. On Saturday, NBC Bay Area <a href="https://www.nbcbayarea.com/news/local/san-francisco/san-francisco-neighbors-say-repeated-waymo-honking-is-keeping-them-up-at-night/3622181/">reported</a> that San Francisco's South of Market residents are being awakened throughout the night by Waymo self-driving cars honking at each other in a parking lot. No one is inside the cars, and they appear to be automatically reacting to each other's presence.</p>
<p>Videos provided by residents to NBC show Waymo cars filing into the parking lot and attempting to back into spots, which seems to trigger honking from other Waymo vehicles. The automatic nature of these interactions—which seem to peak around 4 am every night—has left neighbors bewildered and sleep-deprived.</p>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"><iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WGwVnVr9y2Y?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">NBC Bay Area's report: "Waymo cars keep SF neighborhood awake." </p></div>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">According to NBC, the disturbances began several weeks ago when Waymo vehicles started using a parking lot off 2nd Street near Harrison Street. Residents in <a href="https://x.com/semajrabnud/status/1823391477461815772">nearby high-rise buildings</a> have observed the autonomous vehicles entering the lot to pause between rides, but the cars' behavior has become a source of frustration for the neighborhood.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042921#p3">Read 3 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042921&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/08/self-driving-waymo-cars-keep-sf-residents-awake-all-night-by-honking-at-each-other/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>117</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why cricket’s latest bowling technique is so effective against batters</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042516</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/why-crickets-latest-bowling-technique-is-so-effective-against-batters/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 19:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aerodynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cricket game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fluid dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magnus effect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wind tunnel experiments show how the ball's transverse spin impacts pressure fields.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/cricket3-800x529.jpg" alt="Some cricket bowlers favor keeping the arm horizontal during delivery, the better to trick the batsmen.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/cricket3.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="794" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Some cricket bowlers favor keeping the arm horizontal during delivery, the better to trick the batsmen. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/">Rae Allen/CC BY 2.0</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Although the sport of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cricket">cricket</a> has been around for centuries in some form, the game strategy continues to evolve in the 21st century. Among the newer strategies employed by "bowlers"—the equivalent of the pitcher in baseball—is delivering the ball with the arm horizontally positioned close to the shoulder line, which has proven remarkably effective in "tricking" batsmen in their perception of the ball's trajectory.</p>
<p>Scientists at Amity University Dubai in the United Arab Emirates were curious about the effectiveness of the approach, so they tested the aerodynamics of cricket balls in wind tunnel experiments. The team concluded that this style of bowling creates a high-speed spinning effect that shifts the ball's trajectory mid-flight—an effect also seen in certain baseball pitches, according to a <a href="https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0215749">new paper</a> published in the journal Physics of Fluids.</p>
<p>“The unique and unorthodox bowling styles demonstrated by cricketers have drawn significant attention, particularly emphasizing their proficiency with a new ball in early stages of a match,” <a href="https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/1054079">said co-author Kizhakkelan Sudhakaran Siddharth,</a> a mechanical engineer at Amity University Dubai. “Their bowling techniques frequently deceive batsmen, rendering these bowlers effective throughout all phases of a match in almost all formats of the game.”</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042516#p3">Read 11 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042516&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/why-crickets-latest-bowling-technique-is-so-effective-against-batters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>86</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ex-Twitter staffer wins $600K over Musk’s click-yes-or-resign ultimatum</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042876</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/elon-musk-loses-fight-with-ex-twitter-staffer-must-pay-600k/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 18:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employment law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[severance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[x corp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Elon Musk’s 24-hour email ultimatum unfairly dismissed Twitter staff, court says.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2164441937-800x534.jpg" alt="Ex-Twitter staffer wins $600K over Musk’s click-yes-or-resign ultimatum">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2164441937.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="683" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/elon-musk-arrives-at-the-10th-annual-breakthrough-prize-news-photo/2164441937?adppopup=true">Craig T Fruchtman / Contributor | Getty Images Entertainment</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Elon Musk had no business sending Twitter employees an <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2022/11/musk-tells-twitter-staff-agree-to-work-long-hours-at-high-intensity-or-quit-now/">email giving them 24 hours to click "yes" to keep their jobs</a> or else voluntarily resign during his takeover in 2022, an Irish workplace watchdog ruled Monday.</p>
<p>Not only did the email not provide staff with enough notice, the labor court ruled, but also any employee's failure to click "yes" could in no way constitute a legal act of resignation. Instead, the court reviewed evidence alleging that the email appeared designed to either get employees to agree to new employment terms, sight unseen, or else push employees to volunteer for dismissal during a time of mass layoffs across Twitter.</p>
<p>"Going forward, to build a breakthrough Twitter 2.0 and succeed in an increasingly competitive world, we will need to be extremely hardcore," Musk wrote in the all-staff email. "This will mean working long hours at high intensity. Only exceptional performance will constitute a passing grade."</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042876#p3">Read 14 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042876&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/elon-musk-loses-fight-with-ex-twitter-staffer-must-pay-600k/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>119</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google’s Pixel Watch 3 has a bigger screen, and Pixel Buds Pro 2 are smaller</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042621</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/googles-pixel-watch-3-has-a-bigger-screen-and-pixel-buds-pro-2-are-smaller/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Purdy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google pixel buds pro 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google pixel watch 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pixel buds pro 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pixel recorder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pixel watch 3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pixel Recorder on the Watch 3 is the weird little feature we might just love.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Band-Lineup-800x450.jpeg" alt="Pixel Watch 3 laid out at center, with band options and colors to either side of it.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Band-Lineup.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1303" data-width="2316">Enlarge</a> (credit: Google)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>In addition to a whole bunch of Pixel 9 phones, Google launched the Pixel Watch 3 and Pixel Buds Pro 2 at its <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N_y2tP9of8A">Made by Google event today</a>. Here's the lowdown on what's new, what's interesting, and what Google has to say about the products beyond their AI connection.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img alt="The Pixel Watch 3 45 mm model, which boasts 40 percent more usable screen space than the prior model." src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Pixel-Watch-3-45mm_Active-Hazel_Side-2-scaled.jpeg"><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">The Pixel Watch 3 45 mm model, which boasts 40 percent more usable screen space than the prior model. (credit: Google)</p></div>
<h2>Pixel Watch 3</h2>
<p>There are many fitness, smart home, and AI features on the new Pixel Watch 3, but let's get to the important new stuff: Pixel Recorder. That means, in situations where you aren't being creepy, using your watch to record a note to self, a conversation, a bit of a song, or whatever else on your watch. You can then play the recording back and get the transcription on your Pixel phone.</p>
<p>The other feature that isn't about running a marathon or asking a language model for help is UWB (ultra wideband) phone unlocking with the Pixel Watch 3. That should mean relatively responsive unlocks on your phone, but not if you're a measurably far distance from it.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042621#p3">Read 6 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042621&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/googles-pixel-watch-3-has-a-bigger-screen-and-pixel-buds-pro-2-are-smaller/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Pixel 9 phones are big cameras and screens soldered onto Gemini AI ambitions</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042619</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/the-pixel-9-phones-are-big-cameras-and-screens-soldered-onto-gemini-ai-ambitions/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Purdy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gemini Advanced]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Pixel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pixel 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pixel 9 pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pixel 9 pro fold]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pixel 9 pro xl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["Pro" no longer means "large," and the Fold is the biggest screen ever.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Pixel-9-collage-800x450.jpg" alt="A Google Pixel 9 Fold and Pixel 9 Pro XL, side by side on white background, with Fold open and 9 Pro XL front and back shown on separate models.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Pixel-9-collage.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1440" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> (credit: Google / Aurich Lawson)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Google <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N_y2tP9of8A">announced</a> its fall lineup of Pixel phones today: three standard phones and a second tablet-esque folding model. There are new chips, new cameras, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/04/the-pixel-9-reportedly-gears-up-for-satellite-sos-support/">Satellite SOS</a>, and some notable promises, like the 9 phones being "twice as durable" as their Pixel 8 equivalents and getting seven years of updates. But as you might expect this year, they're primarily showcases for all the things Google's Gemini AI promises to do for you.</p>
<p>Here's what's new, what's coming, and when you can ask your phone to make a shopping list for taco night for a family of six.</p>
<div class="image shortcode-img center full"><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/0.-Blog-header.jpeg"><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">(credit: Google)</p></div>
<h2>Gemini is in the power button, the screenshots, and a free premium subscription</h2>
<p>It's not just you—Google really is "infusing AI into everything we do," as <a href="https://blog.google/products/android/android-gemini-google-ai">noted on its Keyword blog today</a>. Here's a short list of what Google says Android phone owners can do with Gemini:</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042619#p3">Read 17 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042619&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/the-pixel-9-phones-are-big-cameras-and-screens-soldered-onto-gemini-ai-ambitions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>88</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Framework Laptop 13 reviewed, again: Meteor Lake meh, Linux upgrades good</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042317</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/framework-laptop-13-reviewed-again-meteor-lake-meh-linux-upgrades-good/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AMD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework laptop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework laptop 13]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteor lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intel's latest chips often fall behind Ryzen, or even older Intel CPUs. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_2067-800x533.jpeg" alt="The ever-evolving Framework Laptop 13 is back again, this time with some Linux-friendly upgrades and Intel's new Meteor Lake-based Core Ultra CPUs.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_2067.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1707" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The ever-evolving Framework Laptop 13 is back again, this time with some Linux-friendly upgrades and Intel's new Meteor Lake-based Core Ultra CPUs. (credit: Andrew Cunningham)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Would you believe that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/05/review-framework-laptops-13th-gen-intel-upgrade-helps-fix-its-battery-problem/">the Framework Laptop 13</a> is back again?</p>
<p>Framework's fifth motherboard for the Laptop 13—which, in typical fashion, can be easily swapped into any existing Framework Laptop 13 of any generation—is mainly significant because it offers Intel's Meteor Lake-based Core Ultra chips. But Framework likes to release its updates in batches, and this one also comes with a few designed to make the Laptop 13 a better system for Linux enthusiasts.</p>
<p>One of those changes is a redesigned keyboard, which is exactly like the older Framework Laptop 13 keyboard, except it has a Super key instead of a Windows logo on it. The second is a higher-resolution display upgrade, specifically chosen because it looks better in 200 percent scaling mode than the old screen; Linux still has problems with "fractional" scaling modes like 125 percent and 150 percent, which was what the old Framework screen usually looked best at.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042317#p3">Read 27 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042317&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/framework-laptop-13-reviewed-again-meteor-lake-meh-linux-upgrades-good/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>81</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deep-Live-Cam goes viral, allowing anyone to become a digital doppelganger</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042710</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/08/new-ai-tool-enables-real-time-face-swapping-on-webcams-raising-fraud-concerns/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 15:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI scams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deep-live-cam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deepfake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deepfakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[image synthesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video synthesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webcam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Using one photo and free software, someone can impersonate your appearance in a video chat.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/jdvance_example-800x450.jpg" alt="A still video capture of X user João Fiadeiro replacing his face with J.D. Vance in a test of Deep-Live-Cam.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/jdvance_example.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="720" data-width="1280">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> A still video capture of X user João Fiadeiro replacing his face with J.D. Vance in a test of Deep-Live-Cam. </p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Over the past few days, a software package called <a href="https://github.com/hacksider/Deep-Live-Cam">Deep-Live-Cam</a> has been <a href="https://x.com/CoreyBrickley/status/1823234384876515554">going viral</a> on social media because it can take the face of a person extracted from a single photo and apply it to a live webcam video source while following pose, lighting, and expressions performed by the person on the webcam. While the results aren't perfect, the software shows how quickly the tech is developing—and how the capability to deceive others remotely is getting dramatically easier over time.</p>

<p>The Deep-Live-Cam software project has been in the works since late last year, but example videos that show a person imitating Elon Musk and Republican Vice Presidential candidate <a href="https://x.com/jay_wooow/status/1821989710207840730">J.D. Vance</a> (among others) in real time have been making the rounds online. The avalanche of attention briefly made the open source project leap to No. 1 on GitHub's <a href="https://github.com/trending">trending repositories list</a> (it's currently at No. 4 as of this writing), where it is available for download for free.</p>
<p>"<span class="css-1jxf684 r-bcqeeo r-1ttztb7 r-qvutc0 r-poiln3">Weird how all the major innovations coming out of tech lately are under the Fraud skill tree," <a href="https://x.com/CoreyBrickley/status/1823235018866475175">wrote</a> illustrator Corey Brickley in an X thread reacting to an example video of Deep-Live-Cam in action. In another post, he <a href="https://x.com/CoreyBrickley/status/1823234384876515554">wrote</a>, "Nice remember to establish code words with your parents everyone," referring to the potential for similar tools to be used for remote deception—and the concept of using a <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/a-safe-word-can-protect-against-ai-impostor-scams/">safe word</a>, shared among friends and family, to establish your true identity.<br>
</span></p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042710#p3">Read 7 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042710&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/08/new-ai-tool-enables-real-time-face-swapping-on-webcams-raising-fraud-concerns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>126</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ford tells owners to stop driving if they’ve ignored 9-year-old airbag recall</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042764</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/08/765000-owners-still-have-airbags-recalled-in-2015-stop-driving-ford-says/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 15:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbag recall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safety recall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Takata]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The owners have now ignored three safety recalls.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-172965150-800x536.jpg" alt="Macro of car airbag sign on leather">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-172965150-scaled.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1714" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The Takata airbag recall has affected more than 100 million cars across the world.  (credit: Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>The "largest and most complex" automotive safety recall in US history is still not over, nine years after the first owners were contacted about a fix. Today, Ford issued a "do not drive" advisory for owners who still have not had their Takata airbags replaced, for a mix of vehicles that range from Ranger pickup trucks to the mid-engined GT supercar.</p>
<p>The Takata airbag scandal stretches back to the year 2000, when the company first learned from testing that some of its airbags might not deploy properly. A lack of a chemical drying agent, or desiccant, can allow the explosive ammonium nitrate propellant to take on moisture when exposed to hot or humid environments. As a result, the airbag may not inflate properly during a crash, and there were even cases of metal shrapnel being thrown around the vehicle interior.</p>
<p>The first US case of a faulty Takata airbag inflator occurred in 2005. In 2009, a faulty airbag inflator killed the driver of a Honda Accord in Oklahoma, sparking a recall by Honda later that year. A formal safety investigation by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration began in 2014 and concluded a year later when Takata agreed that its inflators were defective.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042764#p3">Read 6 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042764&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/08/765000-owners-still-have-airbags-recalled-in-2015-stop-driving-ford-says/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>115</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 5,200+ day wait for Red Dead Redemption’s PC port may soon be over</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042744</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/08/the-5200-day-wait-for-red-dead-redemptions-pc-port-may-soon-be-over/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042744</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PlayStation Store page bizarrely leaks "now on PC" promo message.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/rdr-800x450.jpg" alt="He's gesturing towards a PC port that's just out of frame. Trust me.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/rdr.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="534" data-width="950">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> He's gesturing towards a PC port that's just out of frame. Trust me. (credit: Rockstar Games)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Rockstar Games fans who don't traffic in game consoles have <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/date/durationresult.html?m1=05&amp;d1=18&amp;y1=2010&amp;m2=8&amp;d2=13&amp;y2=2024">been waiting over 5,200 days</a> to play the original <em>Red Dead Redemption</em> on PC (even as the PC port of its sequel <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/11/red-dead-redemption-2-launches-on-pc-we-take-a-mosey-through-its-upgrades/">approaches its fifth anniversary</a>). PC gamers' long wait for a port may soon be over, though, as some promotional copy for the PC version of the game has been briefly leaked online.</p>
<p>The suggestive verbiage comes from the PlayStation Store of all places, which as of Tuesday morning described <em>Red Dead Redemption</em> as "now on PC for the first time ever" on the page for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/7/23811044/red-dead-redemption-remake-rockstar-games-switch-ps4">the game's 2023 PS4 rerelease</a>. While the language has now been reverted to a more generic description, <a href="https://archive.is/zW0NK">archived copies of the site</a> from just hours ago include some details of what we can expect of the jump from console to PC:</p>
<blockquote><p>Featuring the complete single-player experience of both games [<em>RDR</em> and <em>Undead Nightmare</em>, from previous context], including bonus content from the Game of the Year edition, <em>Red Dead Redemption</em> features all of the 2023 console version upgrades plus PC specific enhancements including support for increased resolutions, multiple displays, and other accessories, plus spatial surround sound.</p>
<p><em>Red Dead Redemption</em> does not feature multiplayer content.</p></blockquote>
<div class="image shortcode-img center large"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/rdrpc.png"><img alt="The PC port promo copy that appeared on the PlayStation Store page for &lt;em&gt;Red Dead Redemption&lt;/em&gt; Tuesday morning." src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/rdrpc-640x418.png" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/rdrpc.png 2x"></a><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/rdrpc.png" class="caption-link" rel="nofollow">The PC port promo copy that appeared on the PlayStation Store page for <em>Red Dead Redemption</em> Tuesday morning.</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://archive.is/zW0NK">Sony / Archive.is</a>)</p></div>
<p>It's hard to know exactly why a description of a PC port would show up on a Sony store page, but it's easy to picture someone in the PR chain pasting in the wrong platform's promotional copy when updating something on the back end.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042744#p3">Read 4 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042744&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/08/the-5200-day-wait-for-red-dead-redemptions-pc-port-may-soon-be-over/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU warned Elon Musk about “disinformation” before Trump interview on X</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042731</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/eu-warned-elon-musk-about-disinformation-before-trump-interview-on-x/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Financial Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[X was reminded to not spread "content that promotes hatred or disorder."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/getty-x-musk-800x534.jpg" alt="A smartphone displays Elon Musk's profile on X, the app formerly known as Twitter.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/getty-x-musk.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1668" data-width="2500">Enlarge</a> (credit: Getty Images | Dan Kitwood )</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Elon Musk clashed with the EU ahead of a planned interview with Donald Trump on X as a war of words broke out between Brussels and the technology billionaire’s social media platform over content related to the US election.</p>
<p>The dispute erupted as Trump, the Republican US presidential nominee, returned to X on Monday with a number of posts on a social media platform that had once banned him, just hours before the interview with Musk.</p>
<p>The billionaire’s planned event with Trump triggered a strident warning to X from Thierry Breton, the EU commissioner for the internal market, about the dissemination of “content that promotes hatred, disorder, incitement to violence, or certain instances of disinformation.”</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042731#p3">Read 20 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042731&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/eu-warned-elon-musk-about-disinformation-before-trump-interview-on-x/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>401</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SpaceX announces first human mission to ever fly over the planet’s poles</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042678</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/08/spacex-announces-first-human-mission-to-ever-fly-over-the-planets-poles/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Berger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 22:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The highest-inclination flight by a human spacecraft to date is 65.1 degrees.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/fram2-800x533.jpg" alt="The crew of Fram2 from left to right: Eric Philips, Jannicke Mikkelsen, Chun Wang, and Rabea Rogge. ">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/fram2.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="679" data-width="1019">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The crew of Fram2 from left to right: Eric Philips, Jannicke Mikkelsen, Chun Wang, and Rabea Rogge.  (credit: SpaceX)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>SpaceX will fly the first-ever human spaceflight over the Earth’s poles, possibly before the end of this year, the company announced Monday. The private Crew Dragon mission will be led by a Chinese-born cryptocurrency entrepreneur named Chun Wang, and he will be joined by a polar explorer, a roboticist, and a filmmaker whom he has befriended in recent years.</p>
<p>The "Fram2" mission, named after the <a href="https://frammuseum.no/polar-history/vessels/the-polar-ship-fram/">Norwegian research ship Fram</a>, will launch into a polar corridor from SpaceX's launch facilities in Florida and fly directly over the north and south poles. The three- to five-day mission is being timed to fly over Antarctica near the summer solstice in the Southern Hemisphere, to afford maximum lighting.</p>
<p>The four-person crew will fly, fittingly, aboard Crew Dragon <em>Endurance</em>, which is named after Ernest Shackleton's famous ship that was trapped in the Antarctic ice and eventually sank there about a century ago. The spacecraft will be fitted with a cupola for both photography and filming.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042678#p3">Read 11 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042678&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/08/spacex-announces-first-human-mission-to-ever-fly-over-the-planets-poles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>147</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MDMA for PTSD: Three studies retracted on heels of FDA rejection</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042683</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/mdma-for-ptsd-three-studies-retracted-on-heels-of-fda-rejection/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth Mole]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 22:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ecstasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lykos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mdma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychedelic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042683</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The company behind the therapy says it will appeal the FDA's decision.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/GettyImages-129369648-800x534.jpeg" alt="MDMA">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/GettyImages-129369648-scaled.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1710" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> MDMA (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/ecstasy-pills-in-hand-news-photo/129369648?searchscope=image%2Cfilm&amp;adppopup=true">Getty | PYMCA/Avalon</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>A scientific journal has retracted three studies underpinning the clinical development of MDMA—aka ecstasy—as a psychedelic treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder. The move came just a day after news broke that the Food and Drug Administration rejected the treatment, despite <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/12/mdma-aka-ecstasy-submitted-to-fda-as-part-of-ptsd-therapy/">positive results reported from two Phase III clinical trials</a>.</p>
<p>On Friday, the company developing the therapy, Lykos Therapeutics, <a href="https://news.lykospbc.com/2024-08-09-Lykos-Therapeutics-Announces-Complete-Response-Letter-for-Midomafetamine-Capsules-for-PTSD">announced that it had received a rejection letter from the FDA</a>. Lykos said the letter echoed the numerous <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/05/fdas-review-of-mdma-for-ptsd-highlights-study-bias-and-safety-concerns/">concerns raised previously by the agency</a> and its expert advisory committee, which, in June, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/06/flawed-scandalous-trials-tank-fda-expert-support-for-mdma-therapy/">voted </a><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/06/flawed-scandalous-trials-tank-fda-expert-support-for-mdma-therapy/">overwhelmingly </a><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/06/flawed-scandalous-trials-tank-fda-expert-support-for-mdma-therapy/">against approving the therapy</a>. The FDA and its advisers identified flaws in the design of the clinical trials, missing data, and a variety of biases in people involved with the trials, including an alleged cult-like support of psychedelics. Lykos is a commercial spinoff of the psychedelic advocacy nonprofit Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies (MAPS).</p>
<p>FDA advisers also noted the <a href="https://qz.com/1809184/psychedelic-therapy-has-a-sexual-abuse-problem-3">public allegations of a sexual assault</a> of a trial participant during a Phase II trial by an unlicensed therapist providing the MDMA-assisted psychotherapy.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042683#p3">Read 6 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042683&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/mdma-for-ptsd-three-studies-retracted-on-heels-of-fda-rejection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>129</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Studying the skin of the great white shark could help reduce drag in aircraft</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042552</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/how-the-great-white-shark-reduces-drag-while-swimming-at-different-speeds/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 21:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biomimicry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fluid dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[great white shark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hydrodynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sharks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[High-ridged denticles reduce drag at low speeds; alternating ridges do so at high speeds.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/sharkTOP-800x534.jpg" alt="Great white shark at Isla Guadalupe, Mexico">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/sharkTOP.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="801" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Great white sharks can reduce drag at different swimming speeds thanks to high and low ridged denticles in its skin. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.5/">Terry Goss/CC BY 2.5</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_white_shark">great white shark</a> (<em>Carcharodon carcharias</em>) is a swift and mighty hunter, capable of reaching speeds as high as 6.7 m/s when breaching, although it prefers to swim at slower speeds for migration and while waiting for prey. A team of Japanese researchers has studied the structure of the great white's skin to learn more about how these creatures adapt so well to a wide range of speeds. Their findings could lead to more efficient aircraft and boats with greatly reduced drag, according to a <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rsif.2024.0063">recent paper</a> published in the Journal of the Royal Society Interface.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/03/the-secret-of-how-the-mako-shark-swims-so-fast-lies-in-its-flexible-scales/">previously reported</a>, anyone who has touched a shark knows the skin feels smooth if you stroke from nose to tail. Reverse the direction, however, and it feels like sandpaper. That's because of tiny translucent scales, roughly 0.2 millimeters in size, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/melissacristinamarquez/2019/03/04/spilling-the-secret-to-a-mako-sharks-speed/#33ad9b1e02ea">called "denticles"</a> (because they strongly resemble teeth) all over the shark's body, especially concentrated in the animal's flanks and fins. It's like a suit of armor for sharks, and it also serves as a means of reducing drag in the water while swimming.</p>
<p>Pressure drag is the result of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_separation">flow separation</a> around an object, like an aircraft or the body of a mako shark as it moves through water; the magnitude of pressure drag is determined by the shape of the object. It's what happens when the fluid flow separates from the surface of an object, forming eddies and vortices that impede the object's movement. Since the shark's body is constantly undulating as it swims, it needs something to help keep the flow attached around that body to reduce that drag. Denticles serve that purpose.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042552#p3">Read 9 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042552&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/how-the-great-white-shark-reduces-drag-while-swimming-at-different-speeds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>65</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google abruptly shuts down AdSense in Russia as tensions with Kremlin escalate</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042637</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/google-abruptly-shuts-down-adsense-in-russia-as-tensions-with-kremlin-escalate/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 20:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AdSense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kremlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian invasion of Ukraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Russia-based YouTubers, in particular, will likely lose significant revenues.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2128890344-800x525.jpg" alt="Google abruptly shuts down AdSense in Russia as tensions with Kremlin escalate">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2128890344.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="672" data-width="1024">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/google-corporate-logo-hangs-above-the-entrance-to-their-news-photo/2128890344?adppopup=true">Gary Hershorn / Contributor | Corbis News</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Google <a href="https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/10502938?hl=en">announced</a> Monday that it's shutting down all AdSense accounts in Russia due to "ongoing developments in Russia."</p>
<p>This effectively ends Russian content creators' ability to monetize their posts, including YouTube videos. The change impacts accounts monetizing content through AdSense, AdMob, and Ad Manager, the support page said.</p>
<p>While Google has declined requests to provide details on what prompted the change, it's the latest escalation of Google's ongoing battle with Russian officials working to control the narrative on Russia's war with Ukraine.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042637#p3">Read 16 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042637&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/google-abruptly-shuts-down-adsense-in-russia-as-tensions-with-kremlin-escalate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>109</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>