<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
        <atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
        <description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 23:09:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <sy:updatePeriod>
            hourly        </sy:updatePeriod>
        <sy:updateFrequency>
            1        </sy:updateFrequency>
        
<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
            <item>
                <title>Congress warned that NASA’s current plan for Artemis “cannot work”</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/congress-told-there-needs-to-be-consequences-for-nasa-delays-amid-chinas-rise/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/congress-told-there-needs-to-be-consequences-for-nasa-delays-amid-chinas-rise/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Eric Berger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artemis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[griffin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starship]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/congress-told-there-needs-to-be-consequences-for-nasa-delays-amid-chinas-rise/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA["The Artemis III mission and those beyond should be canceled."]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>In recent months, it has begun dawning on US lawmakers that, absent significant intervention, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/08/after-recent-tests-china-appears-likely-to-beat-the-united-states-back-to-the-moon/">China will land humans</a> on the Moon before the United States can return there with the Artemis Program.</p>
<p>So far, legislators have yet to take meaningful action on this—<a href="https://spacepolicyonline.com/news/trump-megabill-includes-billions-for-artemis-iss-moving-a-space-shuttle-to-texas-and-more/">a $10 billion infusion</a> into NASA’s budget this summer essentially provided zero funding for efforts needed to land humans on the Moon this decade. But now a subcommittee of the House Committee on Space, Science, and Technology has begun reviewing the space agency’s policy, expressing concerns about Chinese competition in civil spaceflight.</p>
<p>During <a href="https://science.house.gov/hearings?ContentRecord_id=9A80EC32-7ABB-4B9D-B32A-E2376A644046">a hearing on Thursday</a> in Washington, DC, the subcommittee members asked a panel of experts how NASA could maintain its global leadership in space over China in general, and more specifically, how to improve the Artemis Program to reach the Moon more quickly.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/congress-told-there-needs-to-be-consequences-for-nasa-delays-amid-chinas-rise/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/congress-told-there-needs-to-be-consequences-for-nasa-delays-amid-chinas-rise/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2207557317-900x648.jpg" width="900">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/GettyImages-2207557317-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Liu Guoxing/VCG via Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>A Long March 7A rocket carrying the TJS-16 satellite lifts off from the Wenchang Space Launch Site on March 30, 2025, in Wenchang, Hainan Province of China.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>In comedy of errors, men accused of wiping gov databases turned to an AI tool</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/12/previously-convicted-contractors-wiped-gov-databases-after-being-fired-feds-say/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/12/previously-convicted-contractors-wiped-gov-databases-after-being-fired-feds-say/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contractors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[courts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data theft]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/12/previously-convicted-contractors-wiped-gov-databases-after-being-fired-feds-say/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Defendants were convicted of similar crimes a decade ago. How were they cleared again?]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Two sibling contractors convicted a decade ago for hacking into US State Department systems have once again been charged, this time for a comically hamfisted attempt to steal and destroy government records just minutes after being fired from their contractor jobs.</p>
<p>The Department of Justice on Thursday <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/two-virginia-men-arrested-conspiring-destroy-government-databases">said</a> that Muneeb Akhter and Sohaib Akhter, both 34, of Alexandria, Virginia, deleted databases and documents maintained and belonging to three government agencies. The brothers were federal contractors working for an undisclosed company in Washington, DC, that provides software and services to 45 US agencies. Prosecutors said the men coordinated the crimes and began carrying them out just minutes after being fired.</p>
<h2>Using AI to cover up an alleged crime—what could go wrong?</h2>
<p>On February 18 at roughly 4:55 pm, the men were fired from the company, according to an <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.vaed.585302/gov.uscourts.vaed.585302.1.0_1.pdf">indictment</a> unsealed on Thursday. Five minutes later, they allegedly began trying to access their employer’s system and access federal government databases. By then, access to one of the brothers’ accounts had already been terminated. The other brother, however, allegedly accessed a government agency’s database stored on the employer’s server and issued commands to prevent other users from connecting or making changes to the database. Then, prosecutors said, he issued a command to delete 96 databases, many of which contained sensitive investigative files and records related to Freedom of Information Act matters.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/12/previously-convicted-contractors-wiped-gov-databases-after-being-fired-feds-say/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/12/previously-convicted-contractors-wiped-gov-databases-after-being-fired-feds-say/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/data-theft-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/data-theft-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Hand recovering folder with the  word "confidential" from a file cabinet.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Engineer proves that Kohler’s smart toilet cameras aren’t very private</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/despite-accessing-user-data-kohler-still-says-its-smart-toilet-cameras-use-e2ee/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/despite-accessing-user-data-kohler-still-says-its-smart-toilet-cameras-use-e2ee/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Scharon Harding]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cameras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e2ee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[end to end encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart home]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/despite-accessing-user-data-kohler-still-says-its-smart-toilet-cameras-use-e2ee/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Kohler is getting the scoop on people's poop.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Kohler is facing backlash after an engineer <a href="https://varlogsimon.leaflet.pub/3m6zrw6k2bs2p">pointed out</a> that the company’s new smart toilet cameras may not be as private as it wants people to believe. The discussion raises questions about Kohler’s use of the term “end-to-end encryption” (E2EE) and the inherent privacy limitations of a device that films the goings-on of a toilet bowl.</p>
<p>In October, Kohler announced its first “health” product, the Dekoda. Kohler’s announcement described the $599 device (it also requires a subscription that starts at $7 per month) as a toilet bowl attachment that uses “optical sensors and validated machine-learning algorithms” to deliver “valuable insights into your health and wellness.” The announcement added:</p>
<blockquote><p>Data flows to the personalized Kohler Health app, giving users continuous, private awareness of key health and wellness indicators—right on their phone. Features like fingerprint authentication and end-to-end encryption are designed for user privacy and security.</p></blockquote>
<p>The average person is most likely to be familiar with E2EE through messaging apps, like Signal. Messages sent via apps with E2EE are encrypted throughout transmission. Only the message’s sender and recipient can view the decrypted messages, which is intended to prevent third parties, including the app developer, from reading them.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/despite-accessing-user-data-kohler-still-says-its-smart-toilet-cameras-use-e2ee/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/despite-accessing-user-data-kohler-still-says-its-smart-toilet-cameras-use-e2ee/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>71</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/fa9752cdfabfc67f2acd9bfdf4f195ecfdad5f05-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/fa9752cdfabfc67f2acd9bfdf4f195ecfdad5f05-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Kohler</media:credit><media:text>A Dekoda smart toilet camera. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>CDC vaccine panel realizes again it has no idea what it’s doing, delays big vote</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/cdc-vaccine-panel-realizes-again-it-has-no-idea-what-its-doing-delays-big-vote/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/cdc-vaccine-panel-realizes-again-it-has-no-idea-what-its-doing-delays-big-vote/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-vaccine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robert f kennedy jr]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/cdc-vaccine-panel-realizes-again-it-has-no-idea-what-its-doing-delays-big-vote/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Today's meeting was chaotic and included garbage anti-vaccine presentations.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The panel of federal vaccine advisors hand-selected by anti-vaccine Health Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr. has once again punted on whether to strip recommendations for hepatitis B vaccinations for newborns—a move it tried to make in September before realizing <a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/09/rfk-jr-s-anti-vaccine-panel-realizes-it-has-no-idea-what-its-doing-skips-vote/">it didn’t know what it was doing</a>. The decision to delay the vote today came abruptly this afternoon when the panel realized it still does not understand the topic or what it was voting on.</p>
<p>Prior to today’s 6–3 vote to delay a decision, there was a swirl of confusion over the wording of what a new recommendation would be. Panel members had gotten three different versions of the proposed recommendation in the 72 hours prior to the meeting, one panelist said. And the meeting’s data presentations this morning offered no clarity on the subject—they were delivered entirely by anti-vaccine activists who have no subject matter expertise and who made a dizzying amount of false and absurd claims.</p>
<h2>“Completely inappropriate”</h2>
<p>Overall, the meeting was disorganized and farcical. Kennedy’s panel has abandoned the evidence-based framework for setting vaccine policy in favor of airing unvetted presentations with misrepresentations, conspiracy theories, and cherry-picked studies. At times, there were tense exchanges, chaos, confusion, and misunderstandings.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/cdc-vaccine-panel-realizes-again-it-has-no-idea-what-its-doing-delays-big-vote/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/cdc-vaccine-panel-realizes-again-it-has-no-idea-what-its-doing-delays-big-vote/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2249270671-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2249270671-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Elijah Nouvelage</media:credit><media:text>Dr. Robert Malone speaks during a meeting of the CDC Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices (ACIP) at CDC Headquarters on December 4, 2025 in Atlanta, Georgia. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Researchers find what makes AI chatbots politically persuasive</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/researchers-find-what-makes-ai-chatbots-politically-persuasive/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/researchers-find-what-makes-ai-chatbots-politically-persuasive/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jacek Krywko]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Behavioral science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chat-gpt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Human behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large language models]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/researchers-find-what-makes-ai-chatbots-politically-persuasive/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[A massive study of political persuasion shows AIs have, at best, a weak effect.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Roughly two years ago, Sam Altman <a href="https://x.com/sama/status/1716972815960961174?lang=en">tweeted</a> that AI systems would be capable of superhuman persuasion well before achieving general intelligence—a prediction that raised concerns about the influence AI could have over democratic elections.</p>
<p>To see if conversational large language models can really sway political views of the public, scientists at the UK AI Security Institute, MIT, Stanford, Carnegie Mellon, and many other institutions performed by far the largest study on AI persuasiveness to date, involving nearly 80,000 participants in the UK. It turned out political AI chatbots fell far short of superhuman persuasiveness, but the study raises some more nuanced issues about our interactions with AI.</p>
<h2>AI dystopias</h2>
<p>The public debate about the impact AI has on politics has largely revolved around notions drawn from dystopian sci-fi. Large language models have access to essentially every fact and story ever published about any issue or candidate. They have processed information from books on psychology, negotiations, and human manipulation. They can rely on absurdly high computing power in huge data centers worldwide. On top of that, they can often access tons of personal information about individual users thanks to hundreds upon hundreds of online interactions at their disposal.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/researchers-find-what-makes-ai-chatbots-politically-persuasive/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/researchers-find-what-makes-ai-chatbots-politically-persuasive/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/twitter-bot-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/twitter-bot-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Carol Yepes via Getty</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Why won’t Steam Machine support HDMI 2.1? Digging in on the display standard drama.</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/12/why-wont-steam-machine-support-hdmi-2-1-digging-in-on-the-display-standard-drama/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/12/why-wont-steam-machine-support-hdmi-2-1-digging-in-on-the-display-standard-drama/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AMD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drivers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steam machine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steamos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Valve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/12/why-wont-steam-machine-support-hdmi-2-1-digging-in-on-the-display-standard-drama/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Valve tells Ars its "trying to unblock" limits caused by open source driver issues.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>When Valve <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/11/steam-deck-minus-the-screen-valve-announces-new-steam-machine-controller-hardware/">announced its upcoming Steam Machine hardware last month</a>, some eagle-eyed gamers may have been surprised to see that <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/steammachine">the official spec sheet</a> lists support for HDMI 2.0 output, rather than the updated, higher-bandwidth HDMI 2.1 standard <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/11/hdmi-2-1-spec-released-ushering-in-new-era-of-dynamic-hdr-video/">introduced in 2017</a>. Now, Valve tells Ars that, while the hardware itself actually supports HDMI 2.1, the company is struggling to offer full support for that standard due to Linux drivers that are “still a work-in-progress on the software side.”</p>
<p>As <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/02/hdmi-forum-to-amd-no-you-cant-make-an-open-source-hdmi-2-1-driver/">we noted last year</a>, the HDMI Forum (which manages the official specifications for HDMI standards) has officially blocked any open source implementation of HDMI 2.1. That means the open source AMD drivers used by SteamOS can’t fully implement certain features that are specific to the updated output standard.</p>
<p>“At this time an open source HDMI 2.1 implementation is not possible without running afoul of the HDMI Forum requirements,” AMD engineer Alex Deucher said at the time.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/12/why-wont-steam-machine-support-hdmi-2-1-digging-in-on-the-display-standard-drama/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/12/why-wont-steam-machine-support-hdmi-2-1-digging-in-on-the-display-standard-drama/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>69</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/sm1-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/sm1-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Valve</media:credit><media:text>That HDMI port might not be all it's cracked up to be...</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>ChatGPT hyped up violent stalker who believed he was “God’s assassin,” DOJ says</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/chatgpt-hyped-up-violent-stalker-who-believed-he-was-gods-assassin-doj-says/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/chatgpt-hyped-up-violent-stalker-who-believed-he-was-gods-assassin-doj-says/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChatGPT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyberstalking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spotify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiktok]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/chatgpt-hyped-up-violent-stalker-who-believed-he-was-gods-assassin-doj-says/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Podcaster faces up to 70 years and a $3.5 million fine for ChatGPT-linked stalking.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>ChatGPT allegedly validated the worst impulses of a wannabe influencer accused of stalking more than 10 women at boutique gyms, where the chatbot supposedly claimed he’d meet the “wife type.”</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-wdpa/pr/whitehall-borough-resident-charged-cyberstalking-interstate-stalking-and-threats">press release</a> on Tuesday, the Department of Justice confirmed that 31-year-old Brett Michael Dadig currently remains in custody after being charged with cyberstalking, interstate stalking, and making interstate threats. He now faces a maximum sentence of up to 70 years in prison that could be coupled with “a fine of up to $3.5 million,” the DOJ said.</p>
<p>The podcaster—who primarily posted about “his desire to find a wife and his interactions with women”—allegedly harassed and sometimes even doxxed his victims through his videos on platforms including Instagram, Spotify, and TikTok. Over time, his videos and podcasts documented his intense desire to start a family, which was frustrated by his “anger towards women,” whom he claimed were “all the same from fucking 18 to fucking 40 to fucking 90” and “trash.”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/chatgpt-hyped-up-violent-stalker-who-believed-he-was-gods-assassin-doj-says/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/chatgpt-hyped-up-violent-stalker-who-believed-he-was-gods-assassin-doj-says/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>92</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2233803629-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2233803629-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Yurii Karvatskyi | iStock / Getty Images Plus</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>OnePlus 15 finally gets FCC clearance after government shutdown delay—preorders live</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/oneplus-15-finally-gets-fcc-clearance-after-government-shutdown-delay-preorders-live/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/oneplus-15-finally-gets-fcc-clearance-after-government-shutdown-delay-preorders-live/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OnePlus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oneplus 15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/oneplus-15-finally-gets-fcc-clearance-after-government-shutdown-delay-preorders-live/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[The device starts at $900 and comes with a free gift for a limited time.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>OnePlus is ready to sell its new flagship smartphone in the US weeks after it made the device official. Having now finally gotten Federal Communications Commission clearance, the OnePlus 15 is available for preorder. It’s currently only live on the OnePlus storefront, but the device will eventually come to Amazon and Best Buy as well.</p>
<p>The OnePlus 15 launched in China earlier this year, and it was supposed to go on sale in the US a month ago. However, the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/10/trump-admin-defiles-even-the-out-of-office-email-auto-reply/">longest US government shutdown on record</a> got in the way. Most of the FCC’s functions were suspended during the weekslong funding lapse, which prevented the agency from certifying new wireless products. Without that approval, OnePlus could not begin selling the phone. Thus, it had no firm release date when the phone was officially unveiled for the US in early November.</p>
<p>Interested parties can head to the OnePlus website to place an order. The base model starts at $900 with 12GB of RAM and 256GB of storage. This version is only available in black. If you want the Ultraviolet or Sand Storm (with the distinctive micro-arc oxidation finish), you’ll have to upgrade to the $1,000 version, which has 16GB of RAM and 512GB of storage.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/oneplus-15-finally-gets-fcc-clearance-after-government-shutdown-delay-preorders-live/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/oneplus-15-finally-gets-fcc-clearance-after-government-shutdown-delay-preorders-live/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/OnePlus-15-5-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/OnePlus-15-5-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Ryan Whitwam</media:credit><media:text>The OnePlus 15 looks nice, but it also looks more like everything else. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>In 1995, a Netscape employee wrote a hack in 10 days that now runs the Internet</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/in-1995-a-netscape-employee-wrote-a-hack-in-10-days-that-now-runs-the-internet/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/in-1995-a-netscape-employee-wrote-a-hack-in-10-days-that-now-runs-the-internet/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1995]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Joy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brendan eich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browser history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ECMAScript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JavaScript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Node.js]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retrotech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sun microsystems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tales of tech lore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech lore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trademark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[typescript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web development]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/in-1995-a-netscape-employee-wrote-a-hack-in-10-days-that-now-runs-the-internet/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Thirty years later, JavaScript is the glue that holds the interactive web together, warts and all.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Thirty years ago today, Netscape Communications and Sun Microsystems <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070916144913/http://wp.netscape.com/newsref/pr/newsrelease67.html">issued</a> a joint press release announcing JavaScript, an object scripting language designed for creating interactive web applications. The language emerged from a frantic 10-day sprint at pioneering browser company Netscape, where engineer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brendan_Eich">Brendan Eich</a> hacked together a working internal prototype during May 1995.</p>
<p>While the JavaScript language didn’t ship publicly until that September and didn’t reach a 1.0 release until March 1996, the descendants of Eich’s initial 10-day hack now <a href="https://w3techs.com/technologies/details/cp-javascript">run</a> on approximately 98.9 percent of all websites with client-side code, making JavaScript the dominant programming language of the web. It’s wildly popular; beyond the browser, JavaScript powers server backends, mobile apps, desktop software, and even some embedded systems. According to several surveys, JavaScript consistently ranks among the most widely used programming languages in the world.</p>
<p>In crafting JavaScript, Netscape wanted a scripting language that could make webpages interactive, something lightweight that would appeal to web designers and non-professional programmers. Eich drew from several influences: The syntax looked like a trendy new programming language called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_(programming_language)">Java</a> to satisfy Netscape management, but its guts borrowed concepts from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scheme_(programming_language)">Scheme</a>, a language Eich admired, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self_(programming_language)">Self</a>, which contributed JavaScript’s prototype-based object model.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/in-1995-a-netscape-employee-wrote-a-hack-in-10-days-that-now-runs-the-internet/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/in-1995-a-netscape-employee-wrote-a-hack-in-10-days-that-now-runs-the-internet/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>89</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/netscape_logo_header_3-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/netscape_logo_header_3-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Netscape / Benj Edwards</media:credit><media:text>An early logo from the Netscape web browser that featured animated comets.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Welcome to “necroprinting”—3D printer nozzle made from mosquito’s proboscis</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/welcome-to-necroprinting-3d-printer-nozzle-made-from-mosquitos-proboscis/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/welcome-to-necroprinting-3d-printer-nozzle-made-from-mosquitos-proboscis/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jacek Krywko]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3D printing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biomechanics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materials science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mosquitos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[printing]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/welcome-to-necroprinting-3d-printer-nozzle-made-from-mosquitos-proboscis/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[They're quite a bit cheaper than manufactured nozzles if you can dissect them.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Necrobotics is a field of engineering that builds robots out of a mix of synthetic materials and animal body parts. It has produced micro-grippers with pneumatically operated legs taken from dead spiders and walking robots based on deceased cockroaches. “These necrobotics papers inspired us to build something different,” said Changhong Cao, a mechanical engineering professor at the McGill University in Montreal, Canada.</p>
<p>Cao’s team didn’t go for a robot—instead, it adapted a female mosquito proboscis to work as a nozzle in a super-precise 3D printer. And it worked surprisingly well.</p>
<h2>Fangs and stings</h2>
<p>To find the right nozzle for their 3D necroprinting system, Cao’s team began with a broad survey of natural micro-dispensing tips. The researchers examined stingers of bees, wasps, and scorpions; the fangs of venomous snakes; and the claws of centipedes. All of those evolved to deliver a fluid to the target, which is roughly what a 3D printer’s nozzle does. But they all had issues. “Some were too curved and curved for high-precision 3D printing,” Cao explained. “Also, they were optimized for delivering pulses of venom, not for a steady, continuous flow, which is what you need for printing.”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/welcome-to-necroprinting-3d-printer-nozzle-made-from-mosquitos-proboscis/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/welcome-to-necroprinting-3d-printer-nozzle-made-from-mosquitos-proboscis/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2065922040-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2065922040-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Walter Ferrari / 500px</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Trump wants tiny Japanese-style cars for US even as he cuts mpg goals</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/trump-wants-tiny-japanese-style-cars-for-us-even-as-he-cuts-mpg-goals/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/trump-wants-tiny-japanese-style-cars-for-us-even-as-he-cuts-mpg-goals/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CAFE standards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fuel economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kei cars]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/trump-wants-tiny-japanese-style-cars-for-us-even-as-he-cuts-mpg-goals/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Even the first Trump administration had tougher fuel economy targets. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>It’s been less than a year into the second Trump administration, and to many outside observers, US government policies appear confusing or incoherent. Yesterday provided a good example from the automotive sector. As has been widely expected, the White House is moving ahead with plans to significantly erode fuel economy standards, beyond even the permissive levels <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2020/03/heres-the-trump-admins-pathetic-new-fuel-efficiency-rule-for-2026/">that were considered OK</a> during the first Trump term.</p>
<p>Yet at the very announcement of that rollback, surrounded by compliant US automotive executives, the president decided to go <em>off piste</em> to declare his admiration for <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2018/04/a-beginners-guide-to-the-world-of-weird-and-wonderful-japanese-import-cars/">tiny Japanese Kei cars</a>, telling Transportation Secretary Sean Duffy to make them street-legal in the US.</p>
<h2><s>50.4 mpg</s> <s>40.4 mpg</s> 34.5 mpg</h2>
<p>A little over a decade ago, the Obama administration announced new fuel economy standards for light trucks and cars that were meant to go into effect this year, bringing the corporate fleet fuel economy average <a href="https://arstechnica.com/features/2012/10/the-road-ahead-how-well-get-to-54-5-mpg-by-2025/">up to 50.4 mpg</a>. As you can probably tell, that didn’t happen. It wasn’t a popular <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2016/12/epa-reaffirms-55-4mpg-target-fuel-economy-by-2025-automakers-turn-to-trump/">move with automakers</a>, and the first Trump administration ripped up those rules and instituted new, weaker targets of just <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2020/03/heres-the-trump-admins-pathetic-new-fuel-efficiency-rule-for-2026/">40.4 mpg by 2026</a>.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/trump-wants-tiny-japanese-style-cars-for-us-even-as-he-cuts-mpg-goals/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/trump-wants-tiny-japanese-style-cars-for-us-even-as-he-cuts-mpg-goals/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>206</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2234137052-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2234137052-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Kiyoshi Ota/Bloomberg via Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>The Honda N-One is a Kei car, but I doubt Trump would like this one because it's electric.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Lego announces NASA Artemis SLS rocket set to lift off (literally) in 2026</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/lego-announces-nasa-artemis-sls-rocket-set-to-lift-off-literally-in-2026/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/lego-announces-nasa-artemis-sls-rocket-set-to-lift-off-literally-in-2026/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Robert Pearlman]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[42221]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artemis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space collectible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space exploration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space launch system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space memorabilia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space toy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technic]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/lego-announces-nasa-artemis-sls-rocket-set-to-lift-off-literally-in-2026/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Developed with NASA and ESA, the 632-piece kit comes out Jan. 1.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>How do you top a highly detailed scale model of NASA’s new moon-bound rocket and its support tower? If you’re Lego, you make it so it can actually lift off.</p>
<p>Lego’s <a href="https://www.collectspace.com/news/news-120225a-lego-technic-nasa-artemis-space-launch-system-rocket-42221.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NASA Artemis Space Launch System Rocket</a>, part of its Technic line of advanced building sets, will land on store shelves for $60 on January 1, 2026, and then “blast off” from kitchen tables, office desks and living room floors. The 632-piece set climbs skyward, separating from its expendable stages along the way, until the Orion crew spacecraft and its European Service Module top out the motion on their way to the moon—or wherever your imagination carries it.</p>
<p>“The educational LEGO Technic set shows the moment a rocket launches, in three distinct stages,” reads the product <a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=O/y3wEShOBQ&amp;mid=13923&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fnasa-artemis-space-launch-system-rocket-42221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">description on Lego’s website</a>. “Turn the crank to see the solid rocket boosters separate from the core stage, which then also detaches. Continue turning to watch the upper stage with its engine module, Orion spacecraft and launch abort system separate.”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/lego-announces-nasa-artemis-sls-rocket-set-to-lift-off-literally-in-2026/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/12/lego-announces-nasa-artemis-sls-rocket-set-to-lift-off-literally-in-2026/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/news-120225b-lg-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/news-120225b-lg-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>LEGO/collectSPACE.com</media:credit><media:text>The LEGO Technic NASA Artemis Space Launch System Rocket set reproduces in motion the major milestones of the moon-bound vehicle's climb into Earth orbit on its way to flying astronauts to the moon.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>The NPU in your phone keeps improving—why isn’t that making AI better?</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/the-npu-in-your-phone-keeps-improving-why-isnt-that-making-ai-better/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/the-npu-in-your-phone-keeps-improving-why-isnt-that-making-ai-better/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generative ai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NPU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/the-npu-in-your-phone-keeps-improving-why-isnt-that-making-ai-better/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Shrinking AI for your phone is no simple matter.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Almost every technological innovation of the past several years has been laser-focused on one thing: generative AI. Many of these supposedly revolutionary systems run on big, expensive servers in a data center somewhere, but at the same time, chipmakers are crowing about the power of the neural processing units (NPU) they have brought to consumer devices. Every few months, it’s the same thing: This new NPU is 30 or 40 percent faster than the last one. That’s supposed to let you do something important, but no one really gets around to explaining what that is.</p>
<p>Experts envision a future of secure, personal AI tools with on-device intelligence, but does that match the reality of the AI boom? AI on the “edge” sounds great, but almost every AI tool of consequence is running in the cloud. So what’s that chip in your phone even doing?</p>
<h2>What is an NPU?</h2>
<p>Companies launching a new product often get bogged down in superlatives and vague marketing speak, so they do a poor job of explaining technical details. It’s not clear to most people buying a phone why they need the hardware to run AI workloads, and the supposed benefits are largely theoretical.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/the-npu-in-your-phone-keeps-improving-why-isnt-that-making-ai-better/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/the-npu-in-your-phone-keeps-improving-why-isnt-that-making-ai-better/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>96</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/npu_phone-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/npu_phone-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Aurich Lawson | Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>The NPU in your phone might not be doing very much. </media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>A fentanyl vaccine is about to get its first major test</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/a-fentanyl-vaccine-is-about-to-get-its-first-major-test/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/a-fentanyl-vaccine-is-about-to-get-its-first-major-test/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Emily Mullin, WIRED.com]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fentanyl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opioids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccines]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/a-fentanyl-vaccine-is-about-to-get-its-first-major-test/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Vaccine trial in the Netherlands hopes to protect against fentanyl-related overdose and death.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Just a tiny amount of fentanyl, the equivalent of a few grains of sand, is enough to stop a person’s breathing. The <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-type-of-opioid-is-killing-people-in-the-us-europe-and-australia/">synthetic opioid</a> is tasteless, odorless, and invisible when mixed with other substances, and drug users are often unaware of its presence.</p>
<p>It’s why biotech entrepreneur Collin Gage is aiming to protect people against the drug’s lethal effects. In 2023, he became the cofounder and CEO of ARMR Sciences to develop a vaccine against fentanyl. Now, the company is launching a trial to test its vaccine in people for the first time. The goal: prevent deaths from overdose.</p>
<p>“It became very apparent to me that as I assessed the treatment landscape, everything that exists is reactionary,” Gage says. “I thought, why are we not preventing this?”</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/a-fentanyl-vaccine-is-about-to-get-its-first-major-test/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/a-fentanyl-vaccine-is-about-to-get-its-first-major-test/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>93</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2209051218-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2209051218-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Douglas Sacha via Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>12 former FDA chiefs unite to say agency memo on vaccines is deeply stupid</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/12-former-fda-chiefs-unite-to-say-agency-memo-on-vaccines-is-deeply-stupid/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/12-former-fda-chiefs-unite-to-say-agency-memo-on-vaccines-is-deeply-stupid/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clinical trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COVID-19]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vaccines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vinay prasad]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/12-former-fda-chiefs-unite-to-say-agency-memo-on-vaccines-is-deeply-stupid/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Prasad's arguments "misrepresent both the science and the regulatory record."]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>On Friday, Vinay Prasad—the Food and Drug Administration’s chief medical and scientific officer and its top vaccine regulator—emailed <a href="https://www.biocentury.com/article/657740">a stunning memo</a> to staff that quickly leaked to the press. Without evidence, Prasad claimed COVID-19 vaccines have killed 10 children in the US, and, as such, he announced unilateral, sweeping changes to the way the agency regulates and approves vaccines, including seasonal flu shots.</p>
<p>On Wednesday evening, a dozen former FDA commissioners, who collectively oversaw the agency for more than 35 years, responded to the memo with <a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMp2517497?query=featured_home">a scathing rebuke</a>. Uniting to publish their response in the New England Journal of Medicine, the former commissioners said they were “deeply concerned” by Prasad’s memo, which they framed as a “threat” to the FDA’s work and a danger to Americans’ health.</p>
<p>In his memo, Prasad called for abandoning the FDA’s current framework for updating seasonal flu shots and other vaccines, such as those for COVID-19. Those updates currently involve studies that measure well-characterized immune responses (called immunobridging studies). Prasad dismissed this approach as insufficient and, instead, plans to require expensive randomized trials, which can take months to years for each vaccine update.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/12-former-fda-chiefs-unite-to-say-agency-memo-on-vaccines-is-deeply-stupid/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/12/12-former-fda-chiefs-unite-to-say-agency-memo-on-vaccines-is-deeply-stupid/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>134</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/GettyImages-1403288381-1152x648.jpeg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/GettyImages-1403288381-500x500.jpeg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Joe Raedle</media:credit><media:text>Robert Califf, former commissioner of the Food and Drug Administration, was among those who responded to Vinay Prasad's memo.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Admins and defenders gird themselves against maximum-severity server vuln</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/12/admins-and-defenders-gird-themselves-against-maximum-severity-server-vulnerability/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/12/admins-and-defenders-gird-themselves-against-maximum-severity-server-vulnerability/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 23:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[react server components]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulnerabilities]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/12/admins-and-defenders-gird-themselves-against-maximum-severity-server-vulnerability/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Open source React executes malicious code with malformed HTML—no authentication needed.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>Security defenders are girding themselves in response to the disclosure of a maximum-severity vulnerability disclosed Wednesday in React Server, an open-source package that’s widely used by websites and in cloud environments.</p>
<p>The vulnerability is easy to exploit and allows hackers to execute malicious code on servers that run it. Exploit code is now <a href="https://github.com/ejpir/CVE-2025-55182-poc/tree/main">publicly available</a>.</p>
<p>React is embedded into web apps running on servers so that remote devices render JavaScript and content more quickly and with fewer resources required. React is used by an estimated <a href="https://www.wiz.io/blog/critical-vulnerability-in-react-cve-2025-55182">6 percent</a> of all websites and 39 percent of cloud environments. When end users reload a page, React allows servers to re-render only parts that have changed, a feature that drastically speeds up performance and lowers the computing resources required by the server.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/12/admins-and-defenders-gird-themselves-against-maximum-severity-server-vulnerability/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/12/admins-and-defenders-gird-themselves-against-maximum-severity-server-vulnerability/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>69</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/exploit-vulnerability-security-1.jpg">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/exploit-vulnerability-security-1-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Great handling, advanced EV tech: We drive the 2027 BMW iX3</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/great-handling-advanced-ev-tech-we-drive-the-2026-bmw-ix3/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/great-handling-advanced-ev-tech-we-drive-the-2026-bmw-ix3/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 23:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BMW iX3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First drive]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/great-handling-advanced-ev-tech-we-drive-the-2026-bmw-ix3/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[The first of BMW's clean-sheet "Neue Klasse" EVs hits it out of the park.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<aside class="pullbox sidebar fullwidth">BMW provided flights from Washington, DC, to Malaga, Spain, and accommodation so Ars could drive the iX3. Ars does not accept paid editorial content.</aside>
<p>The new BMW iX3 is an important car for the automaker. It’s the first of a new series of vehicles that BMW is calling the Neue Klasse, calling back to a range of cars that helped define the brand in the 1960s. Then, as now, propulsion is provided by the best powertrain BMW’s engineers could design and build, wrapped in styling that heralds the company’s new look. Except now, that powertrain is fully electric, and the cabin features technology that would have been scarcely believable to the driver of a new 1962 BMW 1500.</p>
<p>In fact, the iX3 is only half the story when it comes to BMW’s neue look for the Neue Klasse—there’s an all-electric 3 series sedan on the way, too. The sedan will surely appeal to enthusiasts, particularly the version that the M tuning arm has worked its magic upon, but you’ll have to wait until early 2026 to read about that stuff. Which makes sense: crossovers and SUVs—or “sports activity vehicles” in BMW-speak—are what the market wants these days, so that’s what comes first.</p>
<h2>The technical stuff</h2>
<p>As we learned <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/08/how-bmw-slashed-the-carbon-footprint-of-its-next-ev-the-2026-ix3/">earlier this summer</a>, BMW leaned heavily into sustainability when it designed the iX3. There’s extensive use of recycled battery minerals, interior plastics, and aluminum, and the automaker has gone for a monomaterial approach where possible to make recycling the car a lot easier. There’s also <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/09/neue-klasse-bmws-tech-filled-ix3-electric-suv-is-unveiled/">an all-new EV powertrain</a>, BMW’s sixth-generation. When it goes on sale here next summer, the launch model will be the iX3 50 xDrive, which pairs an asynchronous motor at the front axle and an electrically excited synchronous motor at the rear for a combined output of 463 hp (345 kW) and 475 lb-ft (645 Nm).</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/great-handling-advanced-ev-tech-we-drive-the-2026-bmw-ix3/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/12/great-handling-advanced-ev-tech-we-drive-the-2026-bmw-ix3/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>120</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/BMW-iX3-50-xDrive-Spacesilver-061-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/BMW-iX3-50-xDrive-Spacesilver-061-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>BMW</media:credit><media:text>BMW's new iX3 is a clean-sheet design. It might be the most sustainable BMW ever, and remains decent to drive.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Republicans drop Trump-ordered block on state AI laws from defense bill</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/republicans-once-again-thwart-trumps-push-to-block-state-ai-laws/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/republicans-once-again-thwart-trumps-push-to-block-state-ai-laws/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raise act]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[state AI laws]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/republicans-once-again-thwart-trumps-push-to-block-state-ai-laws/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[“Widespread and powerful movement” keeps Trump from blocking state AI laws.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>A Donald Trump-backed push has failed to wedge a federal measure that would block states from passing AI laws for a decade into the National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA).</p>
<p>House Majority Leader Steve Scalise (R-La.) told reporters Tuesday that a sect of Republicans is now “looking at other places” to potentially pass the measure. Other Republicans opposed including the AI preemption in the defense bill, The Hill <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/technology/5630709-ai-preemption-republican-leaders/">reported</a>, joining critics who see value in allowing states to quickly regulate AI risks as they arise.</p>
<p>For months, Trump has pressured the Republican-led Congress to block state AI laws that the president claims could bog down innovation as AI firms waste time and resources complying with a patchwork of state laws. But Republicans have continually failed to unite behind Trump’s command, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/ted-cruz-gives-up-on-ai-law-moratorium-joins-99-1-vote-against-his-own-plan/">first voting against </a>including a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/05/gop-sneaks-decade-long-ai-regulation-ban-into-spending-bill/">similar measure in the “Big Beautiful” budget bill</a> and then this week failing to negotiate a solution to pass the NDAA measure.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/republicans-once-again-thwart-trumps-push-to-block-state-ai-laws/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/12/republicans-once-again-thwart-trumps-push-to-block-state-ai-laws/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2238395456-1024x648.jpg" width="1024">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-2238395456-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Win McNamee / Staff | Getty Images News</media:credit></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Humans in southern Africa were an isolated population until recently</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/ancient-genomes-from-southern-africa-reveal-distinct-human-lineage/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/ancient-genomes-from-southern-africa-reveal-distinct-human-lineage/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[John Timmer]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genomics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human evolution]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/ancient-genomes-from-southern-africa-reveal-distinct-human-lineage/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[A distinct population that was isolated until the last thousand years or so. ]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>The fossil and genetic evidence agree that modern humans originated in Africa. The most genetically diverse human populations—the groups that have had the longest time to pick up novel mutations—live there today. But the history of what went on within Africa between our origins and the present day is a bit murky.</p>
<p>That’s partly because DNA doesn’t survive long in the conditions typical of most of the continent, which has largely limited us to trying to reconstruct the past using data from present-day populations. The other part is that many of those present-day populations have been impacted by the vast genetic churn <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2017/05/how-the-bantu-people-surged-across-two-thirds-of-africa/">caused by the Bantu expansion</a>, which left its traces across most of the populations south of the Sahara.</p>
<p>But a new study has managed to extract genomes from ancient samples in southern Africa. While all of these are relatively recent, dating from after the end of the most recent glacial period, they reveal a distinct southern African population that was relatively large, outside of the range of previously described human variation, and it remained isolated until only about 1,000 years ago.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/ancient-genomes-from-southern-africa-reveal-distinct-human-lineage/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/12/ancient-genomes-from-southern-africa-reveal-distinct-human-lineage/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-940753366-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/GettyImages-940753366-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Edwin Remsberg</media:credit><media:text>The Zambezi River, which includes Victoria Falls, helps define a region that had a distinct population of modern humans.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>After nearly 30 years, Crucial will stop selling RAM to consumers</title>
                <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/after-nearly-30-years-crucial-will-stop-selling-ram-to-consumers/</link>
                                    <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/after-nearly-30-years-crucial-will-stop-selling-ram-to-consumers/#comments</comments>
                
                <dc:creator>
                    <![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]>
                </dc:creator>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
                		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AMD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crucial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[datacenters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DDR5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DRAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[framework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lenovo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory shortage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Micron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NVIDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pc building]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semiconductors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SK Hynix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSD]]></category>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/after-nearly-30-years-crucial-will-stop-selling-ram-to-consumers/</guid>

                                    <description>
                        <![CDATA[Micron cites AI data center demand as reason for killing DIY upgrade brand.]]>
                    </description>
                                                                <content:encoded>
                            <![CDATA[<p>On Wednesday, Micron Technology <a href="https://investors.micron.com/news-releases/news-release-details/micron-announces-exit-crucial-consumer-business">announced</a> it will exit the consumer RAM business in 2026, ending 29 years of selling RAM and SSDs to PC builders and enthusiasts under the Crucial brand. The company cited heavy demand from AI data centers as the reason for abandoning its consumer brand, a move that will remove one of the most recognizable names in the do-it-yourself PC upgrade market.</p>
<p>“The AI-driven growth in the data center has led to a surge in demand for memory and storage,” Sumit Sadana, EVP and chief business officer at Micron Technology, said in a statement. “Micron has made the difficult decision to exit the Crucial consumer business in order to improve supply and support for our larger, strategic customers in faster-growing segments.”</p>
<p>Micron said it will continue shipping Crucial consumer products through the end of its fiscal second quarter in February 2026 and will honor warranties on existing products. The company will continue selling Micron-branded enterprise products to commercial customers and plans to redeploy affected employees to other positions within the company.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/after-nearly-30-years-crucial-will-stop-selling-ram-to-consumers/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/after-nearly-30-years-crucial-will-stop-selling-ram-to-consumers/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
                        </content:encoded>
                                    
                                    <slash:comments>227</slash:comments>
                
                
                <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/crucial_ram_header-1080x648.jpg" width="1080">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/crucial_ram_header-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Micron Technology</media:credit><media:text>An example of a Crucial DDR5 RAM kit from 2025.</media:text></media:content>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>