<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
	<atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 12:12:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Witch’s Road might take everything in Agatha All Along D23 trailer</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042393</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/08/the-witchs-road-might-take-everything-in-agatha-all-along-d23-trailer/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 21:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Agatha All Along]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D23 Expo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disney plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trailers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA["The Witch's Road will give you the thing you want most... if you make it to the end." ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">





<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"><iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/R9pXbNz6Vbw?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Kathryn Hahn seeks a new witchy coven in <em>Agatha All Along</em>. </p></div>
<p>Disney introduced the poster and first full trailer for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agatha_All_Along_(miniseries)"><em>Agatha All Along</em></a> during its annual D23 Expo this weekend. The nine-episode series, starring Kathryn Hahn, is one of the TV series in the MCU's <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marvel_Cinematic_Universe:_Phase_Five">Phase Five</a>, coming on the heels of <em>Secret Invasion, Loki </em>S2, <em>What If...?</em> S2, and <em>Echo</em>.</p>
<p><strong>(Spoilers for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WandaVision"><em>WandaVision</em></a> below.)</strong></p>
<p>As <a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/07/kathryn-hahn-is-ready-to-walk-the-witchs-road-in-agatha-all-along-trailer/">reported previously</a>, <em>Agatha All Along</em> has been in the works since 2021, officially announced in November of that year, inspired by Hahn's breakout performance in <em>WandaVision</em> as nosy neighbor Agnes—but secretly a powerful witch named Agatha Harkness who was conspiring to steal Wanda's power. The plot twist even inspired <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P8u8md-NiHM">a meta-jingle</a> that went viral. That series ended with Wanda victorious and Agatha robbed of all her powers, trapped in her nosy neighbor persona.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042393#p3">Read 4 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042393&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/08/the-witchs-road-might-take-everything-in-agatha-all-along-d23-trailer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jude Law’s Jedi befriends kids lost in space in Star Wars: Skeleton Crew trailer</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042397</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/08/jude-laws-jedi-befriends-kids-lost-in-space-in-star-wars-skeleton-crew-trailer/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 20:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disney plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skeleton Crew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Wars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trailers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The standalone series is set in the same timeframe as <em>The Mandalorian</em> and <em>Ahsoka</em>. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">





<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<div class="video"><div class="wrapper"><iframe style="display:block" type="text/html" width="980" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/a6voXgBlmpk?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em">Jude Law plays a Jedi in <em>Star Wars: Skeleton Crew</em>. </p></div>
<p>The Star Wars universe continues to expand on streaming television with the release of the first trailer for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Wars:_Skeleton_Crew"><em>Star Wars: Skeleton Crew</em></a> this weekend at Disney's annual D23 Expo. The eight-episode standalone series is set in the same timeframe as <em>The Mandalorian</em> and <em>Ahsoka</em>.</p>
<p>Executive Producer Kathleen Kennedy was intrigued when series co-creator Jon Watts pitched a Star Wars series inspired by the 1985 film <em>The Goonies</em>. (Kennedy had co-produced that film and co-founded Amblin Entertainment.) She told co-creator Christopher Ford that <em>The Goonies</em> hadn't been created specifically for kids, instead telling a story that just happened to be about kids going on an adventure. So Ford and Watts wrote <em>Skeleton Crew</em> with the same mindset: a show for everyone that just happened to feature kids as the central characters. Per the official premise:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Skeleton Crew</em> follows the journey of four kids who make a mysterious discovery on their seemingly safe home planet, then get lost in a strange and dangerous galaxy, crossing paths with the likes of Jod Na Nawood, the mysterious character played by [Jude] Law. Finding their way home—and meeting unlikely allies and enemies—will be a greater adventure than they ever imagined.</p></blockquote>
<p>Jude Law leads the cast as the quick-witted and charming (per Law) "Force-user" Jod Na Nawood. Ravi Cabot-Conyers plays Wim, Ryan Kiera Armstrong plays Fern, Kyriana Kratter plays KB, and Robert Timothy Smith plays Neil. Nick Frost will voice a droid named SM 33. The cast also includes Tunde Adebimpe, Kerry Condon, and Jaleel White in as-yet-undisclosed roles.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042397#p3">Read 2 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042397&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/08/jude-laws-jedi-befriends-kids-lost-in-space-in-star-wars-skeleton-crew-trailer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>71</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>520-million-year-old larva fossil reveals the origins of arthropods</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2041992</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/520-million-year-old-larva-fossil-reveals-the-origins-of-arthropods/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elizabeth Rayne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arthropods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evolution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2041992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early arthropod development illuminated by a microscopic fossil.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/image-1-e1723154345662-800x637.png" alt="Image of a small grey object, curved around its abdomen, with a series of small appendages on the bottom.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/image-1-e1723154345662.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1356" data-width="1704">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> The fossil in question, oriented with its head to the left. (credit: Yang Jie / Zhang Xiguang)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Around half a billion years ago, in what is now the Yunnan Province of China, a tiny larva was trapped in mud. Hundreds of millions of years later, after the mud had long since become the black shales of the Yuan’shan formation, the larva surfaced again, a meticulously preserved time capsule that would unearth more about the evolution of arthropods.</p>
<p><i>Youti yuanshi </i>is barely visible to the naked eye. Roughly the size of a poppy seed, it is preserved so well that its exoskeleton is almost completely intact, and even the outlines of what were once its internal organs can be seen through the lens of a microscope. Durham University researchers who examined it were able to see features of both ancient and modern arthropods. Some of these features told them how the simpler, more wormlike ancestors of living arthropods evolved into more complex organisms.</p>
<p>The research team also found that <i>Y. yuanshi, </i>which existed during the Cambrian Explosion (when most of the main animal groups started to appear on the fossil record), has certain features in common with extant arthropods, such as crabs, velvet worms, and tardigrades. “The deep evolutionary position of <i>Youti yuanshi… </i>illuminat[es] the internal anatomical changes that propelled the rise and diversification of [arthropods],” they said in a study recently published in Nature.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2041992#p3">Read 10 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2041992&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/520-million-year-old-larva-fossil-reveals-the-origins-of-arthropods/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Almost unfixable “Sinkclose” bug affects hundreds of millions of AMD chips</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042298</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/08/almost-unfixable-sinkclose-bug-affects-hundreds-of-millions-of-amd-cpus/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WIRED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AMD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CPU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sinkclose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042298</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Worse-case scenario: "You basically have to throw your computer away."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">





<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Security flaws in your computer's firmware, the deep-seated code that loads first when you turn the machine on and controls even how its operating system boots up, have long been a target for hackers looking for a stealthy foothold. But only rarely does that kind of vulnerability appear not in the firmware of any particular computer maker, but in the chips found across hundreds of millions of PCs and servers. Now security researchers have found one such flaw that has persisted in AMD processors for decades, and that would allow malware to burrow deep enough into a computer's memory that, in many cases, it may be easier to discard a machine than to disinfect it.</p>
<p>At the Defcon hacker conference, Enrique Nissim and Krzysztof Okupski, researchers from the security firm IOActive, plan to present a vulnerability in AMD chips they're calling Sinkclose. The flaw would allow hackers to run their own code in one of the most privileged modes of an AMD processor, known as System Management Mode, designed to be reserved only for a specific, protected portion of its firmware. IOActive's researchers warn that it affects virtually all AMD chips dating back to 2006, or possibly even earlier.</p>
<p></p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042298#p3">Read 13 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042298&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/08/almost-unfixable-sinkclose-bug-affects-hundreds-of-millions-of-amd-cpus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>248</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>More than greenwashing? Sustainable aviation fuels struggle to take off</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042237</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/08/more-than-greenwashing-sustainable-aviation-fuels-struggle-to-take-off/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Inside Climate News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 10:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042237</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alternative fuels are intended to reduce the carbon footprint of airlines.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/contrails-800x533.jpg" alt="Contrails from a jet">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/contrails.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1707" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Sustainable aviation fuels could help cut carbon emissions from commercial flights. 
 (credit: Costfoto/NurPhoto via Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Last November, Virgin Atlantic Airways made headlines for completing the world’s first transatlantic flight using “<a href="https://corporate.virginatlantic.com/gb/en/business-for-good/planet/fuel/flight100.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">100 percent sustainable aviation fuel</a>.”</p>
<p>This week, the Advertising Standard Authority (ASA) of the U.K. banned a Virgin radio ad released prior to the flight, in which they touted their “unique flight mission.” While Virgin did use fuel that releases fewer emissions than traditional supplies, the regulatory agency deemed the company’s sustainability claim “<a href="https://www.asa.org.uk/rulings/virgin-atlantic-airways-ltd-g23-1224417-virgin-atlantic-airways-ltd.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">misleading</a>” because it failed to give a full picture of the adverse environmental and climate impacts of fuel.</p>
<p>“It’s important that claims for sustainable aviation fuel spell out what the reality is, so consumers aren’t misled into thinking that the flight they are taking is greener than it really is,” Miles Lockwood, director of complaints and investigations at the ASA, said in a statement.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042237#p3">Read 20 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042237&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/08/more-than-greenwashing-sustainable-aviation-fuels-struggle-to-take-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>145</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Infamous $30 Logitech F710 called out in $50M lawsuit over Titan sub implosion</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042370</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/08/infamous-30-logitech-f710-called-out-in-50m-lawsuit-over-titan-sub-implosion/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nate Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logitech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Titan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video game controller]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Family of dead <em>Titanic</em> expert blasts "hip" electronics.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sub_gamecontroller_hero_1-800x450.jpg" alt="Stockton Rush shows David Pogue the game controller that pilots the OceanGate Titan sub during a CBS Sunday Morning segment broadcast in November 2022.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sub_gamecontroller_hero_1.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="888" data-width="1577">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> OceanGate CEO Stockton Rush shows David Pogue the 2010-era game controller that pilots the <em>Titan</em> sub during a <em>CBS Sunday Morning</em> segment broadcast in November 2022. (credit: CBS Sunday Morning)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=29co_Hksk6o&amp;t=213s">2022 CBS Sunday Morning segment</a>, CEO Stockton Rush of deep-water submersible company OceanGate gave journalist David Pogue a fun reveal. "We run the whole thing with this game controller," Rush said, holding up a Logitech F710 controller with 3D-printed thumbstick extensions. The controller was wireless, and it was the primary method for controlling the <em>Titan</em> submersible, which would soon make a visit to the wreck of the <em>Titanic</em>. Pogue laughed. "Come on!" he said, covering his eyes with his hand.</p>
<p>Journalists <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/submarine-missing-near-titanic-used-a-30-logitech-gamepad-for-steering/">loved the controller story</a>, covering the inexpensive F710 and the ways that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/06/missing-titanic-sub-isnt-the-first-to-use-game-controls-for-heavy-machinery/">video game controllers have become common control solutions</a> in various military and spaceflight applications in recent years. After all, if your engineers and pilots grew up using two-stick controllers to waste their friends in <em>Halo</em> multiplayer, why not use that built-in muscle memory for other purposes?</p>
<p>So the use of a video game controller was not in itself a crazy decision. But after the <em>Titan</em> sub <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-65934887">imploded</a> on a June 2023 dive to the <em>Titanic</em> site, killing all five passengers including Stockton Rush, the use of a wireless $30 control interface began to look less "cool!" and more "isn't that kind of risky?" The only question at that point was how long it would take the Logitech F710 to show up in a lawsuit.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042370#p3">Read 13 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042370&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2024/08/infamous-30-logitech-f710-called-out-in-50m-lawsuit-over-titan-sub-implosion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>370</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pass the mayo: Condiment could help improve fusion energy yields</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042179</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/kitchen-science-how-mayonnaise-is-advancing-nuclear-fusion-research/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Ouellette]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 20:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[condiments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fluid dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hydrodynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuclear fusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuclear physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phase transitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rayleigh-Taylor instability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Controlling a problematic instability could lead to cheaper internal fusion. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/mayo2-800x533.jpg" alt="A jar of homemade mayonnaise">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/mayo2.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="799" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/">jules/CC BY 2.0</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Inertial confinement fusion is one method for generating energy through nuclear fusion, albeit one plagued by all manner of scientific challenges (although progress <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/08/physicists-achieve-fusion-net-energy-gain-for-second-time/">is being made</a>). Researchers at LeHigh University are attempting to overcome one specific bugbear with this approach by conducting experiments with mayonnaise placed in a rotating figure-eight contraption. They described their most recent findings in a <a href="https://journals.aps.org/pre/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.055103">new paper</a> published in the journal Physical Review E with an eye toward increasing energy yields from fusion.</p>
<p>The work builds on prior research in the LeHigh laboratory of mechanical engineer Arindam Banerjee, who focuses on investigating the dynamics of fluids and other materials in response to extremely high acceleration and centrifugal force. In this case, his team was exploring what's known as the "instability threshold" of elastic/plastic materials. Scientists have debated whether this comes about because of initial conditions, or whether it's the result of "more local catastrophic processes," according to Banerjee. The question is relevant to a variety of fields, including geophysics, astrophysics, explosive welding, and yes, inertial confinement fusion.</p>
<p>How exactly does inertial confinement fusion work? As <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2016/12/partially-liquid-hydrogen-cooperates-with-lasers-for-better-fusion-yield/">Chris Lee explained for Ars</a> back in 2016:</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042179#p3">Read 6 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042179&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/08/kitchen-science-how-mayonnaise-is-advancing-nuclear-fusion-research/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>104</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AT&amp;T rebuked over misleading ad for nonexistent satellite phone calling</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042344</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/att-rebuked-over-misleading-ad-for-nonexistent-satellite-phone-calling/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 20:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ast spacemobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[at&t satellite calling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satellite calling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AT&#038;T reluctantly adds disclaimer: "Satellite calling is not currently available."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/att-epic-bad-golf-day-800x499.jpg" alt="A gloved hand holds a phone while making a call. The screen shows an AT&amp;T logo and the text, " making satellite connection...>
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/att-epic-bad-golf-day.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1568" data-width="2512">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Screenshot from AT&amp;T commercial featuring Ben Stiller making a satellite call to Jordan Spieth. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h2MpZ0pQVmo">AT&amp;T</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>AT&amp;T has been told to stop running ads that claim the carrier is already offering cellular coverage from space.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T intends to offer Supplemental Coverage from Space (SCS) and has a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/01/google-and-att-invest-in-starlink-rival-for-satellite-to-smartphone-service/">deal with AST SpaceMobile</a>, a Starlink competitor that plans a smartphone service from low-Earth-orbit satellites. But AST SpaceMobile's <a href="https://feeds.issuerdirect.com/news-release.html?newsid=4828399196673356">first batch</a> of five satellites isn't scheduled to launch until September.</p>
<p>T-Mobile was annoyed by AT&amp;T running an ad indicating that its satellite-to-cellular service was already available, and filed a challenge with the advertising industry's self-regulatory system run by BBB National Programs. The BBB National Advertising Division (NAD) ruled against AT&amp;T last month and the carrier <a href="https://bbbprograms.org/media-center/dd/att-supplemental-coverage-space">appealed</a> to the National Advertising Review Board (NARB), which has now also ruled against AT&amp;T.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042344#p3">Read 11 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042344&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/att-rebuked-over-misleading-ad-for-nonexistent-satellite-phone-calling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>64</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nashville man arrested for running “laptop farm” to get jobs for North Koreans</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042326</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/08/nashville-man-arrested-for-running-laptop-farm-to-get-jobs-for-north-koreans/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 20:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Identity theft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[it jobs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Laptop farm gave the impression North Korean nationals were working from the US.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/north-korea-hackers-800x534.jpeg" alt="Nashville man arrested for running “laptop farm” to get jobs for North Koreans">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/north-korea-hackers.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="667" data-width="1000">Enlarge</a> </p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Federal authorities have arrested a Nashville man on charges he hosted laptops at his residences in a scheme to deceive US companies into hiring foreign remote IT workers who funneled hundreds of thousands of dollars in income to fund North Korea’s weapons program.</p>
<p>The scheme, federal prosecutors said, worked by getting US companies to unwittingly hire North Korean nationals, who used the stolen identity of a Georgia man to appear to be a US citizen. Under sanctions issued by the federal government, US employers are strictly forbidden from hiring citizens of North Korea. Once the North Korean nationals were hired, the employers sent company-issued laptops to Matthew Isaac Knoot, 38, of Nashville, Tennessee, the prosecutors said in court papers filed in the US District Court of the Middle District of Tennessee. The court documents also said a foreign national with the alias Yang Di was involved in the conspiracy.</p>
<p>The prosecutors wrote:</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042326#p3">Read 6 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042326&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/08/nashville-man-arrested-for-running-laptop-farm-to-get-jobs-for-north-koreans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>117</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>People game AIs via game theory</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042327</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/08/people-act-differently-when-they-think-theyre-training-an-ai/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[John Timmer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 20:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Behavioral science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Human behavior]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[They reject more of the AI's offers, probably to get it to be more generous.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1571202037-800x533.jpg" alt="A judge's gavel near a pile of small change.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1571202037.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1414" data-width="2121">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> In the experiments, people had to judge what constituted a fair monetary offer. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/photo/judges-gavel-and-money-financial-law-royalty-free-image/1571202037?phrase=fairness">manusapon kasosod</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>In many cases, AIs are trained on material that's either made or curated by humans. As a result, it can become a significant challenge to keep the AI from replicating the biases of those humans and the society they belong to. And the stakes are high, given we're using AIs to make medical and financial decisions.</p>
<p>But some researchers at Washington University in St. Louis have found an additional wrinkle in these challenges: The people doing the training may potentially change their behavior when they know it can influence the future choices made by an AI. And, in at least some cases, they carry the changed behaviors into situations that don't involve AI training.</p>
<h2>Would you like to play a game?</h2>
<p>The work involved getting volunteers to participate in a simple form of game theory. Testers gave two participants a pot of money—$10, in this case. One of the two was then asked to offer some fraction of that money to the other, who could choose to accept or reject the offer. If the offer was rejected, nobody got any money.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042327#p3">Read 11 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042327&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/08/people-act-differently-when-they-think-theyre-training-an-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>61</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intel details fixes for crashing 13th- and 14th-gen CPUs as BIOS updates roll out</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042246</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/fix-for-intel-cpu-crashes-causes-minor-situational-slowdowns-requires-bios-update/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 19:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[13th-generation core]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[14th-generation core]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This microcode fix can't be rolled out in a regular software update.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/14THGENDESKTOP-800x532.jpeg" alt="Intel details fixes for crashing 13th- and 14th-gen CPUs as BIOS updates roll out">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/14THGENDESKTOP-scaled.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1703" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> (credit: Intel)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Intel has shared more about the voltage-related issues that affected some 13th- and 14th-generation Core processors, as the company tries to put the episode behind it. <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/cpus/intel-details-microcode-update-patch-has-negligible-performance-impacts-requires-bios-update">As reported by Tom's Hardware</a>, Intel says that the problem originated with "elevated operating voltage" stemming from "incorrect voltage requests," specifically an increase to the minimum operating voltage of the chips. These "elevated voltage events can accumulate over time," eventually damaging the processor and causing system hangs or crashes.</p>
<p>Intel has developed a microcode update to fix those elevated voltage requests, but the bad news for some users is that they will require a BIOS update, and they can't be deployed via software updates as some microcode fixes can be.</p>
<p>Intel says that in most cases, CPU performance should be essentially unaffected by the patch, though the company did notice a handful of benchmark subscores and individual games that exhibited "moderate" slowdown (though we don't know how much that is, in concrete terms). Here's the relevant statement about performance:</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042246#p3">Read 8 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042246&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/fix-for-intel-cpu-crashes-causes-minor-situational-slowdowns-requires-bios-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nova Launcher, savior of cruft-filled Android phones, is on life support</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042216</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/nova-launcher-savior-of-cruft-filled-android-phones-is-on-life-support/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kevin Purdy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 18:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android customization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android launchers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app metrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[branch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nova launcher]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nova Launcher feels the "massive" layoffs at the firm that acquired it in 2022.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-09-at-1.44.07%E2%80%AFPM.png" alt="Lineup of four Android devices showing Nova Launcher aspects, including the logo, icon customization, and app drawer">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-09-at-1.44.07%E2%80%AFPM.png" class="enlarge-link" data-height="414" data-width="756">Enlarge</a> (credit: Nova Launcher)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Back in July 2022, when mobile app metrics firm Branch acquired the popular and well-regarded <a href="https://novalauncher.com/">Nova Launcher for Android</a>, the app's site put up one of those <a href="https://novalauncher.com/branch">self-directed FAQ posts about it</a>. Under the question heading "What does Branch want with Nova?," Nova founder and creator Kevin Barry started his response with, "Not to mess it up, don't worry!"</p>
<p><a href="https://www.branch.io/">Branch</a> (formerly/sometimes Branch Metrics) is a firm concerned with helping businesses track the links that lead into their apps, whether from SMS, email, marketing, or inside other apps. Nova, with <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ninja.sesame.app.edge">its Sesame Search</a> tool that helped users find and access deeper links—like heading straight to calling a car, rather than just opening a rideshare app—seemed like a reasonable fit.</p>
<p>Barry wrote that he had received a number of acquisition offers over the years, but he didn't want to be swallowed by a giant corporation, an OEM, or a volatile startup. "Branch is different," he wrote then, because they wanted to add staff to Nova, keep it available to the public, and mostly leave it alone.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042216#p3">Read 8 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042216&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/nova-launcher-savior-of-cruft-filled-android-phones-is-on-life-support/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>131</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dozens injured, pets killed in fires causing Samsung to recall 1.1M stoves</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042257</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/samsung-recalls-1-1m-electric-stoves-after-fires-caused-injuries-killed-pets/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ashley Belanger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 18:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer product safety commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric range]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electric stove]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fire hazard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samsung]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Samsung is currently offering free knob locks and covers to prevent fires.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Samsung-recall-via-Samsung.jpeg" alt="US Consumer Product Safety Commission announced a recall of 1.1 million Samsung Slide-in Electric Ranges due to hundreds of reported fires.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Samsung-recall-via-Samsung.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="600" data-width="800">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> US Consumer Product Safety Commission announced a recall of 1.1 million Samsung Slide-in Electric Ranges due to hundreds of reported fires. (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://image-us.samsung.com/SamsungUS/home/home-appliances/ranges/freestanding/pd/ne58f9500ss/gallery/03_Range_Electric_NE58F9500SS_Front_Lifestyle_Kitchen_Closed_Silver.jpg?%24product-details-jpg%24">Samsung</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>After hundreds of reports of fires causing dozens of injuries and several pet deaths, Samsung is recalling more than a million electric stoves sold in the US between 2013 and 2024.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.cpsc.gov/Recalls/2024/Samsung-Recalls-Slide-In-Electric-Ranges-Due-to-Fire-Hazard">press release</a>, the US Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) reported that the voluntary recall was due to "front-mounted knobs" on Samsung's slide-in electric ranges. The faulty knobs "can be activated by accidental contact by humans or pets, posing a fire hazard"—particularly when people leave objects on the stove.</p>
<p>The stoves impacted by the recall were widely sold in Costco, Home Depot, Best Buy, Lowe's, and other appliance stores nationwide. Their knobs can be easily triggered by accident, heating up the cooktop and increasing the risks of fires, the CPSC said. Since 2013, Samsung has received "over 300 reports of unintentional activation." According to the CPSC:</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042257#p3">Read 18 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042257&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/samsung-recalls-1-1m-electric-stoves-after-fires-caused-injuries-killed-pets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>166</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Archeology” on the ISS helps identify what astronauts really need</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2041989</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/08/archeology-on-the-iss-helps-identify-what-astronauts-really-need/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jacek Krywko]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 17:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Archeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space archeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space exploration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space station]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2041989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Regular photography shows a tool shed and more isolated toilet would be appreciated.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/image-1-800x534.jpeg" alt="I woman holds a handheld device in front of a rack of equipment.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/image-1.jpeg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="657" data-width="985">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Jessica Watkins gets to work on the ISS (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/station/iss-research/celebrating-womens-history-month-female-space-station-crew-members/">NASA</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>“Archeology really is a perspective on material culture we use as evidence to understand how humans adapt to their environment, to the situations they are in, and to each other. There is no place, no time that is out of bounds,” says Justin Walsh, an archeologist at Chapman University who led the first off-world archeological study on board the ISS.</p>
<p>Walsh’s and his team wanted to understand, document, and preserve the heritage of the astronaut culture at one of the first permanent space habitats. “There is this notion about astronauts that they are high achievers, highly intelligent, and highly trained, that they are not like you and me. What we learned is that they are just people, and they want the comforts of home,” Walsh says.</p>
<h2>Disposable cameras and garbage</h2>
<p>“In 2008, my student in an archeology class raised her hand and said, ‘What about stuff in space, is that heritage?’ I said, ‘Oh my God, I’ve never thought of this before, but yes,’” Walsh says. “Think of Tranquility base—it’s an archeological site. You could go back there, and you could reconstruct not only the specific activities of Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin, but you could understand the engineering culture, the political culture, etc. of the society that created that equipment, sent it to the Moon, and left it there.”</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2041989#p3">Read 19 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2041989&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/space/2024/08/archeology-on-the-iss-helps-identify-what-astronauts-really-need/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ChatGPT unexpectedly began speaking in a user’s cloned voice during testing</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042102</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/08/chatgpt-unexpectedly-began-speaking-in-a-users-cloned-voice-during-testing/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 16:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Woolf: "OpenAI just leaked the plot of Black Mirror's next season."]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/robot_audio_output-800x450.jpg" alt="An illustration of a computer synthesizer spewing out letters.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/robot_audio_output.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="675" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> (credit: <a rel="nofollow" class="caption-link" href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/photo/speaks-letters-text-to-speech-or-tts-text-to-voice-royalty-free-image/1458045238">Ole_CNX via Getty Images</a>)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>On Thursday, OpenAI released the "<a href="https://openai.com/index/gpt-4o-system-card/">system card</a>" for ChatGPT's new <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/05/chatgpt-4o-lets-you-have-real-time-audio-video-conversations-with-emotional-chatbot/">GPT-4o</a> AI model that details model limitations and safety testing procedures. Among other examples, the document reveals that in rare occurrences during testing, the model's <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/07/when-counting-quickly-openais-new-voice-mode-stops-to-catch-its-breath/">Advanced Voice Mode</a> unintentionally imitated users' voices without permission. Currently, OpenAI has safeguards in place that prevent this from happening, but the instance reflects the growing complexity of safely architecting with an AI chatbot that could potentially imitate any voice from a small clip.</p>

<p>Advanced Voice Mode is a feature of ChatGPT that allows users to have spoken conversations with the AI assistant.</p>
<p>In a section of the GPT-4o system card titled "Unauthorized voice generation," OpenAI details an episode where a noisy input somehow prompted the model to suddenly imitate the user's voice. "Voice generation can also occur in non-adversarial situations, such as our use of that ability to generate voices for ChatGPT’s advanced voice mode," OpenAI writes. "During testing, we also observed rare instances where the model would unintentionally generate an output emulating the user’s voice."</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042102#p3">Read 17 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042102&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/08/chatgpt-unexpectedly-began-speaking-in-a-users-cloned-voice-during-testing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>108</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here’s what the electric Dodge Charger’s “Fratzonic exhaust” sounds like</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042189</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/08/heres-what-the-electric-dodge-chargers-fratzonic-exhaust-sounds-like/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 16:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dodge Charger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fratzonic Chambered Exhaust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dodge wants to keep the aural spectacle even as it moves to electric propulsion.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/DG024_011CH-800x534.jpg" alt="A rendering of a silver Dodge Charger EV">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/DG024_011CH-scaled.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1708" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> Dodge doesn't want to be accused of building a boring EV. (credit: Dodge)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Electric motors have many advantages over internal combustion engines, including the fact that they don't waste a lot of their power as sound energy. So quiet are electric vehicles, in fact, that <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2016/12/14/2016-28804/federal-motor-vehicle-safety-standards-minimum-sound-requirements-for-hybrid-and-electric-vehicles">federal vehicle safety regulations</a> require EVs (and hybrids) to make a certain amount of noise at lower speeds to warn vulnerable road users like blind or visually impaired pedestrians of their presence.</p>
<p>Almost all of those cars end up sounding like a choir of depressed angels, a phrase memorably coined by either Richard Porter or Jonny Smith on the <em>Smith and Sniff</em> podcast. That's not the case with the forthcoming electric Dodge Charger, however. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/03/dodge-debuts-the-2024-electric-charger-daytona-with-670-horsepower/">When it first broke cover in March</a>, we learned that the electric Charger would feature something called a "Fratzonic Chambered Exhaust" to give it some aural character. Now, thanks to the video from Dodge embedded here, we can all hear what that sounds like in practice:</p>
<figure class="video ars-wp-video">
    <div class="wrapper ars-wp-video-wrapper" style="padding-bottom: 56.25%;">
        <video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-2042189-1" width="1280" height="720" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Dodge_Charger_Daytona_Scat_Pack.mp4?_=1"></source>Dodge knows that emotion is a big part of muscle car sales, so it's made the electric Charger sound very emotional.</video>    </div>
        <figcaption class="caption">
        <div class="caption-text">Dodge knows that emotion is a big part of muscle car sales, so it's made the electric Charger sound very emotional. </div>
    </figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>The Fratzonic Chambered Exhaust—<a href="https://www.motortrend.com/features/what-is-the-fratzog-logo/">the name refers</a> to a Dodge logo—<a href="https://moparinsiders.com/how-does-dodges-fratzonic-chambered-exhaust-work/">combines</a> various chambers underneath the Charger's body with some woofers and mid-range speakers, all driven by a dedicated 600 W amplifier. The system is also designed to transmit vibrations into the chassis through elastomeric bushings, mimicking an internal combustion engine and its motor mounts.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042189#p3">Read 4 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042189&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/cars/2024/08/heres-what-the-electric-dodge-chargers-fratzonic-exhaust-sounds-like/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>249</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk’s lawsuit over alleged X ad boycott “a very weak case,” professor says</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042149</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/elon-musks-lawsuit-over-alleged-x-ad-boycott-a-very-weak-case-professor-says/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 16:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elon musk x]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[x ad boycott]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Law is unfavorable to X, but Musk filed suit in potentially friendly Texas court.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/elon-musk-x-advertisers-800x450.jpg" alt="Illustration with three pictures of Elon Musk. In two of the photos there are dollar signs over Musk's eyes, in the other photo there are X logos instead.">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/elon-musk-x-advertisers.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1440" data-width="2560">Enlarge</a> (credit: Aurich Lawson | Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Antitrust law professors aren't impressed by <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/elon-musk-declares-it-is-war-on-ad-industry-as-x-sues-over-illegal-boycott/">Elon Musk's lawsuit</a> alleging a supposed X advertising boycott amounts to an antitrust violation. Based on the initial complaint filed by Musk's X Corp., it looks like "a very weak case," Vanderbilt Law School Associate Dean for Research <a href="https://law.vanderbilt.edu/bio/?pid=rebecca-allensworth">Rebecca Haw Allensworth</a> told Ars.</p>
<p>"Given how difficult this will be to win, I would call it an unusual strategy," she said.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.txnd.393003/gov.uscourts.txnd.393003.1.0_2.pdf">lawsuit</a> against the World Federation of Advertisers (WFA) and several large corporations says that the alleged boycott is "a naked restraint of trade without countervailing benefits to competition or consumers." The "collective action among competing advertisers to dictate brand safety standards to be applied by social media platforms shortcuts the competitive process and allows the collective views of a group of advertisers with market power to override the interests of consumers," X claims.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042149#p3">Read 35 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042149&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/08/elon-musks-lawsuit-over-alleged-x-ad-boycott-a-very-weak-case-professor-says/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>257</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ars asks: What was the last CD or DVD you burned?</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042118</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/staff/2024/08/ars-asks-what-was-the-last-cd-or-dvd-you-burned/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee Hutchinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple superdrive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cd burning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CD-R]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cd-rw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disc burning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dvd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dvd-r]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dvd-rw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Optical disc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[optical media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[staffsource]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SuperDrive]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042118</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the demise of Apple's SuperDrive, we reminisce on our final homemade optical discs.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-183340559-800x533.jpg" alt="Photograph of a CD-R disc on fire">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-183340559.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1414" data-width="2121">Enlarge</a> <span class="sep">/</span> This is one method of burning a disc. (credit: 1001slide / Getty Images)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>We noted earlier this week that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/08/apples-venerable-superdrive-dvd-burner-may-finally-be-fading-away/">time seems to have run out</a> for Apple's venerable SuperDrive, which was the last (OEM) option available for folks who still needed to read or create optical media on modern Macs. Andrew's write-up got me thinking: When was the last time any Ars staffers actually burned an optical disc?</p>
<h3>Lee Hutchinson, Senior Technology Editor</h3>
<p>It used to be one of the most common tasks I'd do with a computer. As a child of the '90s, my college years were spent filling and then lugging around <a href="https://mashable.com/article/cd-binders">giant binders stuffed with home-burned CDs</a> in my car to make sure I had exactly the right music on hand for any possible eventuality. The discs in these binders were all labeled with names like "METAL MIX XVIII" and "ULTRA MIX IV" and "MY MIX XIX," and part of the fun was trying to remember which songs I'd put on which disc. (There was always a bit of danger that I'd put on "CAR RIDE JAMS XV" to set the mood for a Friday night trip to the movies with all the boys, but I <em>should</em> have popped on "CAR RIDE JAMS XIV" because "CAR RIDE JAMS XV" opens with Britney Spears' "Lucky"—look, it's a <em>good song</em>, and she <em>cries</em> in her <em>lonely heart</em>, OK?!—thus setting the stage for an evening of ridicule. Those were just the kinds of risks we took back in those ancient days.)</p>
<p>It took a while to try to figure out what the very last time I burned a disc was, but I've narrowed it down to two possibilities. The first (and less likely) option is that the last disc I burned was a Windows 7 install disc because I've had a Windows 7 install disc sitting in a paper envelope on my shelf for so long that I can't remember how it got there. The label is in my handwriting, and it has a CD key written on it. Some quick searching shows I have the same CD key stored in 1Password with an "MSDN/Technet" label on it, which means I probably downloaded the image from good ol' <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_TechNet">TechNet</a>, to which I maintained an active subscription for years until MS finally <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/07/microsoft-killing-off-technet-subscriptions/">killed the affordable version</a>.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042118#p3">Read 23 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042118&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/staff/2024/08/ars-asks-what-was-the-last-cd-or-dvd-you-burned/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>320</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>One startup’s plan to fix AI’s “shoplifting” problem</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042108</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/08/one-startups-plan-to-fix-ais-shoplifting-problem/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[WIRED]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 13:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copyright]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LLMs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042108</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Algorithm will identify sources used by generative AI, compensate them for use.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/billgross-800x534.jpg" alt="One startup’s plan to fix AI’s “shoplifting” problem">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/billgross.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="1494" data-width="2240">Enlarge</a> (credit: Bloomberg via Getty)</p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>Bill Gross <a href="https://slate.com/business/2013/10/googles-big-break-how-bill-gross-goto-com-inspired-the-adwords-business-model.html">made his name</a> in the tech world <a href="https://www.wired.com/1999/09/idealab/">in the 1990s</a>, when he came up with a novel way for search engines to make money on advertising. Under his pricing scheme, advertisers would pay when people clicked on their ads. Now, the “pay-per-click” guy has founded a startup called ProRata, which has an audacious, possibly pie-in-the-sky business model: “AI pay-per-use.”</p>
<p>Gross, who is CEO of the Pasadena, California, company, doesn’t mince words about the generative AI industry. “It’s stealing,” he says. “They’re shoplifting and laundering the world’s knowledge to their benefit.”</p>
<p>AI companies often argue that they need vast troves of data to create cutting-edge generative tools and that scraping data from the Internet, whether it’s text from websites, video or captions from YouTube, or books pilfered from pirate libraries, is legally allowed. Gross doesn’t buy that argument. “I think it’s bullshit,” he says.</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042108#p3">Read 14 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042108&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/08/one-startups-plan-to-fix-ais-shoplifting-problem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>84</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>512-bit RSA key in home energy system gives control of “virtual power plant”</title>
		<link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042026</link>
					<comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/08/home-energy-system-gives-researcher-control-of-virtual-power-plant/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 13:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RSA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It took $70 and 24 hours for Ryan Castellucci to gain access to 200 MW of capacity.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="rss-wrap">
<figure class="intro-image intro-left">
  <img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/home-energy-management-system-800x500.jpg" alt="512-bit RSA key in home energy system gives control of “virtual power plant”">
      <p class="caption" style="font-size:0.8em"><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/home-energy-management-system.jpg" class="enlarge-link" data-height="625" data-width="1000">Enlarge</a> </p>  </figure>






<div><a name="page-1"></a></div>
<p>When Ryan Castellucci recently acquired solar panels and a battery storage system for their home just outside of London, they were drawn to the ability to use an open source dashboard to monitor and control the flow of electricity being generated. Instead, they gained much, much more—some 200 megawatts of programmable capacity to charge or discharge to the grid at will. That’s enough energy to power roughly 40,000 homes.</p>
<p>Castellucci, whose pronouns are they/them, acquired this remarkable control after gaining access to the administrative account for GivEnergy, the UK-based energy management provider who supplied the systems. In addition to the control over an estimated 60,000 installed systems, the admin account—which amounts to root control of the company's cloud-connected products—also made it possible for them to enumerate names, email addresses, usernames, phone numbers, and addresses of all other GivEnergy customers (something the researcher didn't actually do).</p>
<p>“My plan is to set up<a href="https://www.home-assistant.io/"> Home Assistant</a> and integrate it with that, but in the meantime, I decided to let it talk to the cloud,” Castellucci <a href="https://rya.nc/vpp-hack.html">wrote Thursday</a>, referring to the recently installed gear. “I set up some scheduled charging, then started experimenting with the API. The next evening, I had control over a<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_power_plant"> virtual power plant</a> comprised of tens of thousands of grid connected batteries.”</p></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042026#p3">Read 16 remaining paragraphs</a> | <a href="https://arstechnica.com/?p=2042026&comments=1">Comments</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://arstechnica.com/security/2024/08/home-energy-system-gives-researcher-control-of-virtual-power-plant/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>104</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>