<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Ars Technica - All content</title>
    <atom:link href="https://arstechnica.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
    <description>All Ars Technica stories</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:15:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
      hourly    </sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
      1    </sy:updateFrequency>
    
<image>
	<url>https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/cropped-ars-logo-512_480-60x60.png</url>
	<title>Ars Technica</title>
	<link>https://arstechnica.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
      <item>
        <title>The CDC buried a measles forecast that stressed the need for vaccinations</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/the-cdc-buried-a-measles-forecast-that-stressed-the-need-for-vaccinations/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/the-cdc-buried-a-measles-forecast-that-stressed-the-need-for-vaccinations/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Patricia Callahan, ProPublica]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 10:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[measles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[measles anti-vaccine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[measles outbreak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rfk jr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/the-cdc-buried-a-measles-forecast-that-stressed-the-need-for-vaccinations/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[The move is a sign that the public health agency may be falling in line under RFK Jr.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p><em>ProPublica is a Pulitzer Prize-winning investigative newsroom. Sign up for <a href="https://www.propublica.org/newsletters/the-big-story?source=reprint&amp;placement=top-note">The Big Story newsletter</a> to receive stories like this one in your inbox</em>.</p>
<div>
<p>Leaders at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention ordered staff this week not to release their experts’ assessment that found the risk of catching measles is high in areas near outbreaks where vaccination rates are lagging, according to internal records reviewed by ProPublica.</p>
<p>In an aborted plan to roll out the news, the agency would have emphasized the importance of vaccinating people against the highly contagious and potentially deadly disease that has spread to 19 states, the records show.</p>
<p>A CDC spokesperson told ProPublica in a written statement that the agency decided against releasing the assessment “because it does not say anything that the public doesn’t already know.” She added that the CDC continues to recommend vaccines as “the best way to protect against measles.”</p>
<p>But what the nation’s top public health agency said next shows a shift in its long-standing messaging about vaccines, a sign that it may be falling in line under Health and Human Services Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr., a longtime critic of vaccines:</p>
<p>“The decision to vaccinate is a personal one,” the statement said, echoing a line from a <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/opinion/robert-f-kennedy-jr-measles-outbreak-call-action-all-us">column Kennedy wrote</a> for the Fox News website. “People should consult with their healthcare provider to understand their options to get a vaccine and should be informed about the potential risks and benefits associated with vaccines.”</p>
<p>ProPublica shared the new CDC statement about personal choice and risk with Jennifer Nuzzo, director of the Pandemic Center at Brown University School of Public Health. To her, the shift in messaging, and the squelching of this routine announcement, is alarming.</p>
<p>“I’m a bit stunned by that language,” Nuzzo said. “No vaccine is without risk, but that makes it sound like it’s a very active coin toss of a decision. We’ve already had more cases of measles in 2025 than we had in 2024, and it’s spread to multiple states. It is not a coin toss at this point.”</p>
<p>For many years, the CDC hasn’t minced words on vaccines. It <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/partners/vaccinate-with-confidence.html">promoted them with confidence</a>. One campaign was called “<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/flu/spotlights/2022-2023/ad-council-flu-campaign.htm">Get My Flu Shot</a>.” The agency’s website <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines-children/hcp/conversation-tips/index.html">told medical providers</a> they play a critical role in helping parents choose vaccines for their children: “Instead of saying ‘What do you want to do about shots?,’ say ‘Your child needs three shots today.’”</p>
<p>Nuzzo wishes the CDC’s forecasters would put out more details of their data and evidence on the spread of measles, not less. “The growing scale and severity of this measles outbreak and the urgent need for more data to guide the response underscores why we need a fully staffed and functional CDC and more resources for state and local health departments,” she said.</p>
<p>Kennedy’s agency oversees the CDC and on Thursday announced it was poised to eliminate 2,400 jobs there.</p>
<p>When asked what role, if any, Kennedy played in the decision to not release the risk assessment, HHS’s communications director said the aborted announcement “was part of an ongoing process to improve communication processes—nothing more, nothing less.” The CDC, he reiterated, continues to recommend vaccination “as the best way to protect against measles.”</p>
<p>“Secretary Kennedy believes that the decision to vaccinate is a personal one and that people should consult with their healthcare provider to understand their options to get a vaccine,” Andrew G. Nixon said. “It is important that the American people have radical transparency and be informed to make personal healthcare decisions.”</p>
<p>Responding to questions about criticism of the decision among some CDC staff, Nixon wrote, “Some individuals at the CDC seem more interested in protecting their own status or agenda rather than aligning with this Administration and the true mission of public health.”</p>
<p>The CDC’s risk assessment was carried out by its Center for Forecasting and Outbreak Analytics, which relied, in part, on new disease data from the outbreak in Texas. The CDC created the center to address a major shortcoming laid bare during the COVID-19 pandemic. It functions like a National Weather Service for infectious diseases, harnessing data and expertise to predict the course of outbreaks like a meteorologist warns of storms.</p>
<p>Other risk assessments by the center have been posted by the CDC even though their conclusions might seem obvious.</p>
<p>In late February, for example, <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/cfa-qualitative-assessments/php/data-research/h5-risk-assessment.html">forecasters analyzing the spread of H5N1</a> bird flu said people who come “in contact with potentially infected animals or contaminated surfaces or fluids” faced a moderate to high risk of contracting the disease. The risk to the general US population, they said, was low.</p>
<p>In the case of the measles assessment, modelers at the center determined the risk of the disease for the general public in the US is low, but they found the risk is high in communities with low vaccination rates that are near outbreaks or share close social ties to those areas with outbreaks. The CDC had moderate confidence in the assessment, according to an internal Q&amp;A that explained the findings. The agency, it said, lacks detailed data about the onset of the illness for all patients in West Texas and is still learning about the vaccination rates in affected communities as well as travel and social contact among those infected. (The H5N1 assessment was also made with moderate confidence.)</p>
<p>The internal plan to roll out the news of the forecast called for the expert physician who’s leading the CDC’s response to measles to be the chief spokesperson answering questions. “It is important to note that at local levels, vaccine coverage rates may vary considerably, and pockets of unvaccinated people can exist even in areas with high vaccination coverage overall,” the plan said. “The best way to protect against measles is to get the measles, mumps, and rubella (MMR) vaccine.”</p>
<p>This week, though, as the number of confirmed cases rose to 483, more than 30 agency staff were told in an email that after a discussion in the CDC director’s office, “leadership does not want to pursue putting this on the website.”</p>
<p>The cancellation was “not normal at all,” said a CDC staff member who spoke anonymously for fear of reprisal with layoffs looming. “I’ve never seen a rollout plan that was canceled at that far along in the process.”</p>
<p>Anxiety among CDC staff has been building over whether the agency will bend its public health messages to match those of Kennedy, a lawyer who founded an anti-vaccine group and referred clients to a law firm suing a vaccine manufacturer.</p>
<p>During Kennedy’s first week on the job, HHS halted the CDC campaign that encouraged people to get flu shots during a ferocious flu season. On the night that the Trump administration began firing probationary employees across the federal government, some key CDC flu webpages were taken down. Remnants of some of the campaign webpages were restored after <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/shots-health-news/2025/02/19/nx-s1-5302906/cdc-flu-vaccine-campaign-terminated">NPR reported</a> this.</p>
<p>But some at the agency felt like the new leadership had sent a message loud and clear: When next to nobody was paying attention, long-standing public health messages could be silenced.</p>
<p>On the day in February that the world learned that an unvaccinated <a href="https://perma.cc/R8XT-4XUB">child had died</a> of measles in Texas, the first such death in the U.S. since 2015, the HHS secretary <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2025/02/rfk-jr-minimizes-measles-outbreak-in-texas/">downplayed the seriousness</a> of the outbreak. “We have measles outbreaks every year,” he said at a cabinet meeting with President Donald Trump.</p>
<p>In an interview on Fox News this month, Kennedy championed doctors in Texas who he said were treating measles with a steroid, an antibiotic and cod liver oil, a supplement that is high in vitamin A. “They’re seeing what they describe as almost miraculous and instantaneous recovery from that,” Kennedy said.</p>
<p>As parents near the outbreak in Texas stocked up on vitamin A supplements, doctors there raced to assure parents that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/doctors-push-back-parents-embrace-kennedy-vitamin-texas-measles-outbreak-2025-03-08/">only vaccination, not the vitamin, can prevent measles</a>.</p>
<p>Still, the CDC added <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/measles/hcp/clinical-overview/index.html">an entry on Vitamin A</a> to its measles website for clinicians.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, CNN reported that <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/03/26/health/texas-measles-vitamin-a-toxicity/index.html">several hospitalized children in Lubbock, Texas, had abnormal liver function</a>, a likely sign of toxicity from too much vitamin A.</p>
<p>Texas health officials also said that the Trump administration’s decision to rescind $11 billion in pandemic-related grants across the country <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2025/03/26/texas-measles-public-health-funding-cut/">will hinder their ability to respond</a> to the growing outbreak, according to The Texas Tribune.</p>
<p>Measles is among the most contagious diseases and can be dangerous. About 20 percent of unvaccinated people who get measles wind up in the hospital. And <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/measles/signs-symptoms/index.html">nearly 1 to 3 of every 1,000 children</a> with measles will die from respiratory and neurologic complications. The virus can <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/measles/causes/index.html">linger in the air</a> for two hours after an infected person has left an area, and patients can spread measles before they even know they have it.</p>
<p>This week Amtrak said it was notifying customers that they may have been exposed to the disease this month when a passenger with measles <a href="https://abc7ny.com/post/amtrak-confirms-passenger-measles-traveled-new-york-washington-dc/16085440/">rode one of its trains</a> from New York City to Washington, DC.</p>
</div>
<p><script type="text/javascript" src="https://pixel.propublica.org/pixel.js" async></script></p>
<p> </p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/the-cdc-buried-a-measles-forecast-that-stressed-the-need-for-vaccinations/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/the-cdc-buried-a-measles-forecast-that-stressed-the-need-for-vaccinations/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/GettyImages-2196587890-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/GettyImages-2196587890-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Win McNamee</media:credit><media:text>Robert F. Kennedy Jr., the Secretary of Health and Human Services, testifies during his Senate Finance Committee confirmation hearing at the Dirksen Senate Office Building on January 29, 2025 in Washington, DC.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Elon Musk’s X has a new owner—Elon Musk’s xAI</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/elon-musks-x-has-a-new-owner-elon-musks-xai/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/elon-musks-x-has-a-new-owner-elon-musks-xai/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 23:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elon musk x]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xAI]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/elon-musks-x-has-a-new-owner-elon-musks-xai/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[xAI buys X; deal values social network at $33 billion, $11B less than Musk paid.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk today said he has merged X and xAI in a deal that values the social network formerly known as Twitter at $33 billion. Musk purchased Twitter for $44 billion in 2022.</p>
<p>xAI acquired X "in an all-stock transaction. The combination values xAI at $80 billion and X at $33 billion ($45B less $12B debt)," Musk <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1905731750275510312">wrote on X today</a>.</p>
<p>X and xAI were already collaborating, as xAI's <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/11/elon-musks-new-ai-model-doesnt-shy-from-questions-about-cocaine-and-orgies/">Grok</a> is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/11/elon-musks-new-ai-model-doesnt-shy-from-questions-about-cocaine-and-orgies/">trained</a> on X posts. Grok is made available to X users, with paying subscribers getting higher usage limits and more features.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/elon-musks-x-has-a-new-owner-elon-musks-xai/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/elon-musks-x-has-a-new-owner-elon-musks-xai/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>113</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/xai-1152x648-1743206047.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/xai-500x500-1743206055.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | NurPhoto </media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>New Windows 11 build makes mandatory Microsoft Account sign-in even more mandatory</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/new-windows-11-build-makes-mandatory-microsoft-account-sign-in-even-more-mandatory/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/new-windows-11-build-makes-mandatory-microsoft-account-sign-in-even-more-mandatory/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 23:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11 24h2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows 11 25h2]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/new-windows-11-build-makes-mandatory-microsoft-account-sign-in-even-more-mandatory/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA["Bypassnro" is an easy MS Account workaround for Home and Pro Windows editions.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Microsoft released a new Windows Insider build of Windows 11 to its experimental Dev Channel today, with <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2025/03/28/announcing-windows-11-insider-preview-build-26200-5516-dev-channel/">a fairly extensive batch of new features and tweaks</a>. But the most important one for enthusiasts and PC administrators is buried halfway down the list: This build removes a command prompt script called <code>bypassnro</code>, which up until now has been a relatively easy and reliable way to circumvent the otherwise mandatory Microsoft Account sign-in requirement on new Windows 11 PCs and fresh installs of Windows 11 on existing PCs.</p>
<p>Microsoft's Windows Insider Program lead Amanda Langowski and Principal Product Manager Brandon LeBlanc were clear that this change is considered a feature and not a bug.</p>
<p>"We’re removing the bypassnro.cmd script from the build to enhance security and user experience of Windows 11," Langowski and LeBlanc write in the post. "This change ensures that all users exit setup with internet connectivity and a Microsoft Account."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/new-windows-11-build-makes-mandatory-microsoft-account-sign-in-even-more-mandatory/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/new-windows-11-build-makes-mandatory-microsoft-account-sign-in-even-more-mandatory/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>125</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/win11-laptop-1152x648.jpeg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/win11-laptop-500x500.jpeg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Microsoft</media:credit><media:text>A PC running Windows 11.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Why do LLMs make stuff up? New research peers under the hood.</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/03/why-do-llms-make-stuff-up-new-research-peers-under-the-hood/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/03/why-do-llms-make-stuff-up-new-research-peers-under-the-hood/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 22:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/03/why-do-llms-make-stuff-up-new-research-peers-under-the-hood/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Claude's faulty "known entity" neurons sometime override its "don't answer" circuitry.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>One of the most frustrating things about using a large language model is dealing with <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2023/04/why-ai-chatbots-are-the-ultimate-bs-machines-and-how-people-hope-to-fix-them/">its tendency to confabulate information</a>, hallucinating answers that are not supported by its training data. From a human perspective, it can be hard to understand why these models don't simply say "I don't know" instead of making up some plausible-sounding nonsense.</p>
<p>Now, new research from Anthropic is exposing at least some of the inner neural network "circuitry" that helps an LLM decide when to take a stab at a (perhaps hallucinated) response versus when to refuse an answer in the first place. While human understanding of this internal LLM "decision" process is still rough, this kind of research could lead to better overall solutions for the AI confabulation problem.</p>
<h2>When a “known entity” isn't</h2>
<p>In <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2024/05/heres-whats-really-going-on-inside-an-llms-neural-network/">a groundbreaking paper last May</a>, Anthropic used a system of sparse auto-encoders to help illuminate the groups of artificial neurons that are activated when the Claude LLM encounters internal concepts ranging from "Golden Gate Bridge" to "programming errors" (Anthropic calls these groupings "features," as we will in the remainder of this piece). Anthropic's <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/research/tracing-thoughts-language-model">newly published research this week</a> expands on that previous work by tracing how these features can affect other neuron groups that represent computational decision "circuits" Claude follows in crafting its response.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/03/why-do-llms-make-stuff-up-new-research-peers-under-the-hood/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/03/why-do-llms-make-stuff-up-new-research-peers-under-the-hood/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>50</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1479183112-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1479183112-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Which of those boxes represents the "I don't know" part of Claude's digital "brain"?</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Beyond RGB: A new image file format efficiently stores invisible light data</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/scientists-are-storing-light-we-cannot-see-in-formats-meant-for-human-eyes/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/scientists-are-storing-light-we-cannot-see-in-formats-meant-for-human-eyes/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Benj Edwards]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 22:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[image compression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[image formats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JPEG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jpeg xl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multispectrum images]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spectral imaging]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/scientists-are-storing-light-we-cannot-see-in-formats-meant-for-human-eyes/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[New Spectral JPEG XL compression reduces file sizes, making spectral imaging more practical.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Imagine working with special cameras that capture light your eyes can't even see—ultraviolet rays that cause sunburn, infrared heat signatures that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2024/09/new-multispectral-analysis-of-voynich-manuscript-reveals-hidden-details/">reveal hidden writing</a>, or specific wavelengths that plants use for photosynthesis. Or perhaps using a special camera designed to distinguish the subtle visible differences that make paint colors appear just right under specific lighting. Scientists and engineers do this every day, and they're drowning in the resulting data.</p>
<p>A new compression format called <a href="https://jcgt.org/published/0014/01/04/">Spectral JPEG XL</a> might finally solve this growing problem in scientific visualization and computer graphics. Researchers Alban Fichet and Christoph Peters of Intel Corporation detailed the format in a <a href="https://jcgt.org/published/0014/01/04/">recent paper</a> published in the Journal of Computer Graphics Techniques (JCGT). It tackles a serious bottleneck for industries working with these specialized images. These spectral files can contain 30, 100, or more data points per pixel, causing file sizes to balloon into multi-gigabyte territory—making them unwieldy to store and analyze.</p>
<p>When we think of digital images, we typically imagine files that store just three colors: red, green, and blue (RGB). This works well for everyday photos, but capturing the true color and behavior of light requires much more detail. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spectral_imaging">Spectral images</a> aim for this higher fidelity by recording light's intensity not just in broad RGB categories, but across dozens or even hundreds of narrow, specific wavelength bands. This detailed information primarily spans the visible spectrum and often extends into near-infrared and near-ultraviolet regions crucial for simulating how materials interact with light accurately.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/scientists-are-storing-light-we-cannot-see-in-formats-meant-for-human-eyes/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/scientists-are-storing-light-we-cannot-see-in-formats-meant-for-human-eyes/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/spectral_prisms-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/spectral_prisms-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>MirageC via Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Report: US scientists lost $3 billion in NIH grants since Trump took office</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/report-us-scientists-lost-3-billion-in-nih-grants-since-trump-took-office/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/report-us-scientists-lost-3-billion-in-nih-grants-since-trump-took-office/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Beth Mole]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 21:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NIH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/report-us-scientists-lost-3-billion-in-nih-grants-since-trump-took-office/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Scientist warn pipeline of lifesaving discoveries and younger scientists is drying up.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Since Trump took office on January 20, research funding from the National Institutes of Health has plummeted by more than $3 billion compared with the pace of funding in 2024, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/03/28/trump-administration-science-research-cuts/">according to an analysis by The Washington Post</a>.</p>
<p>By this time in March 2024, the NIH had awarded US researchers a total of $1.027 billion for new grants or competitive grant renewals. This year, the figure currently stands at about $400 million. Likewise, funding for renewals of existing grants without competition reached $4.5 billion by this time last year, but has only hit $2 billion this year. Together, this slowdown amounts to a 60 percent drop in grant support for a wide variety of research—from studies on cancer treatments, diabetes, Alzheimer's, vaccines, mental health, transgender health, and more.</p>
<p>The NIH is the primary source of funding for biomedical research in the US. NIH grants support more than 300,000 scientists at more than 2,500 universities, medical schools, and other research organizations across all 50 states.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/report-us-scientists-lost-3-billion-in-nih-grants-since-trump-took-office/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/03/report-us-scientists-lost-3-billion-in-nih-grants-since-trump-took-office/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>74</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1143355093-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1143355093-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty | Mint Images</media:credit><media:text>An empty research lab.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Oracle has reportedly suffered 2 separate breaches exposing thousands of customers‘ PII</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/oracle-is-mum-on-reports-it-has-experienced-2-separate-data-breaches/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/oracle-is-mum-on-reports-it-has-experienced-2-separate-data-breaches/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data breaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oracle health]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/oracle-is-mum-on-reports-it-has-experienced-2-separate-data-breaches/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Alleged breaches affect Oracle Cloud and Oracle Health.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Oracle isn’t commenting on recent reports that it has experienced two separate data breaches that have exposed sensitive personal information belonging to thousands of its customers.</p>
<p>The most recent data breach report, <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/oracle-health-breach-compromises-patient-data-at-us-hospitals/">published Friday</a> by Bleeping Computer, said that Oracle Health—a health care software-as-a-service business the company acquired in 2022—had learned in February that a threat actor accessed one of its servers and made off with patient data from US hospitals. Bleeping Computer said Oracle Health customers have received breach notifications that were printed on plain paper rather than official Oracle letterhead and were signed by Seema Verma, the executive vice president &amp; GM of Oracle Health.</p>
<p>The other report of a data breach occurred eight days ago, when an anonymous person using the handle rose87168 published a sampling of what they said were 6 million records of authentication data belonging to Oracle Cloud customers. Rose87168 <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/oracle-denies-data-breach-after-hacker-claims-theft-of-6-million-data-records/">told Bleeping Computer</a> that they had acquired the data a little more than a month earlier after exploiting a vulnerability that gave access to an Oracle Cloud server.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/oracle-is-mum-on-reports-it-has-experienced-2-separate-data-breaches/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/oracle-is-mum-on-reports-it-has-experienced-2-separate-data-breaches/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GettyImages-515609014-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/GettyImages-515609014-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Michael Short/Bloomberg via Getty Images</media:credit><media:text>Signage stands at the Oracle Corp. headquarters campus in Redwood City, California, on March 14, 2016.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Google discontinues Nest Protect smoke alarm and Nest x Yale lock</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-discontinues-nest-protect-smoke-alarm-and-nest-x-yale-lock/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-discontinues-nest-protect-smoke-alarm-and-nest-x-yale-lock/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart home]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-discontinues-nest-protect-smoke-alarm-and-nest-x-yale-lock/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Google continues backing away from smart home hardware.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Google acquired Nest in 2014 for a whopping $3.4 billion but seems increasingly uninterested in making smart home hardware. The company has <a href="https://www.googlenestcommunity.com/t5/Blog/Upcoming-changes-to-our-device-portfolio-featuring-Nest-Protect-and-Nest-x/ba-p/708064">just announced</a> two of its home gadgets will be discontinued, one of which is quite popular. The Nest Protect smoke and carbon monoxide detector is a common fixture in homes, but Google says it has stopped manufacturing it. The less popular Nest x Yale smart lock is also getting the ax. There are replacements coming, but Google won't be making them.</p>
<p>Nest launched the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2016/02/smoke-alarms-get-smart-four-months-with-the-nest-protect/">2nd gen Protect</a> a year before it became part of Google. Like all smoke detectors, the Nest Protect comes with an expiration date. You're supposed to swap them out every 10 years, so some Nest users are already there. You will have to hurry if you want a new Protect. While they're in stock for the moment, Google won't manufacture any more. It's on sale for $119 on the Google Store for the time being.</p>
<img width="1000" height="682" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/nestxyale.jpg" class="fullwidth full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/nestxyale.jpg 1000w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/nestxyale-640x436.jpg 640w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/nestxyale-768x524.jpg 768w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/nestxyale-980x668.jpg 980w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px">
      The Nest x Yale lock.
        Credit:
          Google
      
<p>Likewise, Google is done with the Nest x Yale smart lock, which it launched in 2018 to complement the Nest Secure home security system. This device requires a Thread-enabled hub, a role the Nest Secure served quite well. Now, you need a $70 Nest Connect to control this lock remotely. If you still want to grab the Nest x Yale smart lock, it's on sale for $229 while supplies last.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-discontinues-nest-protect-smoke-alarm-and-nest-x-yale-lock/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-discontinues-nest-protect-smoke-alarm-and-nest-x-yale-lock/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/nest-protect-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/nest-protect-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Google</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Ex-FCC chairs from both parties say CBS news distortion investigation is bogus</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ex-fcc-chairs-from-both-parties-say-cbs-news-distortion-investigation-is-bogus/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ex-fcc-chairs-from-both-parties-say-cbs-news-distortion-investigation-is-bogus/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 18:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fcc chairman brendan carr]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ex-fcc-chairs-from-both-parties-say-cbs-news-distortion-investigation-is-bogus/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[CBS probe "unprecedented," say chairs who served under George H.W. Bush and Obama.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>The Federal Communications Commission's news distortion investigation into CBS drew a public rebuke from a bipartisan group of five former FCC commissioners, including two former chairmen.</p>
<p>The group criticizing current Chairman Brendan Carr includes Republican Alfred Sikes, the FCC chair from 1989 to 1993, and Democrat Tom Wheeler, the FCC chair from 2013 to 2017. They were joined by Republican Rachelle Chong, Democrat Ervin Duggan, and Democrat Gloria Tristani, all former commissioners.</p>
<p>"<a href="https://www.fcc.gov/ecfs/document/1032657330681/1">These comments</a> are submitted to emphasize the unprecedented nature of this news distortion proceeding, and to express our strong concern that the Federal Communications Commission may be seeking to censor the news media in a manner antithetical to the First Amendment," the former chairs and commissioners told the FCC in a filing this week.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ex-fcc-chairs-from-both-parties-say-cbs-news-distortion-investigation-is-bogus/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ex-fcc-chairs-from-both-parties-say-cbs-news-distortion-investigation-is-bogus/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>89</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/tom-wheeler-1152x648-1743186499.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/tom-wheeler-500x500-1743186509.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | Bill Clark </media:credit><media:text>Tom Wheeler, then-Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, testifies at a Senate committee hearing on September 15, 2016. </media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>NASA to put Starliner’s thrusters through an extensive workout before next launch</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/nasa-to-put-starliners-thrusters-through-an-extensive-workout-before-next-launch/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/nasa-to-put-starliners-thrusters-through-an-extensive-workout-before-next-launch/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Eric Berger]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 18:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starliner]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/nasa-to-put-starliners-thrusters-through-an-extensive-workout-before-next-launch/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA["We’ll continue to work through certification toward the end of this year."]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>More than half a year after an empty Starliner spacecraft safely landed in a New Mexico desert, NASA and Boeing still have not decided whether the vehicle's next flight will carry any astronauts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/blogs/commercialcrew/2025/03/27/nasa-boeing-prepare-for-starliner-testing/">In an update this week</a>, the US space agency said it is still working through the process to certify Starliner for human missions. Whether it carries cargo or humans, Starliner's next flight will not occur until late this year or, more likely, sometime in 2026.</p>
<p>Two things stand out in the new information provided by NASA. First, there remains a lot of work left to do this year before Starliner will fly again, including extensive testing of the vehicle's propulsion system. And secondly, it is becoming clear that Starliner will only ever fly a handful of missions to the space station, if that, before the orbiting laboratory is retired.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/nasa-to-put-starliners-thrusters-through-an-extensive-workout-before-next-launch/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/nasa-to-put-starliners-thrusters-through-an-extensive-workout-before-next-launch/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/52096151366_1f97fed2cc_k-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/52096151366_1f97fed2cc_k-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>NASA</media:credit><media:text>Boeing's Starliner spacecraft undocks from the International Space Station at the conclusion of an unpiloted test flight in May 2022.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Google solves its mysterious Pixel problem, announces 9a launch date</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-confirms-pixel-9a-launch-for-april-10/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-confirms-pixel-9a-launch-for-april-10/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 16:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Pixel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pixel 9a]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-confirms-pixel-9a-launch-for-april-10/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Google has sorted out its Pixel problems and will begin the 9a rollout on April 10.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Google <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/the-pixel-9a-arrives-this-month-for-499-with-streamlined-design-and-larger-battery/">revealed the Pixel 9a</a> last week, but its release plans were put on hold by a mysterious "component quality issue." Whatever that was, it's been worked out. Google now says its new budget smartphone will arrive as soon as April 10. The date varies by market, but the wait is almost over.</p>
<p>The first wave of 9a releases on April 10 will include the US, Canada, and the UK. On April 14, the Pixel 9a will arrive in Europe, launching in Germany, Spain, Italy, Ireland, France, Norway, Denmark, Sweden, Netherlands, Belgium, Austria, Portugal, Switzerland, Poland, Czechia, Romania, Hungary, Slovenia, Slovakia, Lithuania, Estonia, Latvia, and Finland. On April 16, the phone will come to Australia, India, Singapore, Taiwan, and Malaysia.</p>
<p>You may think that takes care of Google's launch commitments, but no—Japan still has no official launch date. That's a bit strange, as Japan is not a new addition to Google's list of supported regions. It's unclear if this has anything to do with the previous component issue. Google says only that the Japanese launch will happen "soon." Its statements about the delayed release were also vague, with representatives noting that the cause was a "passive component."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-confirms-pixel-9a-launch-for-april-10/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/google-confirms-pixel-9a-launch-for-april-10/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Pixel-9a_1-copy-1152x648-1743179341.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Pixel-9a_1-copy-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Google</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Corning’s new ceramic glass might save your next phone from disaster</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/cornings-new-apple-like-ceramic-glass-might-save-your-next-phone-from-disaster/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/cornings-new-apple-like-ceramic-glass-might-save-your-next-phone-from-disaster/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Ryan Whitwam]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 16:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/cornings-new-apple-like-ceramic-glass-might-save-your-next-phone-from-disaster/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Gorilla Glass Ceramic will appear on its first phone in the coming months. ]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>As a society, we have decided to carry expensive electronic devices that are made out of glass. It's a real problem, especially if you have butter fingers. Gorilla Glass maker Corning has announced a new material that might help save the day the next time you drop a phone. The company claims its latest Gorilla Glass Ceramic can withstand drops that would shatter lesser materials.</p>
<p>As the name implies, Corning's new glass incorporates ceramic components to improve strength compared to other types of hardened glass. Corning has offered a bit of data to support this claim. In its <a href="https://www.corning.com/microsites/csm/gorillaglass/PI_Sheets/CGG_Gorilla%20Glass%20Ceramic_PI%20Sheet.pdf">lab tests</a> (PDF), Gorilla Glass Ceramic withstood 10 drops from one meter onto surfaces that closely resemble asphalt. Why Corning does not use real asphalt for this test is unclear. Regardless, <a href="https://www.corning.com/worldwide/en/about-us/news-events/news-releases/2025/03/corning-launches-corning-gorilla-glass-ceramic-expanding-renowned-portfolio-of-tough-cover-materials.html">the company says</a> an unspecified "competitive" type of aluminosilicate glass would typically fail on the first drop.</p>
<p>Chemically strengthened glass has been a key component in the proliferation of smartphones across the world. Since the company provided the glass for that first iPhone back in 2007, it has made glass for more than 7 billion devices. That makes Corning the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/11/corning-faces-antitrust-actions-for-its-gorilla-glass-dominance/">largest glass supplier in the mobile industry</a>, but it does face increasing competition in the budget and midrange segments.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/cornings-new-apple-like-ceramic-glass-might-save-your-next-phone-from-disaster/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/cornings-new-apple-like-ceramic-glass-might-save-your-next-phone-from-disaster/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>123</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/corning-glass-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/corning-glass-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Corning</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Trump annoyed the Smithsonian isn’t promoting discredited racial ideas</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/trump-annoyed-the-smithsonian-isnt-promoting-discredited-racial-ideas/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/trump-annoyed-the-smithsonian-isnt-promoting-discredited-racial-ideas/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[John Timmer]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 15:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eugenics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scientific racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smithsonian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/trump-annoyed-the-smithsonian-isnt-promoting-discredited-racial-ideas/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[New executive order slams museum for recognizing "race is not a biological reality."]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>On Thursday, the Trump administration issued an executive order that took aim at one of the US's foremost cultural and scientific institutions: the Smithsonian. Upset by exhibits that reference the role of racism, sexism, and more in the nation's complicated past, the order tasks the vice president and a former insurance lawyer (?) with ensuring that the Smithsonian Institution is a "symbol of inspiration and American greatness"—a command that specifically includes the National Zoo.</p>
<p>But in the process of airing the administration's grievances, the document specifically calls out a Smithsonian display for accurately describing our current scientific understanding of race. That raises the prospect that the vice president will ultimately demand that the Smithsonian display scientifically inaccurate information.</p>
<h2>Grievance vs. science</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/restoring-truth-and-sanity-to-american-history/">executive order</a>, entitled "Restoring Truth And Sanity To American History," is filled with what has become a standard grievance: the accusation that, by recognizing the many cases where the US has not lived up to its founding ideals, institutions are attempting to "rewrite our nation's history." It specifically calls out discussions of historic racism, sexism, and oppression as undercutting the US's "unparalleled legacy of advancing liberty, individual rights, and human happiness."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/trump-annoyed-the-smithsonian-isnt-promoting-discredited-racial-ideas/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/03/trump-annoyed-the-smithsonian-isnt-promoting-discredited-racial-ideas/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>313</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2163809851-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2163809851-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Douglas Rissing</media:credit><media:text>The exterior of the Smithsonian's Natural History Museum.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>What to make of Nintendo’s mention of new “Switch 2 Edition games”</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/nintendo-hints-at-enhanced-switch-2-edition-games-for-new-console/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/nintendo-hints-at-enhanced-switch-2-edition-games-for-new-console/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Kyle Orland]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 15:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/nintendo-hints-at-enhanced-switch-2-edition-games-for-new-console/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Fine print suggests visual upgrades for original Switch games on new hardware.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>When Nintendo <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/01/its-official-take-a-first-look-at-the-switch-2/">finally officially revealed the Switch 2</a> in January, one of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/01/all-the-things-nintendo-didnt-tell-us-about-the-switch-2/">our major unanswered questions</a> concerned whether games designed for the original Switch would see some form of visual or performance enhancement when running on <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/nintendo-confirms-switch-2-will-play-original-switch-games/">the backward-compatible Switch 2</a>. Now, Nintendo-watchers are pointing to a fleeting mention of "Switch 2 Edition games" as a major hint that such enhancements are in the works for at least some original Switch games.</p>
<p>The completely new reference to "Switch 2 Edition games" comes from <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/gaming-systems/virtual-game-cards/">a Nintendo webpage</a> discussing <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/nintendos-new-system-for-sharing-digital-switch-games-explained/">yesterday's newly announced Virtual Game Cards</a> digital lending feature. In the fine print at the bottom of that page, Nintendo notes that "Nintendo Switch 2 exclusive games <em>and Nintendo Switch 2 Edition games</em> can only be loaded on a Nintendo Switch 2 system [emphasis added]."</p>
<p>The specific wording differentiating these "Switch 2 Edition" games from "Switch 2 exclusives" suggests a new category of game that is compatible with the original Switch but able to run with enhancements on the Switch 2. But it's currently unclear what Switch games will get "Switch 2 Edition" releases or how much developer work (if any) will be needed to create those new versions.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/nintendo-hints-at-enhanced-switch-2-edition-games-for-new-console/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/nintendo-hints-at-enhanced-switch-2-edition-games-for-new-console/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/switch2-new-1152x648.png" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/switch2-new-500x500.png" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Nintendo</media:credit><media:text>Is that just the "Switch 2 Edition" of  a cross-generational &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart 9&lt;/em&gt; we're seeing?</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Gran Turismo 7 expands its use of AI/ML-trained NPCs with good effect</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/gran-turismo-7-gets-an-npc-upgrade-with-improved-gt-sophy-ai/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/gran-turismo-7-gets-an-npc-upgrade-with-improved-gt-sophy-ai/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Jonathan M. Gitlin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 15:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gran turismo 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GT Sophy]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/gran-turismo-7-gets-an-npc-upgrade-with-improved-gt-sophy-ai/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[First, Sony AI made an unbeatable AI driver; now, it's retrained it to be a good NPC.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>In 2022, a team of researchers at Sony AI sat down and made an AI agent <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2022/02/sony-trains-superhuman-ai-to-race-in-gran-turismo/">that was nearly unbeatable</a> at the racing game <em>Gran Turismo 7</em>. More than just car control, the agent, called GT Sophy, also had to learn racing tactics and strategies—and even etiquette. Up against the world's best human players, Sophy beat the humans by 104 races to 52 in a match in 2021.</p>
<p>Since then, Sony AI and Polyphony Digital have been hard at work retraining it from being able to dominate the world's best with ease into <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/02/almost-unbeatable-ai-comes-to-gran-turismo-7/">something</a> that's more fun for the rest of us to compete against. The latest refinement is GT Sophy 2.1, which appeared as part of <em>GT7</em>'s latest update yesterday. It's now enabled at more tracks, and you can finally set up custom races at those tracks using the better AI.</p>
<p>“Since we first introduced GT Sophy three years ago, we have worked closely with [Polyphony Digital] to explore how AI can enhance gameplay and create more dynamic and fun racing experiences for players of all skill levels," said Kaushik Subramanian, senior staff research scientist at Sony AI. "With GT Sophy 2.1, we are giving players more control than ever over their interactions with GT Sophy by allowing them to fine-tune gameplay, experiment with new strategies, and advance their racing skills."</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/gran-turismo-7-gets-an-npc-upgrade-with-improved-gt-sophy-ai/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/gran-turismo-7-gets-an-npc-upgrade-with-improved-gt-sophy-ai/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GT_Sophy_01-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GT_Sophy_01-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Polyphony Digital</media:credit><media:text>Emojis above the cars give you a clue as to the disposition of that particular AI agent at the time.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Tel‘Aran’Rhiod at last—the Wheel of Time reveals the world of dreams</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/03/the-wheel-of-time-takes-us-to-the-world-of-dreams-and-beyond-in-episode-five/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/03/the-wheel-of-time-takes-us-to-the-world-of-dreams-and-beyond-in-episode-five/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Andrew Cunningham & Lee Hutchinson]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 13:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv recap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wheel of time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wheel of time season 3]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/03/the-wheel-of-time-takes-us-to-the-world-of-dreams-and-beyond-in-episode-five/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Perrin broods, Sea Folk sail, and Aes Sedai plot as we jump into episode five.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Andrew Cunningham and Lee Hutchinson have spent decades of their lives with Robert Jordan and Brandon Sanderson's <em>Wheel of Time</em> books, and they previously brought that knowledge to bear as they <a href="https://arstechnica.com/series/the-wheel-of-time-season-one/">recapped each first season episode</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/series/the-wheel-of-time-season-two/">second season episode</a> of Amazon's <em>WoT</em> TV series. Now we're back in the saddle for season 3—along with insights, jokes, and the occasional wild theory.</p>
<p>These recaps won't cover every element of every episode, but they will contain major spoilers for the show and the book series. We'll do our best to not spoil major future events from the books, but there's always the danger that something might slip out. <strong>If you want to stay completely unspoiled and haven't read the books, these recaps aren't for you</strong>.</p>
<p>New episodes of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/video/detail/B0D2VH77R1"><em>The Wheel of Time</em> season three</a> will be posted for <a href="https://amzn.to/3Es0B7q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon Prime</a> subscribers every Thursday. This write-up covers episode five, "Tel'Aran'Rhiod," which was released on March 27.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/03/the-wheel-of-time-takes-us-to-the-world-of-dreams-and-beyond-in-episode-five/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/culture/2025/03/the-wheel-of-time-takes-us-to-the-world-of-dreams-and-beyond-in-episode-five/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/wots3e5_00-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/wots3e5_00-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit> Prime/Amazon MGM Studios </media:credit><media:text>Egwene walks the dream.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>EU will go easy with Apple, Facebook punishment to avoid Trump’s wrath</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/eu-will-go-easy-with-apple-facebook-punishment-to-avoid-trumps-wrath/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/eu-will-go-easy-with-apple-facebook-punishment-to-avoid-trumps-wrath/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Barbara Moens and Henry Foy, Financial Times]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndication]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/eu-will-go-easy-with-apple-facebook-punishment-to-avoid-trumps-wrath/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Lawbreaking under DMA to be punished—but not too severely.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>The EU is set to impose minimal fines on Apple and Facebook-owner Meta next week under its Digital Markets Act, as Brussels seeks to avoid escalating tensions with US President Donald Trump.</p>
<p>According to people familiar with the decisions, the iPhone maker is expected to be fined and ordered to revise its App Store rules, following an investigation into whether they prevent app developers from sending consumers to offers outside its platform.</p>
<p>Regulators will also close another investigation into Apple, which was focused on the company’s design of its web browser choice screen without any further sanctions.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/eu-will-go-easy-with-apple-facebook-punishment-to-avoid-trumps-wrath/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/03/eu-will-go-easy-with-apple-facebook-punishment-to-avoid-trumps-wrath/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>106</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/getty-us-eu-flags-data-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/getty-us-eu-flags-data-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | BeeBright</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Gemini hackers can deliver more potent attacks with a helping hand from… Gemini</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/gemini-hackers-can-deliver-more-potent-attacks-with-a-helping-hand-from-gemini/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/gemini-hackers-can-deliver-more-potent-attacks-with-a-helping-hand-from-gemini/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Dan Goodin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biz & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun-tuning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gemini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large language models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LLMs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prompt injections]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/gemini-hackers-can-deliver-more-potent-attacks-with-a-helping-hand-from-gemini/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA[Hacking LLMs has always been more art than science. A new attack on Gemini could change that.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>In the growing canon of AI security, the indirect prompt injection has emerged as the most powerful means for attackers to hack large language models such as OpenAI’s GPT-3 and GPT-4 or Microsoft’s Copilot. By exploiting a model's inability to distinguish between, on the one hand, developer-defined prompts and, on the other, text in external content LLMs interact with, indirect prompt injections are remarkably effective at invoking harmful or otherwise unintended actions. Examples include divulging end users’ confidential contacts or emails and delivering falsified answers that have the potential to corrupt the integrity of important calculations.</p>
<p>Despite the power of prompt injections, attackers face a fundamental challenge in using them: The inner workings of so-called closed-weights models such as GPT, Anthropic’s Claude, and Google’s Gemini are closely held secrets. Developers of such proprietary platforms tightly restrict access to the underlying code and training data that make them work and, in the process, make them black boxes to external users. As a result, devising working prompt injections requires labor- and time-intensive trial and error through redundant manual effort.</p>
<h2>Algorithmically generated hacks</h2>
<p>For the first time, academic researchers have devised a means to create computer-generated prompt injections against Gemini that have much higher success rates than manually crafted ones. The new method abuses fine-tuning, a feature offered by some closed-weights models for training them to work on large amounts of private or specialized data, such as a law firm’s legal case files, patient files or research managed by a medical facility, or architectural blueprints. Google makes its <a href="https://ai.google.dev/gemini-api/docs/model-tuning">fine-tuning for Gemini’s API</a> available free of charge.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/gemini-hackers-can-deliver-more-potent-attacks-with-a-helping-hand-from-gemini/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/03/gemini-hackers-can-deliver-more-potent-attacks-with-a-helping-hand-from-gemini/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/google-gemini-self-hack-hands-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/google-gemini-self-hack-hands-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Aurich Lawson | Getty Images</media:credit></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Rocket Report: Stoke is stoked; sovereignty is the buzzword in Europe</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/rocket-report-stoke-is-stoked-sovereignty-is-the-buzzword-in-europe/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/rocket-report-stoke-is-stoked-sovereignty-is-the-buzzword-in-europe/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Stephen Clark]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 11:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artemis II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[european space agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[falcon 9]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isar aerospace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[launch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket lab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rocket report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space launch system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spacex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[united launch alliance]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/rocket-report-stoke-is-stoked-sovereignty-is-the-buzzword-in-europe/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA["The idea that we will be able to do it through America… I think is very, very doubtful."]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Edition 7.37 of the Rocket Report! It's been interesting to watch how quickly European officials have embraced ensuring they have a space launch capability independent of other countries. A few years ago, European government satellites regularly launched on Russian Soyuz rockets, and more recently on SpaceX Falcon 9 rockets from the United States. Russia is now <em>non grata</em> in European government circles, and the Trump administration is widening the trans-Atlantic rift. European leaders have cited the Trump administration and its close association with Elon Musk, CEO of SpaceX, as prime reasons to support sovereign access to space, a capability currently offered only by Arianespace. If European nations can reform how they treat their commercial space companies, there's enough ambition, know-how, and money in Europe to foster a competitive launch industry.</p>
<p>As always, we <a href="https://arstechnica.wufoo.com/forms/launch-stories/">welcome reader submissions</a>. If you don't want to miss an issue, please subscribe using the box below (the form will not appear on AMP-enabled versions of the site). Each report will include information on small-, medium-, and heavy-lift rockets as well as a quick look ahead at the next three launches on the calendar.</p>
<figure class="ars-img-shortcode id-1314289 align-center">
    <div>
                        <img decoding="async" width="560" height="81" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png" class="center full" alt="" srcset="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll.png 560w, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/smalll-300x43.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px">
                  </div>
      </figure>

<p><b>Isar Aerospace aims for weekend launch. </b>A German startup named Isar Aerospace will try to launch its first rocket Saturday, aiming to become the first in a wave of new European launch companies to reach orbit, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/this-launcher-is-about-to-displace-the-v-2-as-germanys-largest-rocket/">Ars reports</a>. The Spectrum rocket consists of two stages, stands about 92 feet (28 meters) tall, and can haul payloads up to 1 metric ton (2,200 pounds) into low-Earth orbit. Based in Munich, Isar was founded by three university graduate students in 2018. Isar scrubbed a launch attempt Monday due to unfavorable winds at the launch site in Norway.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/rocket-report-stoke-is-stoked-sovereignty-is-the-buzzword-in-europe/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/03/rocket-report-stoke-is-stoked-sovereignty-is-the-buzzword-in-europe/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>66</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gj_q6cnWcAAkjpz-1152x648.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gj_q6cnWcAAkjpz-500x500.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Stoke Space</media:credit><media:text>Stoke Space's Andromeda upper stage engine is hot-fired on a test stand.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
          <item>
        <title>Trump can’t fire us, FTC Democrats tell court after being ejected from office</title>
        <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ftc-democrats-sue-trump-say-firings-break-law-and-supreme-court-precedent/</link>
                  <comments>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ftc-democrats-sue-trump-say-firings-break-law-and-supreme-court-precedent/#comments</comments>
        
        <dc:creator>
          <![CDATA[Jon Brodkin]]>
        </dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 20:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
        		<category><![CDATA[Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ftc democrats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[president trump]]></category>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ftc-democrats-sue-trump-say-firings-break-law-and-supreme-court-precedent/</guid>

                  <description>
            <![CDATA["A President cannot remove an FTC Commissioner without cause," lawsuit says.]]>
          </description>
                                <content:encoded>
              <![CDATA[<p>Two Democratic members of the Federal Trade Commission who were <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/trump-fires-both-ftc-democrats-in-challenge-to-supreme-court-precedent/">fired by President Trump</a> sued him today, saying their removals are "in direct violation of a century of federal law and Supreme Court precedent."</p>
<p>"Plaintiffs bring this action to vindicate their right to serve the remainder of their respective terms, to defend the integrity of the Commission, and to continue their work for the American people," said the <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.dcd.278902/gov.uscourts.dcd.278902.1.0_2.pdf">lawsuit</a> filed by Rebecca Kelly Slaughter and Alvaro Bedoya in US District Court for the District of Columbia.</p>
<p>Trump last week sent Slaughter and Bedoya notices that said, "I am writing to inform you that you have been removed from the Federal Trade Commission, effective immediately." They were then cut off from their FTC email addresses, asked to return electronic devices, and denied access to their offices.</p><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ftc-democrats-sue-trump-say-firings-break-law-and-supreme-court-precedent/">Read full article</a></p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/03/ftc-democrats-sue-trump-say-firings-break-law-and-supreme-court-precedent/#comments">Comments</a></p>
]]>
            </content:encoded>
                  
                  <slash:comments>202</slash:comments>
        
        
        <media:content height="648" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/bedoya-and-slaughter-1152x648-1742403699.jpg" width="1152">
<media:thumbnail height="500" url="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/bedoya-and-slaughter-500x500-1742403726.jpg" width="500"/>
<media:credit>Getty Images | The Washington Post </media:credit><media:text>Federal Trade Commission Commissioners Rebecca Kelly Slaughter and Alvaro Bedoya at a House Judiciary Committee hearing on Capitol Hill in Washington, DC on July 13, 2023.</media:text></media:content>
      </item>
      </channel>
</rss>